<data>
  <row row="1">
    <cell cellsource="A1">_key</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B1">_text</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C1">_text</cell>
  </row>
  <row row="2">
    <cell cellsource="A2">NAR_LANGUAGE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B2">English</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C2">Italian</cell>
  </row>
  <row row="3">
    <cell cellsource="A3">NAR_1_9_LOOK_BINOCULARS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B3">You see binoculars</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C3" />
  </row>
  <row row="4">
    <cell cellsource="A4">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B4">You can easily see your house from here. It's not that you prefer your TREEHOUSE to your HOUSE, specifically. //It's just that you prefer your TREEHOUSE to literally any conceivable enclosure.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C4" />
  </row>
  <row row="5">
    <cell cellsource="A5">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_DOGHOUSE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B5">The PUPPY CASTLE seems fortified for the moment. You and that pup spent some time adding extra DEFENCING IMPLEMENTS this summer. //They are holding up nicely.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C5" />
  </row>
  <row row="6">
    <cell cellsource="A6">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_HOUSE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B6">There she blows. Harley Manor. //Well, maybe only Half-Harley Manor, since Joey disowned the name in favor of your mother's. Kind of melodramatic of her, you think. //Not that you'd ever say so. She'd bite your head off!</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C6" />
  </row>
  <row row="7">
    <cell cellsource="A7">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_JOEYS_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B7">You can see JOEY'S ROOM through here. PERFECT opportunity for a pesky younger brother to do some quality snooping. Except she only ever does boring stuff like play games, and make obscene gestures at you when she notices you peeking, which is almost always. How does she always seem to KNOW?</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C7" />
  </row>
  <row row="8">
    <cell cellsource="A8">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_LANDING_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B8">It's the window to the stairway landing. You're a bit jealous of the vantage it offers. From there, you can get a great view of your sweet TREEHOUSE. Sometimes you park yourself on that landing, and gaze up at your private abode while swooning deeply.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C8" />
  </row>
  <row row="9">
    <cell cellsource="A9">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B9">Look at this crew. Some sadistic SOB absolutely CRUSHED these lunkheads with the business end of the ugly stick. They're absolutely horrifying. //Still, you feel pretty safe up here, for now. Joey's the one who's in trouble. Time for LITTLE BRO to STEP UP.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C9" />
  </row>
  <row row="10">
    <cell cellsource="A10">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_SKY</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B10">The sky has been clouding over all day. It's been getting gloomier and gloomier. That sinking feeling you have keeps sinking further. It doesn't seem natural. It pretty much HAS to be linked to this grim turn of events, doesn't it?</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C10" />
  </row>
  <row row="11">
    <cell cellsource="A11">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW2</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B11">This is the perfect lookout post for observing the SPOOKY MANSION near your house. //You've been theorizing about its involvement in this cryptic plot for some time, but have reached no solid conclusions. Maybe today you'll finally understand what secrets it keeps? //Or perhaps, satisfying that curiosity will be deferred for some time.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C11" />
  </row>
  <row row="12">
    <cell cellsource="A12">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW2_MANSION_ONCE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B12">The mansion looms. You told your sister it was nothing but trouble, but she never listened. Just as well. You have a feeling that probing its mysteries will have to fall on your shoulders, not hers. Your only job now is to protect her. And hers, to stay safe. It's tough being the man of the house.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C12" />
  </row>
  <row row="13">
    <cell cellsource="A13">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW2_MANSION_AFTER1ST</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B13">The spooky old mansion on the hill. You always said there was something up with that place.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C13" />
  </row>
  <row row="14">
    <cell cellsource="A14">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW2_SHADOWS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B14">What was that?! Did something move out there? //Your imagination is starting to play tricks on you. You decide that your imagination is stupid and can go take a big stupid hike.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C14" />
  </row>
  <row row="15">
    <cell cellsource="A15">NAR_1_9_LOOK_LAMP</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B15">A standard camping lantern.  //Your uses of it are hardly standard, youthinks. More like... OUTSTANDARD. (i.e. great)</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C15" />
  </row>
  <row row="16">
    <cell cellsource="A16">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WORKBENCH</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B16">No TREEHOUSE is complete without a SERIOUS WORKBENCH. Hence, this treehouse is complete.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C16" />
  </row>
  <row row="17">
    <cell cellsource="A17">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B17">There is a NO NONSENSE DRAWER embedded in the SERIOUS WORKBENCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C17" />
  </row>
  <row row="18">
    <cell cellsource="A18">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DIAGRAMS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B18">Sometimes you think your theories make TOO much sense. //Sometimes you think that, to confuse spies or the snooping press, maybe you should jumble your diagrams around a little. //To make it all look like the work of a raving lunatic, instead of a studious young man hot on the trail of nefarious forces cloaked in secrecy.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C18" />
  </row>
  <row row="19">
    <cell cellsource="A19">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B19">You think you’ve cracked the old man’s code this time. //You note that the shading and line work is superb. Frankly you wonder if you are even capable of anything sub-superb.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C19" />
  </row>
  <row row="20">
    <cell cellsource="A20">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CAT</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B20">It's a sketch you made of the weird cat's head the old man has, stuffed and mounted! Personally, you're not THAT big in hollowing them out and putting them on wall, but I guess other people gotta fill up the hours somehow, right? //Oddly, this cat has one red eye and one green eye. You would rate this as: EXTREMELY MYSTERIOUS.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C20" />
  </row>
  <row row="21">
    <cell cellsource="A21">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_DEER</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B21">You sketched the deer's head that the guy has stuffed and mounted.  You know how sometimes you look at a majestic deer in nature and think "I wish I had the skin of that but not its insides stuffed and in my house somehow?" //Turns out, some people work at making that dream come true! In particular, this guy did.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C21" />
  </row>
  <row row="22">
    <cell cellsource="A22">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B22">You feel like you really captured the true essence of this giant conspicuous globe. It is giant and conspicuous, just like in real life!</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C22" />
  </row>
  <row row="23">
    <cell cellsource="A23">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CAGE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B23">When the heat is on from the government, and you need to send an encrypted message while staying off the grid, you entrust it to one of your trained carrier pigeons, THE LONE GUNBIRDS. //You survey the troops: there's LANGLY, BYERS, and of course FROHIKE. He's your favorite!</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C23" />
  </row>
  <row row="24">
    <cell cellsource="A24">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CAGE_1ST_SENT</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B24">Trusty LANGLY and clever BYERS are still left.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C24" />
  </row>
  <row row="25">
    <cell cellsource="A25">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CAGE_2ND_SENT</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B25">Brave BYERS still stands majestic and strong. Chest puffed up, head cocked, and a look in his eye that says, "Sure, I may be painfully stupid, but I'm the last chance you've got."</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C25" />
  </row>
  <row row="26">
    <cell cellsource="A26">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CAGE_3RD_SENT</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B26">It looks so empty now. Sniff.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C26" />
  </row>
  <row row="27">
    <cell cellsource="A27">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SCHEMATICS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B27">THIS thing. Talk about an enigma. One day, you'll figure out what it does, and why certain shady characters want to get their hands on it so badly. You have some theories, of course. //You can't let them find it. Really, no one should be messing with this thing. CERTAINLY not children.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C27" />
  </row>
  <row row="28">
    <cell cellsource="A28">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CHEST</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B28">The perfect place to store your MEGA-DANGEROUS COLLECTION OF FLARES!!</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C28" />
  </row>
  <row row="29">
    <cell cellsource="A29">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CULTTHEORIES</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B29">Your copious notes on some DISREPUTABLE ACTIVITIES carried out by members of what you can only describe as some sort of cult. You've been surreptitiously gathering intelligence on them for a good while. //All the cloak and dagger chicanery would fill you with heady glee, if the facts you've begun to uncover weren't so FRIGGIN' DISTURBING.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C29" />
  </row>
  <row row="30">
    <cell cellsource="A30">NAR_1_9_LOOK_HATCH</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B30">This hatch allows ingress AND egress from your amazing treehouse. //That means you can get in or out of it via a cool hole in the floor. //The hole is kept covered when not in use, because of SAFETY.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C30" />
  </row>
  <row row="31">
    <cell cellsource="A31">NAR_1_9_LOOK_JARS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B31">Look at these jars. These jars are your personal curated collection of jars, containing all sorts of useful items and/or things you thought were cool but don't really remember why anymore.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C31" />
  </row>
  <row row="32">
    <cell cellsource="A32">NAR_1_9_LOOK_GEODES</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B32">Geodes are when you smash open a rock and it's got crystals inside. TOTALLY AMAZING, right? I know. You have tried to find your own geodes but it's really hard to smash open rocks even if you don't use your bare hands, so these have all been given to you.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C32" />
  </row>
  <row row="33">
    <cell cellsource="A33">NAR_1_9_LOOK_RADIO</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B33">You see a radio</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C33" />
  </row>
  <row row="34">
    <cell cellsource="A34">NAR_1_9_LOOK_AUDIOGUN</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B34">Pop quiz: why would ANY cool dude have a treehouse and NOT have a listening device in it? Answer: they wouldn't. //As you are the coolest of dudes, you OBVIOUSLY have that listening device thing COVERED.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C34" />
  </row>
  <row row="35">
    <cell cellsource="A35">NAR_1_9_TREEHOUSE_INTRO</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B35">You are now Joey's KID BROTHER. You can go back to being Jude's BIG SISTER at any time. But then again, what's the hurry? //This guy looks pretty cool, right? Cool for a silly nerd brother, that is. One who's obsessed with a bunch of CRYPTIC AND SINISTER CONSPIRACY NONSENSE that is TOTALLY FAKE. //But then, it all seems to be getting less FAKE by the minute, doesn't it?</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C35" />
  </row>
  <row row="36">
    <cell cellsource="A36">NAR_1_9_TREEHOUSE_INTRO_2</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B36">In fact, with each OCCULT FOE and VILE BEAST that crashes into your home to upset your sister, the FAKENESS ATTRIBUTE of all that stuff shrinks just a little more. You'd claim bragging rights, but at the moment, you've got a sister to save. //Your name is JUDE HARLEY, and today is the day you always feared would come.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C36" />
  </row>
  <row row="37">
    <cell cellsource="A37">NAR_1_9_LOOK_FLAREGUN</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B37">You're probably the only kid in school that owns one of these babies. Hard to believe, really. What if those kids get stranded in the middle of the OCEAN? Then the joke's on them. The big, wet, deadly joke.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C37" />
  </row>
  <row row="38">
    <cell cellsource="A38">NAR_1_9_TAKE_FLAREGUN</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B38">The chamber is empty. Weak. //You should load it with some FLARES. Just in case.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C38" />
  </row>
  <row row="39">
    <cell cellsource="A39">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CHEST</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B39">The perfect place to store your MEGA-DANGEROUS COLLECTION OF FLARES!!</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C39" />
  </row>
  <row row="40">
    <cell cellsource="A40">NAR_1_9_TAKE_FLARES_CHEST</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B40">You remove the FLARES from the METAL CHEST. They're pretty lame on their own though.  //If only you had a super unique FLARE GUN to use them in.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C40" />
  </row>
  <row row="41">
    <cell cellsource="A41">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_1ST_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B41">You take another pouch from the drawer and load it with one more red and green marble.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C41" />
  </row>
  <row row="42">
    <cell cellsource="A42">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_2ND_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B42">Your hands are definitely not shaking as you pluck two more marbles from their safe, cozy compartments in the drawer and drop them into the depths of the pouch's waiting, leathery maw.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C42" />
  </row>
  <row row="43">
    <cell cellsource="A43">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_JUNK</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B43">What are you calling junk?? This stuff is all borderline treasure. No, not even borderline. It's treasure, plain and simple. //Alright, maybe skirting the edge of borderline. Fair enough?</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C43" />
  </row>
  <row row="44">
    <cell cellsource="A44">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_POUCHES</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B44">Oh man, these POUCHES are so handy. You can think of at least a MILLION uses for them. //(All one million uses involve putting some things inside them, FYI.)</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C44" />
  </row>
  <row row="45">
    <cell cellsource="A45">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_POUCHES</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B45">On closer inspection you discover that the POUCHES are perfect for a CARRIER PIGEON'S frame and stamina. Well, by "discover" you guess you mean "knew already", because they're your pouches, and that's literally why you own them. //You take a pouch from the stack and begin pondering what you could put in it.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C45" />
  </row>
  <row row="46">
    <cell cellsource="A46">NAR_1_9_TAKE_DRAWER_POUCH_YES</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B46">You CAPTCHALOGUE the POUCH WITH RED AND GREEN MARBLES IN your SYLLADEX.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C46" />
  </row>
  <row row="47">
    <cell cellsource="A47">NAR_1_9_TAKE_DRAWER_POUCH_NO</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B47">You remember the TROPHY ROOM DIAGRAM and reconsider your choices.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C47" />
  </row>
  <row row="48">
    <cell cellsource="A48">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_POUCH_0</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B48">Look at that nice empty pouch! You sure could put some stuff in that pouch.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C48" />
  </row>
  <row row="49">
    <cell cellsource="A49">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_POUCH_1</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B49">You do a quick visual inspection and confirm that the pouch contains: [[marble1]]</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C49" />
  </row>
  <row row="50">
    <cell cellsource="A50">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_POUCH_2</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B50">The pouch is just about full to bursting, and currently contains: [[marble1]] and [[marble2]]</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C50" />
  </row>
  <row row="51">
    <cell cellsource="A51">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CATSEYE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B51">Just your average cat's eye marbles. They shine a little bit in the dimming light.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C51" />
  </row>
  <row row="52">
    <cell cellsource="A52">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_BLUE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B52">Just your average blue marbles. They shine a bit in the dimming light.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C52" />
  </row>
  <row row="53">
    <cell cellsource="A53">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_YELLOW</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B53">Just your average yellow marbles. They shine MORE THAN a bit in the dimming light.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C53" />
  </row>
  <row row="54">
    <cell cellsource="A54">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_RED</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B54">Just your average red marbles. They ALSO shine a bit in the dimming light.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C54" />
  </row>
  <row row="55">
    <cell cellsource="A55">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_GREEN</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B55">Just your average green marbles. They TOO shine a bit in the dimming light. Is there anything these marbles do that doesn't involve shining a bit in the dimming light??</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C55" />
  </row>
  <row row="56">
    <cell cellsource="A56">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CATSEYE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B56">You move a CAT'S EYE MARBLE to the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C56" />
  </row>
  <row row="57">
    <cell cellsource="A57">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_BLUE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B57">You add a BLUE MARBLE to the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C57" />
  </row>
  <row row="58">
    <cell cellsource="A58">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_YELLOW</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B58">You place a YELLOW MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C58" />
  </row>
  <row row="59">
    <cell cellsource="A59">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_RED</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B59">You put a RED MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C59" />
  </row>
  <row row="60">
    <cell cellsource="A60">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_GREEN</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B60">You drop a GREEN MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C60" />
  </row>
  <row row="61">
    <cell cellsource="A61">NAR_1_9_USE_MARBLES_FULL</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B61">A CARRIER PIGEON couldn't possibly carry that much weight. Better lighten the load.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C61" />
  </row>
  <row row="62">
    <cell cellsource="A62">NAR_1_9_EMPTY_DRAWER_POUCH</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B62">You dump out the contents of pouch. And by “dump out” you mean “carefully put each marble back in its correct compartment according to color.”</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C62" />
  </row>
  <row row="63">
    <cell cellsource="A63">NAR_1_9_1ST_PIGEON_SENT</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B63">R.I.P. dear FROHIKE. The tragedy is nigh insurmountable. Still, you must press on.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C63" />
  </row>
  <row row="64">
    <cell cellsource="A64">NAR_1_9_LOOK_LAMP_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B64">The LANTERN just isn't cutting it! There must be better way to draw the monsters' attention. Something brighter, maybe?</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C64" />
  </row>
  <row row="65">
    <cell cellsource="A65">NAR_1_9_TREEHOUSE_INTRO_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B65">There has got to be something you can do to help Joey! She's gonna get her block knocked off.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C65" />
  </row>
  <row row="66">
    <cell cellsource="A66">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WINDOW1_JOEYS_WINDOW_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell cellsource="B66">There is some noticeable skulking going on in there but you have no idea who or what is the culprit.</cell>
    <cell cellsource="C66" />
  </row>
</data>


