<data>
  <row row="1">
    <cell address="A1">_key</cell>
    <cell address="B1">_text</cell>
    <cell address="C1">_text</cell>
  </row>
  <row row="2">
    <cell address="A2">NAR_LANGUAGE</cell>
    <cell address="B2">English</cell>
    <cell address="C2">Italian</cell>
  </row>
  <row row="3">
    <cell address="A3">NAR_1_1_EXIT_DOOR_DIARY_NO_CONTACT</cell>
    <cell address="B3">You'd like to check if the HALLWAY is clear of monsters before you just waltz out there! JUDE can see it from his TREEHOUSE, you're pretty sure. He can definitely see into your room, anyway.</cell>
    <cell address="C3" />
  </row>
  <row row="4">
    <cell address="A4">NAR_1_1_EXIT_DOOR_NO_DIARY</cell>
    <cell address="B4">You don't want to leave without writing WHAT COULD BE YOUR LAST WORDS EVER in your DIARY! Exciting stuff happens to you once in a green moon. Or was it blue. You're too excited to think about moon colors now. //And no, you're DEFINITELY not just stalling for excuses to avoid going out and facing that beast.</cell>
    <cell address="C4" />
  </row>
  <row row="5">
    <cell address="A5">NAR_1_1_EXIT_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_NO_DIARY_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B5">Wait – it's nice to visit your cuddly little friends and all, um, directly inside their mother's womb, but didn't you come poking in here looking for something?</cell>
    <cell address="C5" />
  </row>
  <row row="6">
    <cell address="A6">NAR_1_1_EXIT_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_NO_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B6">You're suddenly a little unsure about leaving your treasured heirloom behind. You mean, this IS a brilliant and super-safe hiding spot where NOBODY would ever think to look, but still...</cell>
    <cell address="C6" />
  </row>
  <row row="7">
    <cell address="A7">NAR_1_1_GOT_BATTERIES</cell>
    <cell address="B7">Well, at least the batteries still seem to have a little juice. You pop open the flap and find some C-CELL BATTERIES, which you dig out with your fingernails and stick in your inventory. //You had some good times, you and Simon. Or, at the very least, some regular times.</cell>
    <cell address="C7" />
  </row>
  <row row="8">
    <cell address="A8">NAR_1_1_INTRO_1</cell>
    <cell address="B8">Your name is JOEY CLAIRE. //Until just moments ago, it was an ordinary autumn day in your home town of HAUNTSWITCH. You were outside horsing around when a truly ABHORRENT BEAST chased you into your bedroom!</cell>
    <cell address="C8" />
  </row>
  <row row="9">
    <cell address="A9">NAR_1_1_INTRO_2</cell>
    <cell address="B9">You always knew that one day you'd be destined for BIG THINGS, like adventure and stuff. You suppose today is that day. And when adventure knocks, who are you to – //HEY! QUIT BANGING ON THAT DOOR! You are TRYING to introduce yourself.</cell>
    <cell address="C9" />
  </row>
  <row row="10">
    <cell address="A10">NAR_1_1_INTRO_3</cell>
    <cell address="B10">That's more like it. As you were saying. When adventure knocks, who are you to cower in your room hoping that awful thing will just go away? //Why, JOEY is who you are, and that's just what you plan on doing. You won't venture out to get mauled alive by that rude critter's busy limbs. At least, not until you confer with your KID BROTHER on this SPOOKY FIX you're in. //What will you do?</cell>
    <cell address="C10" />
  </row>
  <row row="11">
    <cell address="A11">NAR_1_1_ITM_COMB_PORTAL_KEY_DIARY</cell>
    <cell address="B11">The GREEN KEY doesn't fit in your DIARY. You try forcing it in a little, just to make sure. Yep, definitely doesn't fit. Let's face it: this was a stupid idea.</cell>
    <cell address="C11" />
  </row>
  <row row="12">
    <cell address="A12">NAR_1_1_LOOK_MANTHRO_CHAP</cell>
    <cell address="B12">Your interest in anthropomorphic animals has really hit its peak. Or... has it? //There's a dangerous thought.</cell>
    <cell address="C12" />
  </row>
  <row row="13">
    <cell address="A13">NAR_1_1_LOOK_ANIMAL_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B13">One day you hope to be a VETERINARIAN. Then you can be the one caring for fuzzy-faced baby critters! So when someone catches you in the act of snuggling them all, and tells you to take a hike, you can flash your vet badge and say you're here on PROFESSIONAL MEDICAL BUSINESS. Then THEY'LL have to take the hike, not you.</cell>
    <cell address="C13" />
  </row>
  <row row="14">
    <cell address="A14">NAR_1_1_ITM_PET_TREATS_ANIMAL_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B14">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C14" />
  </row>
  <row row="15">
    <cell address="A15">NAR_1_1_OUTGROW_DREAMS_ANIMAL_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B15">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C15" />
  </row>
  <row row="16">
    <cell address="A16">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BALLETSTATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B16">MOM won this award at around the same age as you for being best at ballet. It's pretty.</cell>
    <cell address="C16" />
  </row>
  <row row="17">
    <cell address="A17">NAR_1_1_PAS_DE_DEUX_BALLETSTATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B17">You mentally perform a little two-step with the award your mother won for ballet. You have danced this dance a thousand times... ON THE LIMITLESS STAGE OF THE IMAGINATION!</cell>
    <cell address="C17" />
  </row>
  <row row="18">
    <cell address="A18">NAR_1_1_AB_BALLET_DANCE_BALLETSTATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B18">You bust out all your most illegal ballet moves on the beautiful statue. This “shadow ballet” against an unbeatable opponent is how raw young steppers like yourself hone your skills sharp between practices. OK, none of that is real. But it’s fun to pretend sometimes.</cell>
    <cell address="C18" />
  </row>
  <row row="19">
    <cell address="A19">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BEANBAG</cell>
    <cell address="B19">Seems like BEANBAGS are making a big comeback lately. Not this retro variant from the '70s, though. There's no coming back from the amount of bean-loss it has suffered over the years.//Still, it beats sitting on the floor, and that's all you can really ask of a BEANBAG.</cell>
    <cell address="C19" />
  </row>
  <row row="20">
    <cell address="A20">NAR_1_1_NAP_IN_BEANBAG</cell>
    <cell address="B20">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C20" />
  </row>
  <row row="21">
    <cell address="A21">NAR_1_1_CONTEMPLATE_OWN_EXISTENCE_IN_BEANBAG</cell>
    <cell address="B21">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C21" />
  </row>
  <row row="22">
    <cell address="A22">NAR_1_1_COME_UP_WITH_GOOD_NICKNAMES_FOR_YOURSELF_IN_BEANBAG</cell>
    <cell address="B22">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C22" />
  </row>
  <row row="23">
    <cell address="A23">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BED</cell>
    <cell address="B23">This is a raised and cushioned platform where you spend several hours every day unconscious and hallucinating, usually while the majority of the other people on the continent are ALSO doing the same thing.</cell>
    <cell address="C23" />
  </row>
  <row row="24">
    <cell address="A24">NAR_1_1_SLEEP_BED</cell>
    <cell address="B24">You'd have to be some sort of NAP FIEND to even consider dozing off under these dire circumstances. You have enough nightmares to worry about, namely the physically manifested ones raiding your house.</cell>
    <cell address="C24" />
  </row>
  <row row="25">
    <cell address="A25">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BOOKS1</cell>
    <cell address="B25">You look over your sweet collection of books. There's "ANIMALS! HERE'S THE 250 GOOD ONES" (you disagreed with SEVERAL of the author's choices), "DOMESTICATED BLISS" (a speculative-future about cats and dogs marrying each other), and "WAG THE DOG" (a satirical political thriller that you bought because you thought it had something to do with dogs: it does NOT).</cell>
    <cell address="C25" />
  </row>
  <row row="26">
    <cell address="A26">NAR_1_1_WRITE_BOOK_REPORT_BOOKS1</cell>
    <cell address="B26">None of these books are appropriate choices for a BOOK REPORT, according to your teachers. Your teachers seems oddly fixated on award-winning books where beloved dogs are introduced and then inevitably die. You kind of hate your teachers sometimes.</cell>
    <cell address="C26" />
  </row>
  <row row="27">
    <cell address="A27">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BOOKS2</cell>
    <cell address="B27">Now here are some choice books. You've got "BAD DANCE: THE SECRETS OF ILLEGAL RUSSIAN BALLET" (how did the school BOOK FAIR have this??? ), "I PUT METAL THINGS ON MY SHOES AND IT MADE MY SHOES NOISIER THAN USUAL: AN ORAL HISTORY OF TAP" (it gets REALLY good when Jonesy "Giggletoes" Johnson realized he could add knee slapping into the mix), and "TAP DANCE TROUBLE" (a Full House Michelle Mystery).</cell>
    <cell address="C27" />
  </row>
  <row row="28">
    <cell address="A28">NAR_1_1_WRITE_BOOK_REPORT_BOOKS2</cell>
    <cell address="B28">None of these books are appropriate choices for a BOOK REPORT, according to your teachers. Your teachers seems oddly fixated on award-winning books where beloved dogs are introduced and then inevitably die. You kind of hate your teachers sometimes.</cell>
    <cell address="C28" />
  </row>
  <row row="29">
    <cell address="A29">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BOOKS3</cell>
    <cell address="B29">Now THESE are some books. There's "THE MORALITY OF MEGAMAN" (he kills his siblings and steals their powers to make killing his other siblings easier, while THEIR only evident crime is standing alone in a room, waiting for his arrival), "BRAIN RUINER: A COLLECTION OF RIDDLES TO MAKE YOU WEEP" (not from difficulty, the riddles are just heart-achingly beautiful), and "HOW TO WIN AT MONOPOLY WITHOUT DESTROYING YOUR RELATIONSHIPS" (auction properties, don't award money for free parking, and play as the doggie!).</cell>
    <cell address="C29" />
  </row>
  <row row="30">
    <cell address="A30">NAR_1_1_WRITE_BOOK_REPORT_BOOKS3</cell>
    <cell address="B30">None of these books are appropriate choices for a BOOK REPORT, according to your teachers. Your teachers seems oddly fixated on award-winning books where beloved dogs are introduced and then inevitably die. You kind of hate your teachers sometimes.</cell>
    <cell address="C30" />
  </row>
  <row row="31">
    <cell address="A31">NAR_1_1_LOOK_BUBSY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B31">It's Bubsy! God you love Bubsy. He's such a funny, lovable... what is he again? Some sort of grotesque, rubber-limbed cat with direly underdeveloped motor skills? You just think he's so... so... //It's time to face the facts. This game has no redeeming qualities whatsoever. It is completely indefensible. You just put this poster up because you think its badness is kind of funny. Jude thinks you're nuts for doing so, but you're like, what if that aesthetic catches on some day? What then, smartypants?? He has no answer.</cell>
    <cell address="C31" />
  </row>
  <row row="32">
    <cell address="A32">NAR_1_1_REGRET_BUBSY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B32">Nintendo Power magazine published a cover story naming Bubsy the "Most Hateful Video Game Mascot of the 90s" //A COVER STORY. Why do you have this.</cell>
    <cell address="C32" />
  </row>
  <row row="33">
    <cell address="A33">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_BUBSY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B33">“WHAT COULD PAWSIBLY GO WRONG???” That’s what Bubsy would say, if he were here. He’d never stop saying it. You’d hear it in your head, forever, echoing like screams echo across still water.</cell>
    <cell address="C33" />
  </row>
  <row row="34">
    <cell address="A34">NAR_1_1_DESPISE_BUBSY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B34">You despise Bubsy, yeah. It’s sort of a passively persistent state. You don’t really need to actively engage in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C34" />
  </row>
  <row row="35">
    <cell address="A35">NAR_1_1_ITM_PET_TREATS_BUBSY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B35">You’re not going to encourage this guy any further.</cell>
    <cell address="C35" />
  </row>
  <row row="36">
    <cell address="A36">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CALENDAR</cell>
    <cell address="B36">It's the 11th of November. Today started off just like any other day: with another sunrise, and the sound of song birds going hog wild out there in the trees. But their songs have all but stopped. And now there's something else going hog wild out there. You don't know what it is, but it ain't birds, and it sure as heck ain't hogs.</cell>
    <cell address="C36" />
  </row>
  <row row="37">
    <cell address="A37">NAR_1_1_MARK_CALENDAR</cell>
    <cell address="B37">You've already marked today's date as part of your DAILY ROUTINE. If anyone claims that you didn't exist on the date of November 10th, 1994, you can shove that big red 'X' right in their face and prove them wrong.</cell>
    <cell address="C37" />
  </row>
  <row row="38">
    <cell address="A38">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CEILING</cell>
    <cell address="B38">You examine the ceiling in more detail, as one does. It is covered by a mural that your mom painted for you when you were very young. Later, you added the stars yourself. You are quite pleased with the results of the long term mother-daughter collaboration.</cell>
    <cell address="C38" />
  </row>
  <row row="39">
    <cell address="A39">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CEILING_CU_STAR</cell>
    <cell address="B39">This huge star was the jewel in the crown of the cheap set of glow-in-the-dark plastic star stickers you bought. It earned a place of honor near your bed, so you can look up at it as you drift to sleep. You found yourself mysteriously drawn to the symbol...</cell>
    <cell address="C39" />
  </row>
  <row row="40">
    <cell address="A40">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CEILING_CU_STARS</cell>
    <cell address="B40">These glow-in-the-dark plastic stars provide a NOT-UNCONVINCING illusion of space for at least a few minutes after you turn off your lights. Your brother once said "they're not accurate" but you said "they are, they're just not from the point of view of Earth," and that shut him up pretty quickly!</cell>
    <cell address="C40" />
  </row>
  <row row="41">
    <cell address="A41">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CEILING_CU_SUN</cell>
    <cell address="B41">This is a fiery inferno of plasma burning so intensely it can heat up a planet billions of miles away. //Sorry, that's not accurate. It's actually just a GRAPHIC DEPICTION of a fiery inferno of plasma burning so intensely it can heat up a planet billions of miles away. Phew!</cell>
    <cell address="C41" />
  </row>
  <row row="42">
    <cell address="A42">NAR_1_1_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_CEILING_CU_SUN</cell>
    <cell address="B42">You kind of do wish that the SUN were green, like the beautiful glowing star over on the other side of the mural. But that would mean it was glow-in-the-dark, and it might be too bright for you to sleep! Hmm! You guess maybe GREEN SUNS are more than you bargain for, sometimes.</cell>
    <cell address="C42" />
  </row>
  <row row="43">
    <cell address="A43">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLARISSA_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B43">## NA NA na-NA-na-na! ## Oops, the theme song gets stuck in your head the second you look at this poster. //Clarissa is a beacon of hope to all sassy teenage girls. The wit, the charm, the relatable teen dilemmas, the 4th wall breaking, the fashion sense... She is the full package. //Not to mention, your number one source of wisdom for dealing with a shrill, twerpy kid brother. Watching Ferguson Darling get wrecked on a weekly basis is one of life's simpler joys.</cell>
    <cell address="C43" />
  </row>
  <row row="44">
    <cell address="A44">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_CLARISSA_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B44">You try to remember if Clarissa ever got in any jams like this. You have so much in common: annoying little brother, computer in your room, uh, second-story bedroom… uhh...// As much as you hate to admit it, Clarissa’s life deviates from yours on a number of vertices. Her parents were around, she had a cool friend who was a boy but not her boyfriend, no monsters in the yard, etc.</cell>
    <cell address="C44" />
  </row>
  <row row="45">
    <cell address="A45">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET</cell>
    <cell address="B45">It's your musty VAULT OF MYSTERY clogged to capacity with ENIGMATIC BRAIN BOGGLERS. Or really just an ordinary closet full of puzzles 'n' stuff. You like all the stuff that's in here. Every single thing.</cell>
    <cell address="C45" />
  </row>
  <row row="46">
    <cell address="A46">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET_CLOSED</cell>
    <cell address="B46">A DOOR! That is CLOSED?! WHAT MYSTERIES lie BEHIND IT? And HOW COULD YOU EVER FIND OUT?!</cell>
    <cell address="C46" />
  </row>
  <row row="47">
    <cell address="A47">NAR_1_1_AVOID_FOREVER_CLOSET</cell>
    <cell address="B47">No! There’s some good stuff in there.</cell>
    <cell address="C47" />
  </row>
  <row row="48">
    <cell address="A48">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET_CU_PUZZLES</cell>
    <cell address="B48">Gadzooks. Astounding and colorful FLABBERGASTERS OF GRAY MATTER (puzzles) AS FAR AS THE EYE CAN SEE. And the eye can see exactly as far into this closet as it is deep, and that's about the amount of space the puzzles take up, so, wow?</cell>
    <cell address="C48" />
  </row>
  <row row="49">
    <cell address="A49">NAR_1_1_PLAY_PUZZLES</cell>
    <cell address="B49">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C49" />
  </row>
  <row row="50">
    <cell address="A50">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET_CU_SIMON</cell>
    <cell address="B50">It's Simon! Gosh you love Simon. //Even if this Simon fellow IS a brutal taskmaster who revels in forcing children to endure tedious repetition.</cell>
    <cell address="C50" />
  </row>
  <row row="51">
    <cell address="A51">NAR_1_1_LOOK_SIMON_AFTER_PLAYED</cell>
    <cell address="B51">You suppose you've had just about all the fun there is to be had with this broken, now batteryless game.</cell>
    <cell address="C51" />
  </row>
  <row row="52">
    <cell address="A52">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B52">You really like this poster but can't really say why. It's pretty, and you like the expression on the ballerina's face. You wonder if this is what it's like when adults go to museums to look at Actual Art. You hope so.</cell>
    <cell address="C52" />
  </row>
  <row row="53">
    <cell address="A53">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CLOSET2</cell>
    <cell address="B53">This is where you keep your clothes! You consider your fashion statement to be "fun and comfortable", and try to model yourself on Clarissa. //Ah, Clarissa. She really does explain quite a few things, EXCEPT of course precisely where she gets her clothes and how she manages to look so great all the time.</cell>
    <cell address="C53" />
  </row>
  <row row="54">
    <cell address="A54">NAR_1_1_NEW_STYLE_MONTAGE_CLOSET2</cell>
    <cell address="B54">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C54" />
  </row>
  <row row="55">
    <cell address="A55">NAR_1_1_LOOK_COMPUTER</cell>
    <cell address="B55">Your modem makes a mighty racket logging you on. Probably not worth riling up any hallway snakes to surf your 'sites right now. (As in, your "Websites.") Hm, unless...</cell>
    <cell address="C55" />
  </row>
  <row row="56">
    <cell address="A56">NAR_1_1_SEARCH_COMPUTER</cell>
    <cell address="B56">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C56" />
  </row>
  <row row="57">
    <cell address="A57">NAR_1_1_HACK_COMPUTER</cell>
    <cell address="B57">UH! YES! You are HACKING this computer! Root control! Sudo command! Black hat! // It does nothing.</cell>
    <cell address="C57" />
  </row>
  <row row="58">
    <cell address="A58">NAR_1_1_LOOK_CONNECT4</cell>
    <cell address="B58">Connect Four! The goal of this game is to get four of your colored circles in a row. It's basically an advanced version of Tic Tac Toe made out of plastic. It's more fun to play with more than one person, but that's never stopped you before!!</cell>
    <cell address="C58" />
  </row>
  <row row="59">
    <cell address="A59">NAR_1_1_USE_CONNECT4</cell>
    <cell address="B59">You play Connect Four with yourself. You know your own strategies, so you are able to force yourself into draw. You congratulate yourself on your cunning strategy.</cell>
    <cell address="C59" />
  </row>
  <row row="60">
    <cell address="A60">NAR_1_1_CONNECT_FIVE_CONNECT4</cell>
    <cell address="B60">There’s enough dangerous and impossible stuff happening already without you trifling with the very framework of reality.</cell>
    <cell address="C60" />
  </row>
  <row row="61">
    <cell address="A61">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DIARY_UNWRITTEN_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B61">You usually don't have much to record in here on account of the humdrum life you lead. But youthinks today will be a different story! //Maybe you should take a moment to record a note now, just in case this is your last chance to set down your final words before your tragic demise at the hands of a horrible snakey thing.</cell>
    <cell address="C61" />
  </row>
  <row row="62">
    <cell address="A62">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DIARY_UNWRITTEN</cell>
    <cell address="B62">Imagine having a life brimming with enough deep, meaningful experiences to fill every last page of this DIARY with captivating chronicles.//Its annals would surely inspire future generations, if they weren't FORBIDDEN FROM READING IT.</cell>
    <cell address="C62" />
  </row>
  <row row="63">
    <cell address="A63">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DIARY_WRITTEN</cell>
    <cell address="B63">“Dear Diary: I Had Some Problems, Then I Probably Got Snatched Up by Monsters.” Let’s go make sure that last part is merely speculative!</cell>
    <cell address="C63" />
  </row>
  <row row="64">
    <cell address="A64">NAR_1_1_READ_DIARY_LOCKED_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B64">It's locked! If you wish to gain access to your LONG BURIED OR RECENTLY BURIED SECRETS, you will have to use the DIARY KEY.</cell>
    <cell address="C64" />
  </row>
  <row row="65">
    <cell address="A65">NAR_1_1_READ_DIARY_LOCKED</cell>
    <cell address="B65">It’s...still locked? Wow. Amazing. You thought that “won’t spontaneously come unlocked!” ad in nickelodeon magazine was probably all talk, but it turns out it was true.</cell>
    <cell address="C65" />
  </row>
  <row row="66">
    <cell address="A66">NAR_1_1_READ_DIARY_UNLOCKED_NOT_WRITTEN</cell>
    <cell address="B66">Maybe something from your past will shed some light on today’s terror-mysteries. Some little detail, mentioned offhand and forgotten, the key kicking off a causal cascade of connections that terminates in a catastrophe of snake monsters. //

"april 13th, 1994.  dear diary, 
ho hum! nothing much happened today. i tried to make some new friends at school, to maybe expand our social circle beyond just me and jude's friends all the time??"//
"wait, is it weird to call my brother's friends my 'social circle?' ah well, you know what i mean diary! i don't have any friends i can really call 'mine' so i'm trying to branch out!"//
"the kids at school are jerks though, and they called me a poser when i tried to talk to them about games i like and stuff! between you and me, i think a bunch of the kids at school might be... evil? jeez, now i'm sounding all paranoid like my brother. they're just up to no good, i can feel it. -joey"//

"june 12th, 1994. dear diary, 
whew, first day of summer vacation! i can't wait to get a break from all those clowns at school. sometimes i think what i REALLY need is a vacation from humanity! -joey"//

"october 25th, 1994.  dear diary,
i can't believe i haven't recorded an entry since the beginning of last summer! needless to say, i've been back to school for a while now. next summer can't come soon enough. :( "//
"i came home to a drunk babysitter again today. sure is some quality adult supervision we youngsters are getting around here! she means well enough though."//
"haven't heard from pa in weeks. last we saw of him, he popped in the house to drop off more stupid mummies and globes or whatever, then skipped off to go on more 'adventures.' what a bozo. also, how lame is it that he made us call him pa instead of dad while we were growing up?"//
"i miss mom. :( :(
-joey"//</cell>
    <cell address="C66" />
  </row>
  <row row="67">
    <cell address="A67">NAR_1_1_WRITE_IN_DIARY_UNLOCKED_UNWRITTEN_FIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B67">If this is to be the last entry in your diary, then by gum you’re going to scare the bejeezus out of whoever finds it once you’re snakechow.//

"november 11th, 1994. dear diary,
forgive my hasty and nervous scribbling! i'm kinda scared. but maybe, also a bit excited? anyway, can't talk much now. there's a sly and cunning monster on the prowl! possibly hungry for kid meat, too. so i've got to..."//
"ok, i don't have a darn clue what i have to do. but i'll fill you in later once i do it! -joey"//</cell>
    <cell address="C67" />
  </row>
  <row row="68">
    <cell address="A68">NAR_1_1_WRITE_IN_DIARY_UNLOCKED_UNWRITTEN_SECOND</cell>
    <cell address="B68">...Satisfied you've done your duty vis-a-vis posterity in case the worst should happen, you re-lock your diary and hide the key again. Safe and sound!</cell>
    <cell address="C68" />
  </row>
  <row row="69">
    <cell address="A69">NAR_1_1_READ_DIARY_WRITTEN_FIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B69">You fetch the key from its hiding place and crack open your diary again.</cell>
    <cell address="C69" />
  </row>
  <row row="70">
    <cell address="A70">NAR_1_1_READ_DIARY_WRITTEN_SECOND</cell>
    <cell address="B70">"april 13th, 1994.  dear diary, 
ho hum! nothing much happened today. i tried to make some new friends at school, to maybe expand our social circle beyond just me and jude's friends all the time??"//
"wait, is it weird to call my brother's friends my 'social circle?' ah well, you know what i mean diary! i don't have any friends i can really call 'mine' so i'm trying to branch out!"//
"the kids at school are jerks though, and they called me a poser when i tried to talk to them about games i like and stuff! between you and me, i think a bunch of the kids at school might be... evil? jeez, now i'm sounding all paranoid like my brother. they're just up to no good, i can feel it. -joey"//

"june 12th, 1994. dear diary, 
whew, first day of summer vacation! i can't wait to get a break from all those clowns at school. sometimes i think what i REALLY need is a vacation from humanity! -joey"//

"october 25th, 1994.  dear diary,
i can't believe i haven't recorded an entry since the beginning of last summer! needless to say, i've been back to school for a while now. next summer can't come soon enough. :( "//
"i came home to a drunk babysitter again today. sure is some quality adult supervision we youngsters are getting around here! she means well enough though."//
"haven't heard from pa in weeks. last we saw of him, he popped in the house to drop off more stupid mummies and globes or whatever, then skipped off to go on more ''adventures''. what a bozo. also, how lame is it that he made us call him pa instead of dad while we were growing up?"//
"i miss mom. :( :(
-joey"//

"november 11th, 1994. dear diary,
forgive my hasty and nervous scribbling! i'm kinda scared. but maybe, also a bit excited? anyway, can't talk much now. there's a sly and cunning monster on the prowl! possibly hungry for kid meat, too. so i've got to..."//
"ok, i don't have a darn clue what i have to do. but i'll fill you in later once i do it! -joey"//</cell>
    <cell address="C70" />
  </row>
  <row row="71">
    <cell address="A71">NAR_1_1_WRITE_IN_DIARY_WRITTEN</cell>
    <cell address="B71">"A few moments passed, and then I started writing in this diary again" won't be the most thrilling entry.</cell>
    <cell address="C71" />
  </row>
  <row row="72">
    <cell address="A72">NAR_1_1_HIDE_DIARY</cell>
    <cell address="B72">You got a diary with a lock specifically so you WOULDN’T have to hide it from Jude. Also because it makes you feel like Harriet the Spy, or rather, a Harriet the Spy who was smart enough to get a diary with a lock on it.</cell>
    <cell address="C72" />
  </row>
  <row row="73">
    <cell address="A73">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B73">You can still hear that thing scuffling around sporadically. It is waiting for you out there, you just know it. Waiting to leap from the shadows and menace you furiously. You really dislike being menaced furiously.</cell>
    <cell address="C73" />
  </row>
  <row row="74">
    <cell address="A74">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DOOR_JUDE_CONTACTED</cell>
    <cell address="B74">You put your ear up to the door and... nope. You don't hear anything. //Perhaps the coast is clear? Only one way to find out.</cell>
    <cell address="C74" />
  </row>
  <row row="75">
    <cell address="A75">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DRESSER</cell>
    <cell address="B75">It's your dresser! This is where you’ve stashed your DIARY, as well as the only known photograph of you and mom together, taken back when you were much, much littler.//What else? Oh yeah, you keep your socks and underwear in here. OR DO YOU????(yes)??</cell>
    <cell address="C75" />
  </row>
  <row row="76">
    <cell address="A76">NAR_1_1_SEARCH_DRESSER</cell>
    <cell address="B76">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C76" />
  </row>
  <row row="77">
    <cell address="A77">NAR_1_1_HIDE_SECRETS_DRESSER</cell>
    <cell address="B77">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C77" />
  </row>
  <row row="78">
    <cell address="A78">NAR_1_1_LOOK_GAMEPOSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B78">These are posters of all your favorite games (that they had posters for). Included are posters for "TETRIS 2" (FUN FACT: Tetris 2 is TWICE as fun as Tetris 1, you can only assume. You haven't actually played Tetris 1.) and "SUPER METROID" (FUN FACT: you have spent approximately 1000 hours on this game, as there is something really appealing about games that let you explore new worlds and solve puzzles there.) //(Also games that let you do this are fun and awesome.)</cell>
    <cell address="C78" />
  </row>
  <row row="79">
    <cell address="A79">NAR_1_1_LOOK_LF_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B79">Posters such as these are really popular among all the girls at school, and with good reason! They're awesome! Who doesn't like COLORS? And SHAPES? And ADORABLE ANIMALS?? //The answer, apparently, is every single boy you know.</cell>
    <cell address="C79" />
  </row>
  <row row="80">
    <cell address="A80">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_LF_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B80">If you were a powerful wizard, you’d summon a flock of rainbow-blooded dolphins to flop all over the monsters and then ride a wizardcorn to the crystal orca future.//You’re not, though. So you’d better knuckle up and get ready to take some eyeless monster scalps. “When the breaks get tough, the tough start breaking” --L.F.</cell>
    <cell address="C80" />
  </row>
  <row row="81">
    <cell address="A81">NAR_1_1_LOOK_MOTHER2_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B81">This game is only available in Japan, but there's this guy at school who says his uncle works at Nintendo, and he gets to play all sorts of secret games before they even come out here, and one time his dad brought home copies of all the games Japan has but we don't, "including Mother 2 AND Super Mario World 5, but they're not at my house because I beat them already."</cell>
    <cell address="C81" />
  </row>
  <row row="82">
    <cell address="A82">NAR_1_1_DEMAND_WESTERN_RELEASE_MOTHER2_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B82">Oh, who are you kidding. They didn’t even bother bringing Mother 1 to the states yet. What’re they waiting for? A substantial foothold for RPGs in western markets? A direct order from the Clinton administration? The specific date of June 14th, 2015? Who knows.</cell>
    <cell address="C82" />
  </row>
  <row row="83">
    <cell address="A83">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_METROID_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B83">SAMUS’ advice for dealing with monsters would probably be to... shoot them. Or change your shape. Or both at once. SAMUS is cool, but occasionally difficult to emulate.</cell>
    <cell address="C83" />
  </row>
  <row row="84">
    <cell address="A84">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_TETRIS2_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B84">TETRIS 2 has a lot of advice about sorting blocks and not a lot of time for anything else. You 
respect TETRIS 2’s laserbeam focus and resolve.</cell>
    <cell address="C84" />
  </row>
  <row row="85">
    <cell address="A85">NAR_1_1_LOOK_MOVIE_POSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B85">These are posters for your favorite movies (that you could find posters for). Your favorite is "THE NEVERENDING STORY", a movie that made you wish you had a giant flying dog for a best friend. //You guess what you're saying is, you wish your dog was huge, and that she could fly.</cell>
    <cell address="C85" />
  </row>
  <row row="86">
    <cell address="A86">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_NEVERENDING_STORY_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B86">Yeah, this kid doesn’t really have any applicable advice for your situation, unless you start riding around on pale white beasts and dealing with the commands of childlike empresses.</cell>
    <cell address="C86" />
  </row>
  <row row="87">
    <cell address="A87">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PHOTO_CU_MOM_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B87">Since she's been gone, you've seen less and less of Pa over the years. Guess he had greener pastures to move on to. Or bluer beauties. //She sure was a looker though. Modeling sensation of the previous decade or two, so you understand. Must be where you get your ravishing looks! Is what you try telling yourself when you're feeling down.</cell>
    <cell address="C87" />
  </row>
  <row row="88">
    <cell address="A88">NAR_1_1_LOOK_DRESSER_CU_MOM</cell>
    <cell address="B88">Maybe amping up "dead mom sadness" will help you find the strength to defeat these brutes! Like how Batman does!</cell>
    <cell address="C88" />
  </row>
  <row row="89">
    <cell address="A89">NAR_1_1_MISS_MOM_MOM</cell>
    <cell address="B89">You miss your mom, yeah. It’s sort of a passively persistent state. You don’t really need to actively engage in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C89" />
  </row>
  <row row="90">
    <cell address="A90">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PHOTO_CU_YOU_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B90">That little girl there? She's destined for big things. Big hopes. Big fears. Big worries. Big lonelinesses. //Now just a dang minute. That creepy snake thing must be getting to ya, with these lame thoughts. Pull yourself together, Joey. //That little girl had a great mom, at least that much you're sure of. You'd never know the glamorous life she led outside these walls, with the touch she had for raising a pair of silly dweebs like you and Jude. You'll never forget.</cell>
    <cell address="C90" />
  </row>
  <row row="91">
    <cell address="A91">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PHOTO_CU_YOU</cell>
    <cell address="B91">Ha ha, OK let's get moving so maybe someday someone gets the chance to take some pics of Future Joey Who Is Alive.</cell>
    <cell address="C91" />
  </row>
  <row row="92">
    <cell address="A92">NAR_1_1_MISS_YOU_YOU</cell>
    <cell address="B92">Awww. Look at that little goofbrisket. You kind of do miss being a doofy little goofbrisket. Those were the days. Being a baby is basically like being a pretty helpless animal, and you do love those. Especially the Great Northwestern Goofbrisket.</cell>
    <cell address="C92" />
  </row>
  <row row="93">
    <cell address="A93">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PUPPY_SURPRISE</cell>
    <cell address="B93">## Puppy Surprise is having puppies! How many?? That's the surprise!!! Puppy Surprise, Puppy Surprise!!!!! ## //Argh. Whenever you look at this thing, the song from that commercial runs through your head like a brazen streaker at a sporting event. Still, you love it so. A mother dog bearing her young, in purchasable plush form. What's not to love?</cell>
    <cell address="C93" />
  </row>
  <row row="94">
    <cell address="A94">NAR_1_1_DISDAIN_PUPPY_SURPRISE</cell>
    <cell address="B94">Yeah right!!! As if you could ever disdain such a sweet lil pup, even if she DIDN’T contain some of the most priceless and sentimental treasures you could ever imagine.</cell>
    <cell address="C94" />
  </row>
  <row row="95">
    <cell address="A95">NAR_1_1_ITM_POGS_PUPPY_SURPRISE</cell>
    <cell address="B95">This is where you’ve kept some of your most precious treasures, so you’re not going to be befouling it with your brother’s cardboard trash discs.//Except the Scully one. In she goes.</cell>
    <cell address="C95" />
  </row>
  <row row="96">
    <cell address="A96">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_DIARY_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B96">So that's where you put it! Ahh, yes. No one would EVER think to look for it inside a plush mother dog. Least of all your brother, who is on record as having "washed [his] hands of the wretched animal." //Jude can be pretty melodramatic.</cell>
    <cell address="C96" />
  </row>
  <row row="97">
    <cell address="A97">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B97">Some old trinket that used to be your mom's. You have no idea what it is, but looking at it reminds you of her. //She found it on an expedition with Pa or something, way before you were born. Couldn't possibly be a powerful ancient artifact freighted with mystical import or anything. Could it? //You don't care for such leading questions, to be honest. Really it just looks like the outlandish toy of a peculiar child, and this is the interpretation you prefer.</cell>
    <cell address="C97" />
  </row>
  <row row="98">
    <cell address="A98">NAR_1_1_LOOK_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_PUPPIES</cell>
    <cell address="B98">It actually came with FIVE puppies, but you got rid of two to make room for other stuff. You don't know ANYBODY else who got five – some kid from school got four in hers, and she wouldn't shut up about it for a week. //You're not one to brag, but, yeah. You walked with a little spring in your step for a while, after birthing that quintet of pups. Maybe you "Five Puppy People" are just cut from a different kind of cloth. Is... something you should probably never, ever say out loud.</cell>
    <cell address="C98" />
  </row>
  <row row="99">
    <cell address="A99">NAR_1_1_LOOK_RAINBOW_BRITE</cell>
    <cell address="B99">They're cute characters who bring color to a colorless world. You like colors! You like cute! So that's why you've got this in your bedroom. MYSTERY SOLVED.</cell>
    <cell address="C99" />
  </row>
  <row row="100">
    <cell address="A100">NAR_1_1_SEEK_COUNSEL_RAINBOW_BRITE</cell>
    <cell address="B100">PAINT THE WALLS WITH THEIR BLOOD JOEY MAKE YOUR RAGE A PRISM OF WRATH JOEY TIE A RAINBOW AROUND THE NECK OF THE PITCH-HEARTED JOEY BRING THEM LOW JOEY MAKE THEM KNEEL//...//You’re not sure where that came from.</cell>
    <cell address="C100" />
  </row>
  <row row="101">
    <cell address="A101">NAR_1_1_LOOK_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B101">It's your SNES! Pronounced "Sness" of course, like someone's peculiar name. Like a weird friend who doesn't get out much. Come to think of it, SNES probably considers YOU its weird friend who doesn't get out much. This is a strange reverie to have, it occurs to you. Just another minute gone by in Joey's Exciting Lonely Life.</cell>
    <cell address="C101" />
  </row>
  <row row="102">
    <cell address="A102">NAR_1_1_LOOK_SNESGAMES</cell>
    <cell address="B102">A prodigious collection of titles for SNES's hungry cartridge-shaped mouth. All the best ones are here! Well, all the ones you happen to own are here! You could spend all day listing them. There's Bubsy, there's... //Mentioning Bubsy made you feel a little queasy, so you think you'll stop there. You might go lie down for a bit, actually.</cell>
    <cell address="C102" />
  </row>
  <row row="103">
    <cell address="A103">NAR_1_1_GAME_GENIE_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B103">You DARE? You DARE to call upon the RAW and ANCIENT magicks of the GAME GENIE? Have you lost your MIND? OK, enough fooling around. You don’t actually have one of those whimsically-named cheat devices. But sometimes you like to pretend you do, and that it’s actually big scary genie who’s all mad about his circumstances.</cell>
    <cell address="C103" />
  </row>
  <row row="104">
    <cell address="A104">NAR_1_1_BLOW_ON_SNESGAMES_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B104">According to your Super Nintendo Entertainment System User Manual, blowing on game cartridges is bad for them. As such you NEVER do it, even when the games won’t start and that would definitely fix it and... and...//YOU KNOW WHAT FINE, IT IS LIKE YOU ARE LINKA THE PLANETEER AND THE FUSSY SNES CARTRIDGE IS A BAD GUY WHO WANTS TO POLLUTE THE EARTH FOR REASONS WHICH ARE NEVER REALLY EXPLORED. OR SOMETHING.//Gah. It feels great to finally admit it.</cell>
    <cell address="C104" />
  </row>
  <row row="105">
    <cell address="A105">NAR_1_1_BLOW_ON_SNESGAMES</cell>
    <cell address="B105">But really, you don’t have time to play games right now.</cell>
    <cell address="C105" />
  </row>
  <row row="106">
    <cell address="A106">NAR_1_1_LOOK_TAP_SHOES</cell>
    <cell address="B106">Along with ballet, you also study tap dancing. You haven't decided which you prefer: ballet is fun, but tap's also fun, in a different kind of way. //You have considered blending the two, wearing one tap shoe and one ballet shoe at the same time, but decided to fully master both and earn the respect of your teachers before unveiling your prodigious "ballap" technique to the world.</cell>
    <cell address="C106" />
  </row>
  <row row="107">
    <cell address="A107">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_TAP_SHOES</cell>
    <cell address="B107">Some people hide secret keys in the toes of their shoes! Shoes they’re not actually wearing, generally. You think. You’ve never been entirely clear on this practice, which is why you keep yours inside the womb of a toy dog.</cell>
    <cell address="C107" />
  </row>
  <row row="108">
    <cell address="A108">NAR_1_1_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_TAP_SHOES</cell>
    <cell address="B108">Some people hide secret keys in the toes of their shoes! Shoes they’re not actually wearing, generally. You think. You’ve never been entirely clear on this practice, which is why you keep yours inside the womb of a toy dog.</cell>
    <cell address="C108" />
  </row>
  <row row="109">
    <cell address="A109">NAR_1_1_LOOK_TOYS</cell>
    <cell address="B109">This is your Display Of Cute Animals, rated from most to least cute. //Hmm. Upon inspection, you're pretty sure that Popple should be a few slots to the left. You'll fix it next time you can get a ladder in here.</cell>
    <cell address="C109" />
  </row>
  <row row="110">
    <cell address="A110">NAR_1_1_LOOK_TV</cell>
    <cell address="B110">You don't use this TV to actually "watch TV". The cable line doesn't even run up here. This boob-tube is strictly for the vidya games. If you tried watching TV, you'd just get a lot of staticky garbage and lame network crap. Nickelodeon's programming is where it's at. It's the bleeding edge of cool for the youth of today, you read once. And then you nodded sagely, because you agreed.</cell>
    <cell address="C110" />
  </row>
  <row row="111">
    <cell address="A111">NAR_1_1_LOOK_VET_KIT_AFTERFIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B111">The perfect accessory for the youth who claims she wants to be a veterinarian when she grows up!</cell>
    <cell address="C111" />
  </row>
  <row row="112">
    <cell address="A112">NAR_1_1_LOOK_VET_KIT_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B112">The perfect accessory for the youth who claims she wants to be a veterinarian when she grows up! //Yeah, by now you're old enough to figure you'll probably get roped into doing something a lot more boring for a living, but it's still fun to open up your kit sometimes and relive younger Joey's daydreams about patching up cute sick animals and letting them nuzzle you in adorable gratitude.</cell>
    <cell address="C112" />
  </row>
  <row row="113">
    <cell address="A113">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WALKIE_TALKIE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B113">It's your trusty WALKIE-TALKIE. Your BROTHER got a pair of them out of that paranoid whackjob catalog of his and gave you one. //You have no idea why he got a set made for conspiracy bozos instead of just a normal set, but whatever. Now you keep it around in case of an emergency, which you guess is exactly the thing that is happening now. //Aw, who are you kidding. You only keep it around because it's just some junk you didn't have anything better to do with than leave lying around for however long it was gonna keep being there. That's how it is with junk. //Still, if anyone asks, you'll say it's for emergencies. Yeah.</cell>
    <cell address="C113" />
  </row>
  <row row="114">
    <cell address="A114">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B114">It's your trusty WALKIE-TALKIE. For EMERGENCIES.</cell>
    <cell address="C114" />
  </row>
  <row row="115">
    <cell address="A115">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B115">You can see the whole backyard from this window, but you're almost afraid to look. //But you'll probably look anyway, because fear is for cowards.</cell>
    <cell address="C115" />
  </row>
  <row row="116">
    <cell address="A116">NAR_1_1_BAR_WINDOW_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B116">So, cards on the table, you’ve never been exactly sure what BARRING a window means. Wait, it’s probably just jamming a metal bar up there so it can’t be opened. OK. You don’t have one of those.</cell>
    <cell address="C116" />
  </row>
  <row row="117">
    <cell address="A117">NAR_1_1_UNPLUG_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B117">Your window isn’t plugged in. Why would... what does that even mean? Plugged into what? It’s a hole in the side of the house filled in with glass. You decide to chalk this loonytoons nutso idea up to your current case of MONSTER RATTLES.</cell>
    <cell address="C117" />
  </row>
  <row row="118">
    <cell address="A118">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_BUSHES</cell>
    <cell address="B118">You eye the bushes suspiciously, but you don't see anything else popping out of them... yet.</cell>
    <cell address="C118" />
  </row>
  <row row="119">
    <cell address="A119">NAR_1_1_LEAP_TO_SAFETY_WINDOW_CU_BUSHES</cell>
    <cell address="B119">You’d probably break every leg in your body!! And then wouldn’t YOU just be the tastiest monster snack in town, all of your legs pre-broken and everything. No thanks!</cell>
    <cell address="C119" />
  </row>
  <row row="120">
    <cell address="A120">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_DOGHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B120">Poor puppy! If that icky snakey thing hurt her – well, you'd use your budding VETERINARY SKILLS to patch her up and make it all better, but you'd also be very angry! //Right now she doesn't seem to want to come out of her doghouse. You don't blame her!</cell>
    <cell address="C120" />
  </row>
  <row row="121">
    <cell address="A121">NAR_1_1_CALL_FOR_HELP_WINDOW_CU_DOGHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B121">The only thing that big softie could protect you from is a rampaging bowl of kibble. She wants no part of this.</cell>
    <cell address="C121" />
  </row>
  <row row="122">
    <cell address="A122">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_FLASHINGLIGHT</cell>
    <cell address="B122">Good grief. What is that goofball even trying to do, flashing that lantern at you? Is that Morse code? You don't know Morse code, and he dang well knows it. //He's probably trying to get you to talk to him on your WALKIE-TALKIE. You really could have figured that out without all the covert ops nonsense.</cell>
    <cell address="C122" />
  </row>
  <row row="123">
    <cell address="A123">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_FLASHINGLIGHT_AFTER_JUDE_CONVO</cell>
    <cell address="B123">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C123" />
  </row>
  <row row="124">
    <cell address="A124">NAR_1_1_CONSIDER_SIGNIFICANCE_WINDOW_CU_FLASHINGLIGHT</cell>
    <cell address="B124">You briefly muse on the metaphorical significance of the FLASHING LIGHT. What could it represent? The past? The future? AMERICA?//It’s your stupid brother.</cell>
    <cell address="C124" />
  </row>
  <row row="125">
    <cell address="A125">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_LEAF_PILE</cell>
    <cell address="B125">They're scattered all over the yard now. Sure was fun jumping in them. It's like you always say. Sucks to be a tidy leaf heap near autumn hooligans. OK you never once said that, but you'll rake it up later. //If there IS a later.</cell>
    <cell address="C125" />
  </row>
  <row row="126">
    <cell address="A126">NAR_1_1_REMINISCE_WINDOW_CU_LEAF_PILE</cell>
    <cell address="B126">Remember when you were raking up those leaves? Your dog knocked JUDE over, and you laughed, and then everything turned to monsters. Ah, memories!</cell>
    <cell address="C126" />
  </row>
  <row row="127">
    <cell address="A127">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_SKY</cell>
    <cell address="B127">The sun has just set, making for a glorious autumn eve. As such, autumnal evening glory radiates from the heavens, kissing the clouds on its way down to Earth. //Stupid clouds. THEY don't have to worry about monsters. Clouds don't gotta worry about NOTHIN'.</cell>
    <cell address="C127" />
  </row>
  <row row="128">
    <cell address="A128">NAR_1_1_SEEK_ANSWERS_IN_THE_SKY_SKY</cell>
    <cell address="B128">Who ever heard of getting answers from the SKY? Outrageous! Well, except astronomers. And astronauts. Meteorologists, too. Wait, didn’t sailors use the stars to navigate? You remember that from somewhere.// OK, but you’re not any of those things (YET). The sky is still silent to you.</cell>
    <cell address="C128" />
  </row>
  <row row="129">
    <cell address="A129">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_TREEHOUSE_AFTERFIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B129">Jude's TREEHOUSE. What's he doing in there? Forget it, you don't even wanna know.</cell>
    <cell address="C129" />
  </row>
  <row row="130">
    <cell address="A130">NAR_1_1_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_TREEHOUSE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B130">Looks like Jude scurried up to his tree house to get away from that thing. He acts like it's like his MISSION CONTROL ROOM up there, like a goofy kid legitimately has any secret business of that sort. //You're not allowed up there, he says. To which you reply, you'd rather step on a rake than set foot in his rickety little nerd hut. //You school him so often, you really should be pulling in a teacher's salary.</cell>
    <cell address="C130" />
  </row>
  <row row="131">
    <cell address="A131">NAR_1_1_OPEN_DIARY_LOCKED_AFTERFIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B131">You need the DIARY KEY to open it.</cell>
    <cell address="C131" />
  </row>
  <row row="132">
    <cell address="A132">NAR_1_1_OPEN_DIARY_LOCKED_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B132">It's locked! You'll need to find the DIARY KEY, which you keep hidden to prevent snooping kid brothers from prying into your personal affairs. //Where did you put that key again?? And on the ONE DAY something happens to you that's worth Dear Diarying over! //Diary will surely find this monster crisis SO much more interesting than your half-hearted attempts to rate the boys at school, whose hunkiness attributes tend to be dubious AT BEST.</cell>
    <cell address="C132" />
  </row>
  <row row="133">
    <cell address="A133">NAR_1_1_SEARCH_PUPPY_SURPRISE</cell>
    <cell address="B133">You reach inside the expecting plush canine, and... //## Puppy Surprise is having puppies! ##</cell>
    <cell address="C133" />
  </row>
  <row row="134">
    <cell address="A134">NAR_1_1_PLAY_SIMON</cell>
    <cell address="B134">OK, one game for old time's sake.</cell>
    <cell address="C134" />
  </row>
  <row row="135">
    <cell address="A135">NAR_1_1_PLAYING_SIMON</cell>
    <cell address="B135">Wow, it's really been a while. You wonder if it still works.</cell>
    <cell address="C135" />
  </row>
  <row row="136">
    <cell address="A136">NAR_1_1_PLAYED_SIMON</cell>
    <cell address="B136">It seems the green button is broken. What a pity. It's like you always say, starting now. A game is only as fun as its least broken part.</cell>
    <cell address="C136" />
  </row>
  <row row="137">
    <cell address="A137">NAR_1_1_TAKE_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_DIARY_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B137">You collect the key from its plush hiding place.</cell>
    <cell address="C137" />
  </row>
  <row row="138">
    <cell address="A138">NAR_1_1_TAKE_PUPPY_SURPRISE_CU_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B138">You think maybe you should keep this close. Just a feeling.</cell>
    <cell address="C138" />
  </row>
  <row row="139">
    <cell address="A139">NAR_1_1_TAKE_TAP_SHOES</cell>
    <cell address="B139">You add the TAP DANCE ABILITECH to your TECHNICHE. Yep, those are the words that refer to those concepts. You learn them literally just now. //Hot wow, your feet are suddenly AFLAME with the spirit of DANCE! Tippety-tappety tip tip tap!</cell>
    <cell address="C139" />
  </row>
  <row row="140">
    <cell address="A140">NAR_1_1_TAKE_VET_KIT</cell>
    <cell address="B140">Ehh, leave it. You are at WAR with one or more scary monsters. What are you going to do, HEAL them to death?!</cell>
    <cell address="C140" />
  </row>
  <row row="141">
    <cell address="A141">NAR_1_1_SCAVENGE_VET_KIT</cell>
    <cell address="B141">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C141" />
  </row>
  <row row="142">
    <cell address="A142">NAR_1_1_TAKE_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B142">Feels light. Either you're getting stronger as you become a strapping young teen, or...</cell>
    <cell address="C142" />
  </row>
  <row row="143">
    <cell address="A143">NAR_1_1_BECOME_TRUCKER_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B143">AH, BREAKER BREAKER ONE-NINE THIS IS BIG RUBBER DUCK, ABOUT TO, UH... NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TRUCKERS SAY AFTER THAT FIRST PART, ACTUALLY. OVER AND OUT. TEN FOUR.</cell>
    <cell address="C143" />
  </row>
  <row row="144">
    <cell address="A144">NAR_1_1_ITM_WALKIE_TALKIE_COMPUTER</cell>
    <cell address="B144">You can't just plug THIS THING into THAT THING without using some ABSURD CABLE that would be a nightmare to locate, assuming it even exists.//Maybe in some other universe, computers can interface with vocal devices and make you sound like a SUAVE ROBOT, but around here you make do with what you got.</cell>
    <cell address="C144" />
  </row>
  <row row="145">
    <cell address="A145">NAR_1_1_UNLOCK_DIARY</cell>
    <cell address="B145">You unlock and open your DIARY. Nice. Juicy secrets, here you come! Except they're just your boring secrets, so you don't care.</cell>
    <cell address="C145" />
  </row>
  <row row="146">
    <cell address="A146">NAR_1_1_USE_COMPUTER_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B146">The computer refuses to turn on without its precious electricity. Spoiled computer.</cell>
    <cell address="C146" />
  </row>
  <row row="147">
    <cell address="A147">NAR_1_1_USE_COMPUTER_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B147">The modem's not dialing. Jude's probably left the phone in his room off the hook off again. If only you lived in a two-line household! What an incomprehensible luxury.</cell>
    <cell address="C147" />
  </row>
  <row row="148">
    <cell address="A148">NAR_1_1_USE_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B148">This is no time for video horseplay!!! You've got bigger fish to cower from, safely in your bedroom.</cell>
    <cell address="C148" />
  </row>
  <row row="149">
    <cell address="A149">NAR_1_1_TAKE_CONTROLLER_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B149">When you were little, you used to stick the end of the controller cord in your pocket and pretend you were controlling... YOURSELF! Courageous JOEY, off on an exciting adventure, fighting monsters, solving puzzles!// You don’t need the controller anymore, but you wouldn’t mind having a little of that old courage back.</cell>
    <cell address="C149" />
  </row>
  <row row="150">
    <cell address="A150">NAR_1_1_AB_TAP_DANCE_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B150">Maybe, someday, you will be able to dance with a video game. But the science just isn’t there yet. Such a game would be truly... revolutionary. You’re not sure why you paused just now, in your head.</cell>
    <cell address="C150" />
  </row>
  <row row="151">
    <cell address="A151">NAR_1_1_AB_BALLET_DANCE_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B151">Maybe, someday, you will be able to dance with a video game. But the science just isn’t there yet. Such a game would be truly... revolutionary. You’re not sure why you paused just now, in your head.</cell>
    <cell address="C151" />
  </row>
  <row row="152">
    <cell address="A152">NAR_1_1_WINDOW_CU_INTRO</cell>
    <cell address="B152">You take a peek out the window into the backyard. No monsters in sight at the moment. Phew! Now where'd your KID BROTHER and PET DOG get to?</cell>
    <cell address="C152" />
  </row>
  <row row="153">
    <cell address="A153">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_CLARISSA_POSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B153">There is no need to unlock the mysteries of CLARISSA. She is happy to EXPLAIN IT ALL.</cell>
    <cell address="C153" />
  </row>
  <row row="154">
    <cell address="A154">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_SNES</cell>
    <cell address="B154">You jab your diary key at the SNES, whimsically hoping this combo might save the game of YOUR VERY LIFE. But it doesn't. It just scratches the SNES a bit.</cell>
    <cell address="C154" />
  </row>
  <row row="155">
    <cell address="A155">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_COMPUTER</cell>
    <cell address="B155">Sorry but that's the key to your diary, and your diary IS NOT on your computer. But... // What if?! It could be ON LINE. A LIVING JOURNAL of sorts...</cell>
    <cell address="C155" />
  </row>
  <row row="156">
    <cell address="A156">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_DRESSER</cell>
    <cell address="B156">You get so excited about unlocking your DIARY that you accidentally jab the DIARY KEY right into your dresser! Maybe if you INSPECT the dresser, you can get a closer look, and also chill out just a bit about reading your own DIARY.</cell>
    <cell address="C156" />
  </row>
  <row row="157">
    <cell address="A157">NAR_1_1_ITM_DIARY_KEY_VET_KIT</cell>
    <cell address="B157">You attempt to unlock the JUNIOR VETERINARIAN'S MEDKIT with your DIARY KEY. You fail, because this is clearly the key to your DIARY! Also because the MEDKIT is already UNLOCKED.// By which you mean there's no lock on it at all.</cell>
    <cell address="C157" />
  </row>
  <row row="158">
    <cell address="A158">NAR_1_1_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_VET_KIT</cell>
    <cell address="B158">Maybe this thing goes to your JUNIOR VETERINARIAN'S MEDKIT? Probably not, since the key is a treasured family heirloom, and also because your MEDKIT has no lock.</cell>
    <cell address="C158" />
  </row>
  <row row="159">
    <cell address="A159">NAR_1_1_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_CLOSET</cell>
    <cell address="B159">You’re fairly certain this hasn’t just been the key to your closet door this whole time. Supporting this hypothesis is the fact that your closet door does not actually feature a lock.</cell>
    <cell address="C159" />
  </row>
  <row row="160">
    <cell address="A160">NAR_1_9_HALLWAY_INTRO</cell>
    <cell address="B160">Looks like the coast is clear. For now. //Better hurry over to the HALL CLOSET and retrieve your WEAPON, before that crafty old snake can get the drop on you.</cell>
    <cell address="C160" />
  </row>
  <row row="161">
    <cell address="A161">NAR_1_2_LOOK_SUPER_SOAKER</cell>
    <cell address="B161">With this, you can shoot a small stream of water up to FIFTY FEET away! With this you'll NEVER come across something needing moisture 49 feet away and be unable to help. //It's a public service, really.</cell>
    <cell address="C161" />
  </row>
  <row row="162">
    <cell address="A162">NAR_1_2_LOOK_JUDE_ROOM_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B162">This is the door to your neurotic dork of a brother's MAXIMUM SECURITY BEDROOM. He keeps it locked up tight because of all the silly conspiracy "work" he does in there. //You sincerely doubt you'll be entering this room any time soon even if you were hellbent on the idea. But really, why would you even want to? It's surely full of nerd stink and goober crud, not to mention where his PET dwells. //You love all animals, but just the same, that's one you'd rather let Jude deal with.</cell>
    <cell address="C162" />
  </row>
  <row row="163">
    <cell address="A163">NAR_1_2_LOOK_JUDE_ROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B163">Jude's bedroom, the Fortress of Nerditude. You're definitely not going in there.</cell>
    <cell address="C163" />
  </row>
  <row row="164">
    <cell address="A164">NAR_1_2_PRANK_HILARIOUSLY_JUDE_ROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B164">The door to his room is locked and Jude is in his treehouse, so any prank you could set up out here in the hall would almost certainly be discovered before he entered! Also, you are at very real risk of being devoured by man-eating monsters at any moment. Just, you know. A reminder.</cell>
    <cell address="C164" />
  </row>
  <row row="165">
    <cell address="A165">NAR_1_2_ITM_POGS_JUDE_ROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B165">You slip a few under the door. When all this is over, when everything that’s gone wrong has been set right again, when the monsters live on only in your nightmares... then he’ll know... that you have some of his pogs.</cell>
    <cell address="C165" />
  </row>
  <row row="166">
    <cell address="A166">NAR_1_2_OPEN_JUDE_BEDROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B166">He always keeps it locked. Even if you did manage to get in there he probably has traps or something set up. Not worth trying to get gum out of your hair for the second time.</cell>
    <cell address="C166" />
  </row>
  <row row="167">
    <cell address="A167">NAR_1_2_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_JUDE_ROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B167">The key isn't going to work here.</cell>
    <cell address="C167" />
  </row>
  <row row="168">
    <cell address="A168">NAR_1_2_LOOK_BEDROOM_DOOR_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B168">The door to your room. Heavily personalized, of course. Jude thinks he's the only one who can nerd up his door. But you showed him two can, and in fact WILL, play at that game.</cell>
    <cell address="C168" />
  </row>
  <row row="169">
    <cell address="A169">NAR_1_2_LOOK_BEDROOM_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B169">Your door could probably use more stickers.</cell>
    <cell address="C169" />
  </row>
  <row row="170">
    <cell address="A170">NAR_1_2_LOOK_BEDROOM_DOOR_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B170">The door to your bedroom. You hear distinct sounds of MONSTER COMMOTION.</cell>
    <cell address="C170" />
  </row>
  <row row="171">
    <cell address="A171">NAR_1_2_EXIT_BEDROOM_DOOR_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B171">That does not seem wise as there is most likely a terrible, LITTLE GIRL-EATING MENACE in there. Or at the very least, an unpleasant creature more than willing to slap you ineffectually.</cell>
    <cell address="C171" />
  </row>
  <row row="172">
    <cell address="A172">NAR_1_2_LOOK_STATUE_WITH_DARTS</cell>
    <cell address="B172">From the last Nerf war with Jude. Balinda here provides great cover for those who are really terrible with firearms, namely you.</cell>
    <cell address="C172" />
  </row>
  <row row="173">
    <cell address="A173">NAR_1_2_SCROUNGE_AMMO_STATUE_WITH_DARTS</cell>
    <cell address="B173">You don't use guns.</cell>
    <cell address="C173" />
  </row>
  <row row="174">
    <cell address="A174">NAR_1_2_LOOK_CARDBOARD_BOX_SHELF</cell>
    <cell address="B174">Aw yes, here it is!</cell>
    <cell address="C174" />
  </row>
  <row row="175">
    <cell address="A175">NAR_1_2_ITM_POGS_STATUE_WITH_DARTS</cell>
    <cell address="B175">You cast a few tokens before the feet of the local TOTEM OF COMBAT. You feel her gratitude pour out in wave after wave of... POWER. Getting... stronger!! You can do anyth - no, it’s gone. Oh well.</cell>
    <cell address="C175" />
  </row>
  <row row="176">
    <cell address="A176">NAR_1_2_SEARCH_CARDBOARD_BOX_FLOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B176">You dump it all out and snag the whole lot. A FLASHLIGHT? Yours now. Some PET TREATS? Weird, but hey it's a weird night.// You put the BALLET SLIPPERS immediately into your TECHNICHE. You can now do ballet dance too. Your ABILITECH savvy is SKYROCKETING. No one kid should have so much power. Use it wisely.</cell>
    <cell address="C176" />
  </row>
  <row row="177">
    <cell address="A177">NAR_1_2_TAKE_CARDBOARD_BOX_SHELF</cell>
    <cell address="B177">The small legs and arms of a fourteen year-old child can't possibly reach such heights. But the BOX does look somewhat precarious. //Perhaps there is a way to knock it down?</cell>
    <cell address="C177" />
  </row>
  <row row="178">
    <cell address="A178">NAR_1_2_LOOK_CARDBOARD_BOX_FLOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B178">You hope there was nothing fragile in there. Wonder what's stashed in here?</cell>
    <cell address="C178" />
  </row>
  <row row="179">
    <cell address="A179">NAR_1_2_LOOK_CARDBOARD_BOX_FLOOR_SEARCHED</cell>
    <cell address="B179">There is nothing left in the box but cardboard-scented air.</cell>
    <cell address="C179" />
  </row>
  <row row="180">
    <cell address="A180">NAR_1_2_LOOK_DRESSER_WITH_LAMPSHADE</cell>
    <cell address="B180">The lampshade on this dresser renders it marginally more useful than a dresser that doesn't have a lampshade on it. For example, THIS dresser allows you to easily illuminate its top, at your merest whim!</cell>
    <cell address="C180" />
  </row>
  <row row="181">
    <cell address="A181">NAR_1_2_PORTAL_KEY_DRESSER_WITH_LAMPSHADE</cell>
    <cell address="B181">You don't know. Those two don't share a VISUAL MOTIF. On the other hand... maybe that's what the locked dresser WANTS you to think... //Okay no. The key doesn't fit.</cell>
    <cell address="C181" />
  </row>
  <row row="182">
    <cell address="A182">NAR_1_2_LOOK_SUPER_SOAKER</cell>
    <cell address="B182">With this, you can shoot a small stream of water up to FIFTY FEET away! With this you'll NEVER come across something needing moisture 49 feet away and be unable to help. //It's a public service, really.</cell>
    <cell address="C182" />
  </row>
  <row row="183">
    <cell address="A183">NAR_1_2_LOOK_SIDE_TABLE</cell>
    <cell address="B183">It’s your mother’s jewelry box, a priceless heirloom of immeasurable sentimental value. Also there appear to be some empty cans of Pringles that your brother left on the hallway side table, for reasons unfathomable to a rational mind.</cell>
    <cell address="C183" />
  </row>
  <row row="184">
    <cell address="A184">NAR_1_2_LOOK_GLOBE-LIKE_SCULPTURE</cell>
    <cell address="B184">It is a globe-like sculpture with an arrow that conveniently alerts you to the location of the ceiling! Ah! So THAT'S where it is! Thank you, globe-like sculpture!</cell>
    <cell address="C184" />
  </row>
  <row row="185">
    <cell address="A185">NAR_1_2_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_GLOBE-LIKE_SCULPTURE</cell>
    <cell address="B185">Unfortunately, you can't find any place on this GLOBE-LIKE SCULPTURE for a key. You're glad there isn't a giant keyhole on the surface of the actual planet, though. It would be a horrible thing to fall into.</cell>
    <cell address="C185" />
  </row>
  <row row="186">
    <cell address="A186">NAR_1_2_LOOK_DOWNSTAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B186">The staircase down to the first floor of the house. Dare you proceed? //Traipsing through your house alone has always been spooky enough, even when the menace was only the figment of a silly kid's brain. Alas, now it is a figment of REALITY.</cell>
    <cell address="C186" />
  </row>
  <row row="187">
    <cell address="A187">NAR_1_2_LOOK_DOWNSTAIRS_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B187">There's a real ROWDY CREW making a racket down there!</cell>
    <cell address="C187" />
  </row>
  <row row="188">
    <cell address="A188">NAR_1_2_EXIT_DOWNSTAIRS_NO_FLASHLIGHT_CONTAINER</cell>
    <cell address="B188">It looks pretty dang dark down there. Maybe you should get out your FLASHLIGHT first, before you bound downstairs like it’s Christmas up in here or something?</cell>
    <cell address="C188" />
  </row>
  <row row="189">
    <cell address="A189">NAR_1_2_EXIT_DOWNSTAIRS_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B189">You just fled from that vulgar rabble and their gnashing maws. There's no way you're going back down there!</cell>
    <cell address="C189" />
  </row>
  <row row="190">
    <cell address="A190">NAR_1_2_ITM_PET_TREATS_DOWNSTAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B190">Maybe you could scatter them across the stairs, so the monsters trip and fall! Or... so they think there's more food this way. Dang it. Another brilliant maneuver DOWN THE TUBES.</cell>
    <cell address="C190" />
  </row>
  <row row="191">
    <cell address="A191">NAR_1_2_ITM_POGS_DOWNSTAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B191">No, go right ahead! Waste valuable ESCAPE TIME by performing fascinating POG-related experiments on the staircase! Just go completely POGWILD and see what happens!//SPOILERS: The monsters will be unimpressed by your hijinks, and you’ll DIE FOR NOTHING. You’ll be given a proper burial and a humble tombstone, succinctly marked by the word “OOPS.”</cell>
    <cell address="C191" />
  </row>
  <row row="192">
    <cell address="A192">NAR_1_2_LOOK_HALL_CLOSET</cell>
    <cell address="B192">It's the hallway closet. If memory serves, there's a box full of some old belongings of yours in here. You wonder if it has what you're looking for?</cell>
    <cell address="C192" />
  </row>
  <row row="193">
    <cell address="A193">NAR_1_2_LOOK_HALL_CLOSET_OPEN</cell>
    <cell address="B193">You think back to before. Back to when this closet door was shut. You had a reasonably good guess about what was inside--but now? Now your hypothesis has been verified. That’s called science, Joey. CLOSET SCIENCE.</cell>
    <cell address="C193" />
  </row>
  <row row="194">
    <cell address="A194">NAR_1_2_LOOK_ATTIC_STAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B194">It's been a while since you've been up in the ATTIC. Historically speaking, it's been TOTALLY OFF LIMITS. Pa's word is law. //But now that you think about it... who's around to stop you? Certainly not him.</cell>
    <cell address="C194" />
  </row>
  <row row="195">
    <cell address="A195">NAR_1_3_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_ATTIC_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B195">It doesn't work.</cell>
    <cell address="C195" />
  </row>
  <row row="196">
    <cell address="A196">NAR_1_3_EXIT_HALLWAY_DOOR_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B196">That door is the only thing separating you from untold magnitudes of wanton monster calamity. Leaving it shut could significantly prolong your life.</cell>
    <cell address="C196" />
  </row>
  <row row="197">
    <cell address="A197">NAR_1_3_LOOK_ATTIC_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B197">On the rare occasions he is home, Pa can be heard bumping around up here while tending to his hoard of stupid antique trash. Or, priceless artifacts, you mean.</cell>
    <cell address="C197" />
  </row>
  <row row="198">
    <cell address="A198">NAR_1_3_OPEN_ATTIC_DOOR_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B198">You need to use the ATTIC KEY to UNLOCK it! //This should be done rather quickly and with much haste. Like, boatloads of haste.</cell>
    <cell address="C198" />
  </row>
  <row row="199">
    <cell address="A199">NAR_1_3_LOOK_ATTIC_STUFF_BOTTOM</cell>
    <cell address="B199">It's a bunch of stuff that should be moved into the attic at some point! Or, at the very least, to the top of the stairs to join the other stuff that should be moved into the attic at some point up there. //There is quite a nuanced hierarchy of junk in your house, now that you think about it. Rich strata of junk clusters distinguished only by their distance to the promised land of musty garbage, a.k.a., The Attic.</cell>
    <cell address="C199" />
  </row>
  <row row="200">
    <cell address="A200">NAR_1_3_LOOK_ATTIC_STUFF_TOP</cell>
    <cell address="B200">This is a bunch of stuff that should be moved into the attic at some point! There's some toys here too that you don't play with that much anymore.</cell>
    <cell address="C200" />
  </row>
  <row row="201">
    <cell address="A201">NAR_1_3_LOOK_CATERPILLAR</cell>
    <cell address="B201">This toy caterpillar was supposed to be so you could learn "how to cure caterpillar diseases" but it turns out a) there's not any caterpillar diseases that you know how to cure, and b) plush caterpillars don't get sick anyway. //Still pretty cute though!</cell>
    <cell address="C201" />
  </row>
  <row row="202">
    <cell address="A202">NAR_1_3_ITM_PET_TREATS_CATERPILLAR</cell>
    <cell address="B202">No! He has his own treats! They're like these little plastic apples that stick to his mouth with MAGNETS or something. You... you've got to see it in action again sometime. It's phenomenal.</cell>
    <cell address="C202" />
  </row>
  <row row="203">
    <cell address="A203">NAR_1_3_LOOK_HALLWAY_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B203">The HALLWAY DOOR seems spookier from this side. You suppose that's the ATTIC'S SPOOKY AURA just doing it's thing. Frankly, you feel a little spookier yourself, just basking in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C203" />
  </row>
  <row row="204">
    <cell address="A204">NAR_1_3_LOOK_HALLWAY_DOOR_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B204">This leads right back to the HALLWAY, which is lousy with monsters. They’ll bust through that door any second, so think fast!</cell>
    <cell address="C204" />
  </row>
  <row row="205">
    <cell address="A205">NAR_1_3_LOOK_SLINKY</cell>
    <cell address="B205">For as long as you can remember, this SLINKY has remained on these very stairs, like something akin to STONEHENGE, eternally trapped between slinks, unmovable and unshakable. The true eighth wonder of the world.</cell>
    <cell address="C205" />
  </row>
  <row row="206">
    <cell address="A206">NAR_1_3_TAKE_SLINKY</cell>
    <cell address="B206">You're kind of loath to touch it and disturb whatever astronomically improbable equilibrium is at play. Best just leave it be.</cell>
    <cell address="C206" />
  </row>
  <row row="207">
    <cell address="A207">NAR_1_3_ITM_PIGEON_SLINKY</cell>
    <cell address="B207">The PIGEON gives the SLINKY a sly and knowing look before immediately becoming tangled in the SLINKY. You help him out. Unbelievably, the SLINKY remains in the same position as before. It’s the crummiest miracle anyone has ever seen.</cell>
    <cell address="C207" />
  </row>
  <row row="208">
    <cell address="A208">NAR_1_3_ITM_POGS_SLINKY</cell>
    <cell address="B208">Wow. When considered together, these popular toys are actually pretty terrible. You're sort of astonished that anyone has ever had fun with them!</cell>
    <cell address="C208" />
  </row>
  <row row="209">
    <cell address="A209">NAR_1_3_OPEN_ATTIC_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B209">The attic door is locked! You'll need the ATTIC KEY to get in here. //It's really spooky in there, but it might be a good hiding spot for when things get too hot to handle.</cell>
    <cell address="C209" />
  </row>
  <row row="210">
    <cell address="A210">NAR_1_4_LOOK_BOTTOM_PHOTOS</cell>
    <cell address="B210">Old family photos, from a time before you existed.</cell>
    <cell address="C210" />
  </row>
  <row row="211">
    <cell address="A211">NAR_1_4_LOOK_BOTTOM_PHOTOS_CU_BEAUTY_PHOTO</cell>
    <cell address="B211">OOH LA LA. There's mom lookin' TRES GLAMNIFIQUE. When you grow up, you hope this is what mirrors will look like.</cell>
    <cell address="C211" />
  </row>
  <row row="212">
    <cell address="A212">NAR_1_4_LOOK_BOTTOM_PHOTOS_CU_OLD_PHOTO</cell>
    <cell address="B212">This is an oldie, but goodie. It's PA, and someone you presume to be his sister, as kids. It was so long ago. You like to think that, however you feel about your father now, you would have gotten along famously with these two adorable rapscallions.</cell>
    <cell address="C212" />
  </row>
  <row row="213">
    <cell address="A213">NAR_1_4_LOOK_BOTTOM_PHOTOS_CU_WEDDING_PHOTO</cell>
    <cell address="B213">MOM is the picture of GRACE and RADIANCE. And PA is just PA. Seriously, has he EVER changed his look? Sometimes you wonder if he was born with his spectacles and mustache. Or at least one of the two.</cell>
    <cell address="C213" />
  </row>
  <row row="214">
    <cell address="A214">NAR_1_4_LOOK_DOWN</cell>
    <cell address="B214">The LIVING ROOM is downstairs.</cell>
    <cell address="C214" />
  </row>
  <row row="215">
    <cell address="A215">NAR_1_4_LOOK_SERPENT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B215">This creepy statue showed up one day with your father. You have no idea what its deal is, but you can imagine it involves snakes and, oh I don't know, MYSTERIES??</cell>
    <cell address="C215" />
  </row>
  <row row="216">
    <cell address="A216">NAR_1_4_ITM_SPICE_MIX_SERPENT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B216">Ah, if only this were a real snake! Then you could chop it up, add the SPICE MIX, and fry it in a pan with some fricasseed crawdads! And if only you were some kind of swamp person, so that didn’t sound incredibly disgusting!</cell>
    <cell address="C216" />
  </row>
  <row row="217">
    <cell address="A217">NAR_1_4_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_SERPENT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B217">Huh. You were about to think some snarky quip about how these two things are OBVIOUSLY not related, so why would you try to use one with the other, JEEZ, but something about this key does remind you of snakes. Weird.//You have a feeling these two things aren’t actually related in any practical way, though. What the heck were you thinking, trying to use them together? It doesn’t even have a keyhole. COME ON.</cell>
    <cell address="C217" />
  </row>
  <row row="218">
    <cell address="A218">NAR_1_4_ITM_PET_TREATS_SERPENT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B218">This snake is a statue, and cares little for treats. You, for your part, care little for snakes.</cell>
    <cell address="C218" />
  </row>
  <row row="219">
    <cell address="A219">NAR_1_4_ITM_PIGEON_SERPENT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B219">The PIGEON is surprisingly unperturbed by your attempt to feed it to a stone snake. The PIGEON gives you a look, as if to say “Who do you think you’re fooling with this sad little performance? Don’t you have something more important to be doing?”</cell>
    <cell address="C219" />
  </row>
  <row row="220">
    <cell address="A220">NAR_1_4_LOOK_TOP_PHOTOS</cell>
    <cell address="B220">Some recent family photos. You actually took a couple of these yourself! You're well on your way to being a real Ansel Adams! Well, if these were in black and white... and also more of the stunning beauty of the American West and less so of your family... maybe pioneered some new exposure technique... listen, they're still pretty nice photos, alright?</cell>
    <cell address="C220" />
  </row>
  <row row="221">
    <cell address="A221">NAR_1_4_LOOK_TOP_PHOTOS_CU_FAMILY_PHOTO</cell>
    <cell address="B221">You and Jude have a lot of fun memories with your babysitter. By now, probably more racked up with her than you have with MOM and PA combined. You always saw her as a cool and fun older kid, a role model to strive to be like one day! //Until you finally got old enough to realize she's a pretty sucky role model. Still fun and all, but so bad at grownup stuff. Kinda sad. You suddenly wonder what sort of adult role models she's had in her life? That's probably a thing that would be too awkward to ask, so never mind.</cell>
    <cell address="C221" />
  </row>
  <row row="222">
    <cell address="A222">NAR_1_4_LOOK_TOP_PHOTOS_CU_HUNTING_PHOTO</cell>
    <cell address="B222">Ugh. You can't even look at this picture. You deplore cruelty to animals. One of the many ways you and your father never saw eye to eye. One of the other ways was how he never actually looked at you much, let alone at your eyes.</cell>
    <cell address="C222" />
  </row>
  <row row="223">
    <cell address="A223">NAR_1_4_LOOK_TOP_PHOTOS_CU_SCHOOL_PHOTOS</cell>
    <cell address="B223">A lovely diptych of school portraits. The laser background, the bad hair days... simply perfection. //Ha ha, Jude puts the DIP in diptych, you mutter to yourself. Such an unreal burn on the unsuspecting chump, but he probably wouldn't even get it. Come to think of it... maybe neither do you?</cell>
    <cell address="C223" />
  </row>
  <row row="224">
    <cell address="A224">NAR_1_4_LOOK_UP</cell>
    <cell address="B224">Leads back up to the HALLWAY, obviously.</cell>
    <cell address="C224" />
  </row>
  <row row="225">
    <cell address="A225">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B225">That CREEPY MANSION looms large in the darkening shadow. Sometimes you feel like somebody's watching you from the gloomy windows.</cell>
    <cell address="C225" />
  </row>
  <row row="226">
    <cell address="A226">NAR_1_4_OPEN_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B226">No way! Some of those monsters had wings! And the others were many-armed snake monsters, who can probably climb up one story to an open window QUITE easily. Actually, you’re pretty lucky they haven’t just smashed through this window already?</cell>
    <cell address="C226" />
  </row>
  <row row="227">
    <cell address="A227">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_BUSHES</cell>
    <cell address="B227">They need a good pruning. Anything could be hiding in there waiting to jump out! Let this be a critical lesson to everyone. Keep up with your yard work, kids.</cell>
    <cell address="C227" />
  </row>
  <row row="228">
    <cell address="A228">NAR_1_4_ITM_POGS_WINDOW_CU_BUSHES</cell>
    <cell address="B228">Ah, of course! Because POGS are made of CARDBOARD and the BUSHES are, uh... leafy? Alright, you admit it. This idea doesn’t make any sense at all. You put it in the TRASH, where it belongs.</cell>
    <cell address="C228" />
  </row>
  <row row="229">
    <cell address="A229">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_FIGURES</cell>
    <cell address="B229">Um. Who're they? //Are they involved in all the conspiracy stuff Jude's been all worked up about? //Oh god. What if... what if that conspiracy stuff, instead of making zero sense... actually made an amount of sense slightly greater than zero?? You're starting to get nervous.</cell>
    <cell address="C229" />
  </row>
  <row row="230">
    <cell address="A230">NAR_1_4_CALL_FOR_HELP_WINDOW_CU_FIGURES</cell>
    <cell address="B230">They can definitely see the monsters in your yard from where they are, so they’ve made their position on the issue of helping you quite plain. And that position is: standing creepily on a hill.</cell>
    <cell address="C230" />
  </row>
  <row row="231">
    <cell address="A231">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_LEAVES</cell>
    <cell address="B231">Ah, simpler times. A rake. A child. A boring afternoon. That was the life.</cell>
    <cell address="C231" />
  </row>
  <row row="232">
    <cell address="A232">NAR_1_4_ITM_PET_TREATS_WINDOW_CU_LEAVES</cell>
    <cell address="B232">Arrgh! You could have hidden PET TREATS in the leaf pile for your dog to find, nosing around through the leaves all adorable and such. Your determination to make this dream a reality stirs you forth.</cell>
    <cell address="C232" />
  </row>
  <row row="233">
    <cell address="A233">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_MANSION</cell>
    <cell address="B233">Jude always said there was something up with that place, and you never listened. Maybe he was on to something after all.</cell>
    <cell address="C233" />
  </row>
  <row row="234">
    <cell address="A234">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_SKY</cell>
    <cell address="B234">Starting to get dark now. Pff, EVENINGS. So predictable.</cell>
    <cell address="C234" />
  </row>
  <row row="235">
    <cell address="A235">NAR_1_4_LOOK_WINDOW_CU_TREEHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B235">Your brother's still holed up in there. At least he quit blinking all the useless Morse code.</cell>
    <cell address="C235" />
  </row>
  <row row="236">
    <cell address="A236">NAR_1_4_CALL_FOR_HELP_WINDOW_CU_TREEHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B236">You’ve already got a WALKIE-TALKIE for that.</cell>
    <cell address="C236" />
  </row>
  <row row="237">
    <cell address="A237">NAR_1_4_ITM_POGS_WINDOW_CU_TREEHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B237">That would involve you opening the window, probably. Also, that’s ridiculous. Just because Jude is in the TREEHOUSE and the POGS are his doesn’t mean the two objects can interact in a meaningful way. Get your head in the game, Joey.</cell>
    <cell address="C237" />
  </row>
  <row row="238">
    <cell address="A238">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_CAGES</cell>
    <cell address="B238">Why don't you leave that poor bird alone?</cell>
    <cell address="C238" />
  </row>
  <row row="239">
    <cell address="A239">NAR_1_10_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_PORTAL_KEYHOLE</cell>
    <cell address="B239">What? It fits! Repeat: THE GREEN KEY YOU KEPT IN A TOY DOG FITS INTO THE POTENTIALLY DIABOLICAL AND UNDENIABLY MYSTERIOUS KEYHOLE! This is nuts.</cell>
    <cell address="C239" />
  </row>
  <row row="240">
    <cell address="A240">NAR_1_10_LOOK_BROKEN_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell address="B240">Gah! Pa, maybe get just ONE really GOOD globe, and you won't have to fill the house with all these inferior ones.</cell>
    <cell address="C240" />
  </row>
  <row row="241">
    <cell address="A241">NAR_1_10_REPAIR_BROKEN_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell address="B241">The world is in crisis! If only Captain Planet were here! Then the monsters could eat him, and you could escape while they were distracted.</cell>
    <cell address="C241" />
  </row>
  <row row="242">
    <cell address="A242">NAR_1_10_LOOK_CAGES</cell>
    <cell address="B242">Jude's old pigeon cages. You'd suggest he throw them out, but "old cages" definitely fit with the rest of the aesthetic up here.</cell>
    <cell address="C242" />
  </row>
  <row row="243">
    <cell address="A243">NAR_1_10_LOOK_CRANE</cell>
    <cell address="B243">What the heck is a CRANE doing in your attic? Pa, why would you... Better yet, Joey, why would you keep wondering why your crazy old Pa does such things?</cell>
    <cell address="C243" />
  </row>
  <row row="244">
    <cell address="A244">NAR_1_10_LOOK_CRATE</cell>
    <cell address="B244">Another victim of Jude's overzealous crowbarring, no doubt. That boy and his crowbar. Any chance he gets to go prying and jimmying, the kid just goes nutso.</cell>
    <cell address="C244" />
  </row>
  <row row="245">
    <cell address="A245">NAR_1_10_REPAIR_CRATE</cell>
    <cell address="B245">Maybe you can pack yourself in and ship yourself OUT of mortal danger? No, that’s ridiculous. Shipping is always a mistake.</cell>
    <cell address="C245" />
  </row>
  <row row="246">
    <cell address="A246">NAR_1_10_FASHION_CRUDE_ARMAMENTS_CRATE</cell>
    <cell address="B246">You don’t have an ARMAMENTKIND SPECIBUS in your STRIFE DECK, so such an action would be frivolous in the extreme. You’re a little shocked that you even considered it. Keep it together, Joey.</cell>
    <cell address="C246" />
  </row>
  <row row="247">
    <cell address="A247">NAR_1_10_LOOK_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B247">You're glad that you're on this side of the door. This side of the door is for safe little girls. The other side is for monster food. Ideally, never the twain shall meet.</cell>
    <cell address="C247" />
  </row>
  <row row="248">
    <cell address="A248">NAR_1_10_LOOK_DRAPE</cell>
    <cell address="B248">This VAST DRAPE would theoretically be absolutely perfect for hiding something secretive or diabolical. You suddenly wonder aloud, ''I wonder if this drape is hiding something secretive or diabolical?''</cell>
    <cell address="C248" />
  </row>
  <row row="249">
    <cell address="A249">NAR_1_10_CLIMB_DRAPE</cell>
    <cell address="B249">It’s probably not very securely attached to... to... what the heck is this thing, anyway?</cell>
    <cell address="C249" />
  </row>
  <row row="250">
    <cell address="A250">NAR_1_10_PERMANENTLY_IGNORE_DRAPE</cell>
    <cell address="B250">You resolve to ignore this mysterious, alluring DRAPE, this beguiling and bewitching cascade of velvet and mysteries. Mysteries that, you have come to realize (as you continue to ignore this DRAPE, and the object it covers) may be more menacing and monstrous than you knew.//Is the object beneath this DRAPE (which you are still ignoring, with a fierce and focused intensity) the opening note of a sonata in a minor key, or a key that tilts the tumblers locking away the secrets in a young girl’s head, or rather, in her hand?//You have no idea, since you’re obviously ignoring this thing forever.</cell>
    <cell address="C250" />
  </row>
  <row row="251">
    <cell address="A251">NAR_1_10_LOOK_GLOBES_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B251">Why does he love globes so much?? Maybe they remind him of adventure. All the little abstract geological features, the jagged borders of exotic nations, the tiny bumps representing mountains... maybe it all has a way of capturing the imagination. You guess you can see that. //Unfortunately, whenever you look at globes in school or wherever, instead of reminding you of adventure, they just remind you of HIM.</cell>
    <cell address="C251" />
  </row>
  <row row="252">
    <cell address="A252">NAR_1_10_LOOK_GLOBES</cell>
    <cell address="B252">Why does he love globes so much?? Probably remind him of adventure. Lousy mustache-packing adventure glutton.</cell>
    <cell address="C252" />
  </row>
  <row row="253">
    <cell address="A253">NAR_1_10_NAP_IN_GLOBES</cell>
    <cell address="B253">Look, if you’re going to take a nap anywhere, it’s not going to be in this ridiculous pile of broken and almost-certainly-inaccurate GLOBES. It’s going to be in that soft pile of straw over there. But you’re not taking a nap anywhere, so this is really more a question for the philosophers.</cell>
    <cell address="C253" />
  </row>
  <row row="254">
    <cell address="A254">NAR_1_10_ITM_SPICE_MIX_GLOBES</cell>
    <cell address="B254">Nah, you’re really not in the mood for... INTERNATIONAL CUISINE. Ugh. That one was pretty bad. You guess you brought it on yourself, though, trying to use those completely unrelated things together for no reason but to see what would happen.</cell>
    <cell address="C254" />
  </row>
  <row row="255">
    <cell address="A255">NAR_1_10_LOOK_GUN</cell>
    <cell address="B255">Since he got his FIRST-BEST SHOTGUN, this one fell out of favor and now primarily functions as a home to a thick layer of ATTIC DUST. Meanwhile, its favored brother is living out a shotgun's daydream in the hands of your father.</cell>
    <cell address="C255" />
  </row>
  <row row="256">
    <cell address="A256">NAR_1_10_READ_INSCRIPTION_GUN</cell>
    <cell address="B256">To my dearest JAKE, on the occasion of your birthday. May you blast the bejeesus out of anything that menaces you (or for any other reason, I suppose). From your loving sister, JANE.</cell>
    <cell address="C256" />
  </row>
  <row row="257">
    <cell address="A257">NAR_1_10_LOOK_GUNS</cell>
    <cell address="B257">Ick, more of his guns. These are antiques, and would probably fetch a tidy sum at auction. But the only real perk to their antiquity in your view is, it probably means it's been ages since they were used to murder anything furry and precious.</cell>
    <cell address="C257" />
  </row>
  <row row="258">
    <cell address="A258">NAR_1_10_ASSESS_VALUE_ANTIQUE_GUNS</cell>
    <cell address="B258">In the cold calculus of capitalism, the value of these guns is merely a function of whatever someone will pay for them. When that someone is you, their value is pretty much nil.</cell>
    <cell address="C258" />
  </row>
  <row row="259">
    <cell address="A259">NAR_1_10_LOOK_HAND_IN_JAR</cell>
    <cell address="B259">Well, turns out you live in a house that has a hand in a jar in it. You must now carry this knowledge with you forever.</cell>
    <cell address="C259" />
  </row>
  <row row="260">
    <cell address="A260">NAR_1_10_HIGH_FIVE_HAND_IN_JAR</cell>
    <cell address="B260">You’ve left them hanging long enough. Far TOO long. In fact, as you stare at the gross, desiccated hand in the jar, you begin to suspect that the time for you to break open this jar and slap an anonymous dead hand against your own alive hand has, tragically, passed.//You are actually pretty much certain of it.</cell>
    <cell address="C260" />
  </row>
  <row row="261">
    <cell address="A261">NAR_1_10_ITM_POGS_HAND_IN_JAR</cell>
    <cell address="B261">You’ve got more respect for the dead than that, even if “the dead” is just a gross hand in a jar that gives you the MAX JEEBLIES.</cell>
    <cell address="C261" />
  </row>
  <row row="262">
    <cell address="A262">NAR_1_10_LOOK_INVOICE</cell>
    <cell address="B262">The handwriting is barely legible, and there's no return address, leaving you exactly where you were without it. With no idea who shipped this crate to your house, why, what huge thing it contained, what the huge thing does, and why you should care.</cell>
    <cell address="C262" />
  </row>
  <row row="263">
    <cell address="A263">NAR_1_10_TAKE_INVOICE</cell>
    <cell address="B263">No, this really isn’t that kind of mystery (the boring kind where you have to frequently refer to your rigorously-maintained collection of shipping invoices in order to make any progress. you HATE those).</cell>
    <cell address="C263" />
  </row>
  <row row="264">
    <cell address="A264">NAR_1_10_LOOK_LAMP</cell>
    <cell address="B264">Quite possibly the tackiest thing you've ever seen. It definitely belongs locked up in an attic, with the key all but thrown away. And maybe if you're being honest, by attic, you mean jail.</cell>
    <cell address="C264" />
  </row>
  <row row="265">
    <cell address="A265">NAR_1_10_LOOK_MASKS</cell>
    <cell address="B265">Ah, the skeleton-man. The devil. The fortune teller, and the horse with his head turned sideways. You and your brother spent many an October 31st fooling your neighbors out of their candies with these cunning disguises.</cell>
    <cell address="C265" />
  </row>
  <row row="266">
    <cell address="A266">NAR_1_10_LOOK_PORTAL</cell>
    <cell address="B266">Could this be the thing Jude was jabbering about? It's always been so hard to take him seriously. But now... you're not sure what to believe.</cell>
    <cell address="C266" />
  </row>
  <row row="267">
    <cell address="A267">NAR_1_10_LOOK_PORTAL_KEYHOLE</cell>
    <cell address="B267">Looks like an AWFULLY good place to stick a key. Not just any key either. Gotta be a really KOOKY lookin' key that makes this outlandish contraption tick.</cell>
    <cell address="C267" />
  </row>
  <row row="268">
    <cell address="A268">NAR_1_10_LOOK_SARCOPHAGUS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B268">PA's passion for PREVIOUSLY ALIVE ARTIFACTURE has always given you the willies. What is it with him? Not only does he not respect the lives of the critters he shoots, but he seems infatuated with the notion of death itself. What a twisted fellow. //Then again, you could be blowing it all out of proportion. Maybe he's not awful, just complicated. Who knows how unfairly your young mind is judging his behavior. You suppose you'll sort it all out when you're a little older. Possibly with the aid of a therapist.</cell>
    <cell address="C268" />
  </row>
  <row row="269">
    <cell address="A269">NAR_1_10_LOOK_SARCOPHAGUS</cell>
    <cell address="B269">PA's passion for PREVIOUSLY ALIVE ARTIFACTURE has always given you the willies.</cell>
    <cell address="C269" />
  </row>
  <row row="270">
    <cell address="A270">NAR_1_10_LOOK_STRAW</cell>
    <cell address="B270">So much PACKING STRAW. Whatever was packed in this crate must have been delicate. Either that, or it was an elephant, and this was its food supply.</cell>
    <cell address="C270" />
  </row>
  <row row="271">
    <cell address="A271">NAR_1_10_NAP_IN_STRAW</cell>
    <cell address="B271">When the monsters bust down the attic door, you’d rather not be all tuckered out and ready for the chomping like some kind of KID CUISINE, featuring an actual KID. You hate KID CUISINE. Wait, what were you thinking about? Oh yeah, straw-naps. No.</cell>
    <cell address="C271" />
  </row>
  <row row="272">
    <cell address="A272">NAR_1_10_LOOK_STUFF</cell>
    <cell address="B272">You haven't been up here in a while. Pa sure does keep a lot of weird crap up here. Weirder than the other crap, that is. Or... maybe not. Maybe all his stupid crap is basically the same.</cell>
    <cell address="C272" />
  </row>
  <row row="273">
    <cell address="A273">NAR_1_10_POGS_STUFF</cell>
    <cell address="B273">You have feeling that a dusty pile of junk in the attic is the eventual fate for every POG in existence. JUDE, on the other hand, says they’ll eventually become the currency of the post-apocalyptic wasteland. Could go either way, you guess.</cell>
    <cell address="C273" />
  </row>
  <row row="274">
    <cell address="A274">NAR_1_10_LOOK_SWITCH</cell>
    <cell address="B274">The switch is connected to a light bulb so old, it probably burned out shortly after Edison personally crafted it.</cell>
    <cell address="C274" />
  </row>
  <row row="275">
    <cell address="A275">NAR_1_10_REMOVE_DRAPE</cell>
    <cell address="B275">You remove the drape to reveal an IMPRESSIVE AND PUZZLING PIECE OF MACHINERY. //You're not going to lie. The first words that come to your mind are secretive and diabolical, when describing this gizmo. //Secretive by definition, insofar as it was literally being concealed moments ago. //And diabolical? //You're not sure why you'd describe it that way. Just a funny feeling...</cell>
    <cell address="C275" />
  </row>
  <row row="276">
    <cell address="A276">NAR_1_10_TAKE_GUN</cell>
    <cell address="B276">There is no chance you are going to pick up this gun, and you CERTAINLY aren't going to ''lock and load'' any time soon. It just isn't going to happen, sorry.</cell>
    <cell address="C276" />
  </row>
  <row row="277">
    <cell address="A277">NAR_1_10_TAKE_MASKS</cell>
    <cell address="B277">Why would you want to cover up your cute face with such a creepy mask? No thank you sir!</cell>
    <cell address="C277" />
  </row>
  <row row="278">
    <cell address="A278">NAR_1_10_PERFECT_DISGUISE_MASKS</cell>
    <cell address="B278">Disguising your identity (and impairing your vision) wouldn’t really help matters much. You’re pretty sure the monsters are going to eat anybody they meet. It’s not like they’re interested in eating you, specifically. You really, really hope you’re right about that.</cell>
    <cell address="C278" />
  </row>
  <row row="279">
    <cell address="A279">NAR_1_10_THROW_SWITCH</cell>
    <cell address="B279">Throwing the switch does nothing. Or it turned on a porch light somewhere else. You can never tell.</cell>
    <cell address="C279" />
  </row>
  <row row="280">
    <cell address="A280">NAR_1_10_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_LAMP</cell>
    <cell address="B280">If this were one of those old-timey lamps from pioneer times, and if the little turny things on the sides of those lamps looked like this key, and if this lamp were missing its key, then you STILL wouldn’t have accomplished anything by doing this.</cell>
    <cell address="C280" />
  </row>
  <row row="281">
    <cell address="A281">NAR_1_10_ITM_SPICE_MIX_SARCOPHAGUS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B281">You don’t think this guy needs any help with preservation.//That’s what you were going for, right? Like how salt preserves meat, and he’s a mummy, or whatever. It was a little bit of situational humor on your part. Joey Claire, keepin’ it light. OK.//OK.//You feel weird that you’re even thinking this to yourself, but you weren’t going to eat this mummy. Like, what, you wanted to eat the mummy, but you were worried it would be bland, so you thought you’d spice him up a little first. No. Of course not.//AUGH WHY ARE YOU STILL SO HUNGRY? AND WHY DON’T YOU HAVE A BETTER BABYSITTER WHO BUYS FOOD REGULARLY AND DOES A BETTER JOB INSTILLING THE BIZARRE HUMAN ANATHEMA OF MUMMY-CANNIBALISM?</cell>
    <cell address="C281" />
  </row>
  <row row="282">
    <cell address="A282">NAR_1_10_ITM_SPICE_MIX_SARCOPHAGUS_AFTERFIRST</cell>
    <cell address="B282">AND WHY ARE YOU STILL TRYING TO EAT HIM?</cell>
    <cell address="C282" />
  </row>
  <row row="283">
    <cell address="A283">NAR_1_10_ITM_PET_TREATS_STRAW</cell>
    <cell address="B283">Yeah, let’s see, pet treats for food, CHECK. Old straw for bedding, CHECK. You’ve got everything you need to begin your awful new life as the person who lives alone in this attic forever! You’ve even got masks and stuff for when you get REALLY crazy after a couple of years pass.</cell>
    <cell address="C283" />
  </row>
  <row row="284">
    <cell address="A284">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_STRAW</cell>
    <cell address="B284">The pigeon nestles down into the warm straw, the picture of contentment and safety. UH, beg pardon, Snuggles O’Snoozington, you were under the impression this was a TEAM adventure? Not the late shift at the Nap Factory? You scoop the pigeon back up.</cell>
    <cell address="C284" />
  </row>
  <row row="285">
    <cell address="A285">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_CRANE</cell>
    <cell address="B285">The pigeon starts doing a weird little dance around the crane. Heh, does it think the crane is another bird? It’s not that kind of crane, pigeon! Haha!//Wait. That doesn’t make any sense. It’d have to be WAY smarter than it is to be that dumb. This is quite the mystery you’ve stumbl-- oh no, wait. OK. Never mind. It’s pooping on the crane.</cell>
    <cell address="C285" />
  </row>
  <row row="286">
    <cell address="A286">NAR_1_10_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_CAGES</cell>
    <cell address="B286">If all this thing unlocked was some empty cages in the attic... well, not that your life has any obligation to be entertaining or to deliver some kind of payoff on the narrative expectations it raises, but that would be REALLY anticlimactic.</cell>
    <cell address="C286" />
  </row>
  <row row="287">
    <cell address="A287">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_SWITCH</cell>
    <cell address="B287">The pigeon perches on the switch, which doesn’t move. Pigeons, like most birds, are pretty light! You know this because you’re an aspiring veterinarian. You didn’t forget, and expect the pigeon to be able to move that switch or anything. No sir.</cell>
    <cell address="C287" />
  </row>
  <row row="288">
    <cell address="A288">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_DRAPE</cell>
    <cell address="B288">The pigeon slips under the drape. After a moment, you hear the terrifying sound of... pigeon snores. Yeah, he thinks it’s nighttime now. Because of the drape. You reach under and retrieve him.</cell>
    <cell address="C288" />
  </row>
  <row row="289">
    <cell address="A289">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_PORTAL</cell>
    <cell address="B289">You hold the pigeon in front of the impressive piece of machinery. He is plainly mystified. You feel pretty superior to your tiny companion before you remember that, oh yeah, you have no idea what this thing is either.</cell>
    <cell address="C289" />
  </row>
  <row row="290">
    <cell address="A290">NAR_1_10_ITM_PIGEON_PORTAL_KEYHOLE</cell>
    <cell address="B290">You place the bird next to the keyhole. It gets that look in its eye... the look a watchmaker gets when presented with a broken watch. The look a surgeon gets when opening up a broken person. The practiced evaluation of a familiar problem.//Without hesitation, and with incomparable confidence, the pigeon jams its beak right in the keyhole and gets stuck. You wiggle it free. Lousy goddamn stupid pigeon.</cell>
    <cell address="C290" />
  </row>
  <row row="291">
    <cell address="A291">NAR_1_10_ITM_POGS_PORTAL_KEYHOLE</cell>
    <cell address="B291">Oh yeah! Definitely! Your brother’s POGS, the crappy cardboard discs with cartoon characters on them, the things that didn’t exist until a few years ago, are the secret answer to activating this enormous clockwork snake machine that’s been in your attic forever. Puzzle solved. Adventure over.</cell>
    <cell address="C291" />
  </row>
  <row row="292">
    <cell address="A292">NAR_1_10_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B292">...No. This door is locked or unlocked by the ATTIC KEY. This... this is the GREEN KEY. You went through a whole ghoulish taxidermy lightshow puzzle to get the key to this door. Joey. Keep it together. Come on.</cell>
    <cell address="C292" />
  </row>
  <row row="293">
    <cell address="A293">NAR_1_10_LOOK_HORSEY</cell>
    <cell address="B293">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C293" />
  </row>
  <row row="294">
    <cell address="A294">NAR_1_10_RIDE_HORSEY</cell>
    <cell address="B294">If only this were a REAL horse, and if only you knew HOW to ride horses, and if only the monsters wouldn’t probably EAT the horse, THEN... your troubles would be over.</cell>
    <cell address="C294" />
  </row>
  <row row="295">
    <cell address="A295">NAR_1_4_DEACTIVATE_MONSTER_STAIRS_1</cell>
    <cell address="B295">Yeah! How quickly your fellowship breaks, monsters! You and Jude have turned them against each other with your SIS &amp; BRO LIGHTSHOW maneuver! Works every time, apparently!</cell>
    <cell address="C295" />
  </row>
  <row row="296">
    <cell address="A296">NAR_1_4_DEACTIVATE_MONSTER_STAIRS_2</cell>
    <cell address="B296">More monster discord sown by you and Jude’s incredible light-based teamwork! It can’t fail! Oh wait, you’re out of monsters for this last one to be discordant with! Uh oh!</cell>
    <cell address="C296" />
  </row>
  <row row="297">
    <cell address="A297">NAR_1_5_EXIT_FRONT_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B297">Leaving the protection of your home seems like a particularly bad idea at the moment. Could be creatures and weirdos ahoy out there.</cell>
    <cell address="C297" />
  </row>
  <row row="298">
    <cell address="A298">NAR_1_5_EXIT_KITCHEN_DOOR_MONSTERS_NO_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B298">Um, no, let's not do that! The other side is literally full of monsters!</cell>
    <cell address="C298" />
  </row>
  <row row="299">
    <cell address="A299">NAR_1_5_EXIT_KITCHEN_DOOR_MONSTERS_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B299">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C299" />
  </row>
  <row row="300">
    <cell address="A300">NAR_1_5_LOOK_BEANBAG_CHAIR</cell>
    <cell address="B300">A beanbag chair. Super comfy and thankfully not filled with real beans.</cell>
    <cell address="C300" />
  </row>
  <row row="301">
    <cell address="A301">NAR_1_5_ITM_SPICE_MIX_BEANBAG_CHAIR</cell>
    <cell address="B301">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C301" />
  </row>
  <row row="302">
    <cell address="A302">NAR_1_5_LOOK_BOOKSHELF</cell>
    <cell address="B302">This bookshelf contains several of Pa's books, including "PISTOLS TO PELTS: HOW TO TURN ANIMALS INTO WEIRD RUGS AND STUFF," "TEACH YOURSELF TAXIDERMY, I GUESS," and "SAFARI! STORIES OF BOLD MEN AND THE ANIMALS THEY KILLED FROM A DISTANCE EVEN THOUGH THEY WEREN'T HUNGRY AND DID NOT INTEND TO EAT THEM."</cell>
    <cell address="C302" />
  </row>
  <row row="303">
    <cell address="A303">NAR_1_5_CHECK_FOR_SECRET_PASSAGE_BOOKSHELF</cell>
    <cell address="B303">Look, this room creeps you out enough as it is. If there’s some EXTRA-creepy secret passage that’s been hidden here your whole life, it can STAY hidden as far as you’re concerned.</cell>
    <cell address="C303" />
  </row>
  <row row="304">
    <cell address="A304">NAR_1_5_LOOK_FRONT_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B304">You can't tell if the noises you hear are from the monsters or the wind. It's either some particularly wooshy monsters, or some really groany wind.</cell>
    <cell address="C304" />
  </row>
  <row row="305">
    <cell address="A305">NAR_1_5_LOOK_KITCHEN_DOOR_MONSTERS_NO_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B305">There's a lot of noise coming from these doors, a noise which will be characterized as "monsters scrambling on the other side to get in." It's that noise!</cell>
    <cell address="C305" />
  </row>
  <row row="306">
    <cell address="A306">NAR_1_5_LOOK_KITCHEN_DOOR_MONSTERS_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B306">Oh man, the thought of going back into the kitchen is pretty nerve-wracking, but you've just got to get that pigeon!</cell>
    <cell address="C306" />
  </row>
  <row row="307">
    <cell address="A307">NAR_1_5_LOOK_KITCHEN_DOOR_NO_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B307">The KITCHEN is this way.</cell>
    <cell address="C307" />
  </row>
  <row row="308">
    <cell address="A308">NAR_1_5_LOOK_KITCHEN_DOOR_NO_MONSTERS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B308">Through here lies the Parlor of Snacks, or in some circles, what's known as the KITCHEN. The snacks are beckoning you. Look, you know there's a monster crisis brewing and all, but that is no reason for an intrepid girl to eschew snacks altogether.</cell>
    <cell address="C308" />
  </row>
  <row row="309">
    <cell address="A309">NAR_1_5_LOOK_PIANO</cell>
    <cell address="B309">A piano can be used to turn the slight motion of one's fingers into music. Those ivories... how they BEG to be tickled... //BUT YOU MUSTN'T! //You really only know how to play "Chopsticks" anyway, and that gets old real fast.</cell>
    <cell address="C309" />
  </row>
  <row row="310">
    <cell address="A310">NAR_1_5_LOOK_STAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B310">Those sure are some stairs. All like, jutting at right angles, proceeding upward diagonally. Ready for feet to be on them. Man.</cell>
    <cell address="C310" />
  </row>
  <row row="311">
    <cell address="A311">NAR_1_5_LOOK_STUFFED_BEAR_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B311">It's a bear that your Pa shot and killed and stuffed and turned into a trophy. Now all his friends who come in this room will think "Oh, this guy shot a bear. Okay."</cell>
    <cell address="C311" />
  </row>
  <row row="312">
    <cell address="A312">NAR_1_5_OUTRUN_STUFFED_BEAR_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B312">You don’t need to outrun the bear. You only need to outrun YOU. Wait, that joke doesn’t really work when you’re narrating to yourself. Or...wait. What are you talking about. You drop this line of thought forever.//Hey, a bear.</cell>
    <cell address="C312" />
  </row>
  <row row="313">
    <cell address="A313">NAR_1_5_LOOK_TAXIDERMY_ANIMAL</cell>
    <cell address="B313">One of Pa's recent conquests. You hate looking at it, the poor thing. You hope that heaven exists and that this creature's soul is there right now, and you just literally started sobbing.</cell>
    <cell address="C313" />
  </row>
  <row row="314">
    <cell address="A314">NAR_1_5_LOOK_TROPHY_ROOM_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B314">In your opinion, the TROPHY ROOM is the worst room in the entire house. Oh, the humanity. Or what little was demonstrated when those innocent animals were slaughtered. :(</cell>
    <cell address="C314" />
  </row>
  <row row="315">
    <cell address="A315">NAR_1_5_LOOK_TV</cell>
    <cell address="B315">There's the big screen. Got the cable hookup and everything. It's your home altar, and your method of worship is listless vegetation. The gods reward you with copious amusements, and brief visitations from demigods such as Clarissa, Ren &amp; Stimpy, Alex Mack, and that green kid from ReBoot. OK, maybe some of those demigods are a bit lame, and/or gross. But you love them all anyway.</cell>
    <cell address="C315" />
  </row>
  <row row="316">
    <cell address="A316">NAR_1_5_ITM_POGS_TV</cell>
    <cell address="B316">No, these things are basically the OPPOSITE of TV and you don’t want to cause an explosion.</cell>
    <cell address="C316" />
  </row>
  <row row="317">
    <cell address="A317">NAR_1_5_LOOK_UNIVERSAL_REMOTE</cell>
    <cell address="B317">Pa's major totem of power. The impressively clunky item controls the TV, the garage door, toaster, thermostat and pretty much everything else of a gizmological nature. You literally cannot pick it up without using both hands.</cell>
    <cell address="C317" />
  </row>
  <row row="318">
    <cell address="A318">NAR_1_5_TAKE_UNIVERSAL_REMOTE</cell>
    <cell address="B318">A UNIVERSAL REMOTE definitely sounds like something that would be useful on your adventure! Except the power’s out, “UNIVERSAL” is probably disappointingly misleading, and who said you were on an adventure anyway? So far, you haven’t even left your house!</cell>
    <cell address="C318" />
  </row>
  <row row="319">
    <cell address="A319">NAR_1_5_PLAY_PIANO</cell>
    <cell address="B319">You don't have any training, AND you don't want to alert anyone that you're here, so you decide to put off your concerto. Oh, also, that piano's jam-packed with a lot of silly nonsense, so that settles THAT.</cell>
    <cell address="C319" />
  </row>
  <row row="320">
    <cell address="A320">NAR_1_5_PLAY_HAUNTING_MELODY_PIANO</cell>
    <cell address="B320">Oh, that would be just the thing, wouldn’t it? Some kind of eerie, lonely sonata to really set the tone for the adventure ahead. Something in a minor key, maybe? It’s a shame that would probably provoke a bunch of monsters to eat you.//Also, you can’t really play the piano.</cell>
    <cell address="C320" />
  </row>
  <row row="321">
    <cell address="A321">NAR_1_5_TAKE_BATTERIES_UNIVERSAL_REMOTE</cell>
    <cell address="B321">You add the E-CELL BATTERIES to your SYLLADEX.</cell>
    <cell address="C321" />
  </row>
  <row row="322">
    <cell address="A322">NAR_1_5_USE_TV</cell>
    <cell address="B322">What, use the TV without employing the ultimate in system-unification technology, the UNIVERSAL REMOTE? Uh, ok, go right ahead and do that. Use the TV directly with your hands, like the cavemen used to. //You decide not to, because you don't want to be like cavemen used to be. Good choice.</cell>
    <cell address="C322" />
  </row>
  <row row="323">
    <cell address="A323">NAR_1_5_USE_UNIVERSAL_REMOTE</cell>
    <cell address="B323">Why would you want to turn on the TV and alert monsters to your whereabouts? Sometimes you don't even THINK.</cell>
    <cell address="C323" />
  </row>
  <row row="324">
    <cell address="A324">NAR_1_5_ITM_PET_TREATS_STUFFED_BEAR_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B324">This bear isn't hungry. Come to think of it, it's not most things anymore.</cell>
    <cell address="C324" />
  </row>
  <row row="325">
    <cell address="A325">NAR_1_5_ITM_SPICE_MIX_STUFFED_BEAR_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B325">Your head is already swimming just standing downwind from the rank miasma that surrounds this awful thing. You really don’t think its flavor needs any strengthening.</cell>
    <cell address="C325" />
  </row>
  <row row="326">
    <cell address="A326">NAR_1_5_ITM_SPICE_MIX_TV</cell>
    <cell address="B326">There should probably be some wisecrack here about how combining the SPICE MIX with the TV gets you THE SPICE CHANNEL, but you barely even know what that is, so there isn't.</cell>
    <cell address="C326" />
  </row>
  <row row="327">
    <cell address="A327">NAR_1_5_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_PIANO</cell>
    <cell address="B327">What, you think it's gonna click into place and suddenly be a "Key of C" or something?</cell>
    <cell address="C327" />
  </row>
  <row row="328">
    <cell address="A328">NAR_1_5_ITM_PET_TREATS_TAXIDERMY_ANIMAL</cell>
    <cell address="B328">That animal is long past appreciating any treats, unfortunately.</cell>
    <cell address="C328" />
  </row>
  <row row="329">
    <cell address="A329">NAR_1_6_HIDE_SUIT_OF_ARMOR</cell>
    <cell address="B329">Brilliant! Use ARMOR for a SHIELD! You're safe for now. Sure, you're accomplishing a heck ton of nothing at a breakneck pace, but at least you're safe for now.</cell>
    <cell address="C329" />
  </row>
  <row row="330">
    <cell address="A330">NAR_1_6_LOOK_ANTLERS</cell>
    <cell address="B330">There is something odd about the ANTLERS. You can't quite put a finger on it. Or can you? Maybe... in a literal sense?</cell>
    <cell address="C330" />
  </row>
  <row row="331">
    <cell address="A331">NAR_1_6_LOOK_ANTLERS_MOVED</cell>
    <cell address="B331">The puzzle is solved. You gotta learn to leave well enough alone, you think. And also to leave gross enough alone.</cell>
    <cell address="C331" />
  </row>
  <row row="332">
    <cell address="A332">NAR_1_6_LOOK_ATTIC_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B332">You did it! The ATTIC KEY has been found.</cell>
    <cell address="C332" />
  </row>
  <row row="333">
    <cell address="A333">NAR_1_6_LOOK_CAT_HEAD_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B333">The cat's hollow eyes welcome you to your nightmares. Its vacant sockets blindly stare you down.</cell>
    <cell address="C333" />
  </row>
  <row row="334">
    <cell address="A334">NAR_1_6_LOOK_DARKNESS</cell>
    <cell address="B334">It's too dark to see much of anything in here.</cell>
    <cell address="C334" />
  </row>
  <row row="335">
    <cell address="A335">NAR_1_6_LOOK_DEER_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B335">Yep, everything in this room is as horrible as you remember.</cell>
    <cell address="C335" />
  </row>
  <row row="336">
    <cell address="A336">NAR_1_6_LOOK_DEER_TROPHY_MOVED</cell>
    <cell address="B336">This deer ended up helping you out, even if it was only due to your Pa’s grotesque taxidermy tinkering. You wish the deer was alive, and strong, and your friend. You truly wish you had a deerfriend.</cell>
    <cell address="C336" />
  </row>
  <row row="337">
    <cell address="A337">NAR_1_6_LOOK_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B337">The LIVING ROOM seems clear of monsters for now.</cell>
    <cell address="C337" />
  </row>
  <row row="338">
    <cell address="A338">NAR_1_6_LOOK_EYE_SOCKETS_BEAMS</cell>
    <cell address="B338">The deer's laserbeam-vision locks eye contact with the ferocious cat head. This is really intense! Or it would be, if the cat actually had eyes. Instead it's just another weird and creepy thing taking place in your house.</cell>
    <cell address="C338" />
  </row>
  <row row="339">
    <cell address="A339">NAR_1_6_LOOK_EYE_SOCKETS_NO_BEAMS</cell>
    <cell address="B339">Yep, that's one eyeless cat head. Lil' creepy.</cell>
    <cell address="C339" />
  </row>
  <row row="340">
    <cell address="A340">NAR_1_6_LOOK_FIREPLACE</cell>
    <cell address="B340">This place would be a pretty good place for a fire. You call it a "fire place." Yeah, just neat a little phrase you coined on the fly. That's how you roll.</cell>
    <cell address="C340" />
  </row>
  <row row="341">
    <cell address="A341">NAR_1_6_LOOK_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell address="B341">This weird globe has an "X" on it and doesn't correspond to any planet you've ever seen. Again: weird!</cell>
    <cell address="C341" />
  </row>
  <row row="342">
    <cell address="A342">NAR_1_6_LOOK_GLOBE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B342">Pa's love of globes knows no bounds. This one is either really old or really bad. You don't recognize any of the continents. Is it Earth from a different geological era, or just some phony made-up fantasy planet? //You'd have a much better idea of what you're looking at if you could read these scribbly labels. The only intelligible bit of scrawl you see is a big old "X" mark. Could it indicate... treasure?</cell>
    <cell address="C342" />
  </row>
  <row row="343">
    <cell address="A343">NAR_1_6_LOOK_GRANDFATHER_CLOCK</cell>
    <cell address="B343">It's a grandfather clock. Is there a grandmother clock to go with it? Wait, there is no such thing as a grandmother clock... YET. You just discovered another reason why you MUST survive this.</cell>
    <cell address="C343" />
  </row>
  <row row="344">
    <cell address="A344">NAR_1_6_SMASH_GRANDFATHER_CLOCK</cell>
    <cell address="B344">You don’t think you’ll be smashing this ridiculous antique JUST yet. Though it is taking a HEROIC effort to resist.//Wait, what? What the heck was that about. Ridiculous folly. Inexcusable. Moving right along.</cell>
    <cell address="C344" />
  </row>
  <row row="345">
    <cell address="A345">NAR_1_6_LOOK_KATANA</cell>
    <cell address="B345">This is a katana! It's a traditional samurai sword. SPOILER ALERT: you have no idea what to do with one.</cell>
    <cell address="C345" />
  </row>
  <row row="346">
    <cell address="A346">NAR_1_6_LOOK_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B346">This guy isn't winning any beauty pageants. Though you suspect it would KILL IT in the talent portion of the contest. (Its talent is being ugly.)</cell>
    <cell address="C346" />
  </row>
  <row row="347">
    <cell address="A347">NAR_1_6_LOOK_SUIT_OF_ARMOR</cell>
    <cell address="B347">The wearer of this suit must have been a huge fellow. Where did he even find this thing? A big-and-tall, uh... renaissance fair?</cell>
    <cell address="C347" />
  </row>
  <row row="348">
    <cell address="A348">NAR_1_6_LOOK_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B348">This is a specially-built semitransparent collection of matter which allows light to be transmitted through it, while at the same time acting as a barrier against wind and precipitation. //You call it... //"A window."</cell>
    <cell address="C348" />
  </row>
  <row row="349">
    <cell address="A349">NAR_1_6_PULL_ANTLERS_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B349">The LACK OF ACTION is supremely disappointing. Then again, it's awfully dark in here. Maybe if the power was on you'd observe something different.</cell>
    <cell address="C349" />
  </row>
  <row row="350">
    <cell address="A350">NAR_1_6_PULL_ANTLERS_POWER_BEAMS</cell>
    <cell address="B350">You think you have the hang of it now.</cell>
    <cell address="C350" />
  </row>
  <row row="351">
    <cell address="A351">NAR_1_6_PULL_ANTLERS_POWER_NO_BEAMS</cell>
    <cell address="B351">Whoa! That sure did something.</cell>
    <cell address="C351" />
  </row>
  <row row="352">
    <cell address="A352">NAR_1_6_WEAR_ANTLERS</cell>
    <cell address="B352">You really don't want to wear the ANTLERS. You frankly can't imagine a scenario that would include you choosing to wear any HORNS, DEER or OTHERWISE.</cell>
    <cell address="C352" />
  </row>
  <row row="353">
    <cell address="A353">NAR_1_6_PULL_ANTLERS_EYES_IN</cell>
    <cell address="B353">YES! You did it! You solved the creepy lasercat hornswoggle puzzle that two animals died to create... at minimum. Score one pretty gross victory for JOEY CLAIRE, THE EXTRAORDINAIRE.// Wait, there might be one more step to this. [TEXT TO BE EDITED]</cell>
    <cell address="C353" />
  </row>
  <row row="354">
    <cell address="A354">NAR_1_6_SPIN_GLOBE_FAIL</cell>
    <cell address="B354">You give the globe a spin and watch it whirl around. It makes you a bit dizzy. You probably need more practice with globes. You're a featherweight compared to Pa.</cell>
    <cell address="C354" />
  </row>
  <row row="355">
    <cell address="A355">NAR_1_6_SPIN_GLOBE_SUCCESS</cell>
    <cell address="B355">The globe offers a plaintive SQUEAK as it spins on its antique axis.</cell>
    <cell address="C355" />
  </row>
  <row row="356">
    <cell address="A356">NAR_1_6_REMINISCE_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell address="B356">You had all kinds of theories about this globe when you were little. Was it the ancient past?? The FAR-OFF FUTURE?? You never asked your Pa what the deal was, because you were afraid the answer would be depressingly mundane.</cell>
    <cell address="C356" />
  </row>
  <row row="357">
    <cell address="A357">NAR_1_6_STRIFE_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B357">You are seized by an inexplicably courageous urge to tangle with this appalling cretin. You pause for a moment and think of something cool to say.</cell>
    <cell address="C357" />
  </row>
  <row row="358">
    <cell address="A358">NAR_1_6_TAKE_ATTIC_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B358">You retrieve the ATTIC KEY from its wildly inconvenient yet semi-secure hiding place and put it in your SYLLADEX.</cell>
    <cell address="C358" />
  </row>
  <row row="359">
    <cell address="A359">NAR_1_6_TRIGGER_MONSTER_ATTACK</cell>
    <cell address="B359">It spotted you! Completely busted. What now?</cell>
    <cell address="C359" />
  </row>
  <row row="360">
    <cell address="A360">NAR_1_6_USE_DARKNESS</cell>
    <cell address="B360">You know what? Seeing's for CHUMPS. You're just going to grope around the dark room and FEEL your way to solving all your probl-</cell>
    <cell address="C360" />
  </row>
  <row row="361">
    <cell address="A361">NAR_1_6_EMBRACE_DARKNESS</cell>
    <cell address="B361">Embrace...what? The darkness? No way! You’re a gutsy hero with a heart of gold and a shoe of gum. You may pass through the darkness in your quest, but you will never let it taint your aforementioned golden heart.</cell>
    <cell address="C361" />
  </row>
  <row row="362">
    <cell address="A362">NAR_1_6_WEAR_SUIT_OF_ARMOR</cell>
    <cell address="B362">It's really not your size.</cell>
    <cell address="C362" />
  </row>
  <row row="363">
    <cell address="A363">NAR_1_6_WIELD_KATANA</cell>
    <cell address="B363">You briefly and inexpertly wield the katana before putting it down again. You have no idea how to katana! You don't even know the act of wielding one isn't called "how to katana!"</cell>
    <cell address="C363" />
  </row>
  <row row="364">
    <cell address="A364">NAR_1_6_BREAK_KATANA</cell>
    <cell address="B364">You really don’t have any interest in this thing whatsoever, so why would you break it? Contrary to what some folks think, you can be uninterested in something without hating it!</cell>
    <cell address="C364" />
  </row>
  <row row="365">
    <cell address="A365">NAR_1_6_ITM_PIGEON_KATANA</cell>
    <cell address="B365">The pigeon flies straight toward the sharp end of the katana! Aaaaand... narrowly misses it. Phew!</cell>
    <cell address="C365" />
  </row>
  <row row="366">
    <cell address="A366">NAR_1_6_ITM_SPICE_MIX_CAT_HEAD_TROPHY</cell>
    <cell address="B366">You sprinkle a pinch of the MAGIC SPICE MIX onto the mouldering cat head trophy. From the depths of your soul, you somehow summon the willpower to resist eating it.</cell>
    <cell address="C366" />
  </row>
  <row row="367">
    <cell address="A367">NAR_1_6_ITM_PIGEON_EYE_SOCKETS</cell>
    <cell address="B367">You stuff the carrier pigeon into the eye socket. It slides in perfectly, just as anyone would've expected! //But nothing happens, so you put the alive and surprisingly compressible bird back into your SYLLADEX. It's never the most obvious solutions that work, huh?</cell>
    <cell address="C367" />
  </row>
  <row row="368">
    <cell address="A368">NAR_1_6_ITM_PET_TREATS_EYE_SOCKETS</cell>
    <cell address="B368">You consider shoving the PET TREATS down in the eye sockets, so that it looks like cat is both ALIVE and BONKERS for pet treats. It would just make you sad, you think.</cell>
    <cell address="C368" />
  </row>
  <row row="369">
    <cell address="A369">NAR_1_6_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_DARKNESS</cell>
    <cell address="B369">You take this opportunity to see if your GREEN KEY can glow in the dark, but alas, it cannot.</cell>
    <cell address="C369" />
  </row>
  <row row="370">
    <cell address="A370">NAR_1_6_ITM_POGS_EYE_SOCKETS</cell>
    <cell address="B370">You put one pog on top of each of the eye sockets. Now it's got pogs for eyes! You put some pogs over your eyes too, so you match. After several minutes of standing still and silently enjoying your pog eyes, you put the pogs back in your SYLLADEX.</cell>
    <cell address="C370" />
  </row>
  <row row="371">
    <cell address="A371">NAR_1_6_ITM_POGS_FIREPLACE</cell>
    <cell address="B371">You consider burning the pogs, but then consider their obvious value and decide not to burn them. //FOR NOW.</cell>
    <cell address="C371" />
  </row>
  <row row="372">
    <cell address="A372">NAR_1_6_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_FIREPLACE</cell>
    <cell address="B372">With this FIREPLACE and your STALE CRACKER, you're a couple ingredients short of cooking up the saddest little S'MORE ever made.</cell>
    <cell address="C372" />
  </row>
  <row row="373">
    <cell address="A373">NAR_1_6_ITM_POUCH_MARBLES_EYE_SOCKETS_BEAMS_ON</cell>
    <cell address="B373">What a gross yet perfect fit!</cell>
    <cell address="C373" />
  </row>
  <row row="374">
    <cell address="A374">NAR_1_6_ITM_POUCH_MARBLES_EYE_SOCKETS_BEAMS_OFF</cell>
    <cell address="B374">That sure did something!</cell>
    <cell address="C374" />
  </row>
  <row row="375">
    <cell address="A375">NAR_1_6_AB_FLASHLIGHT_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B375">You are seized by an inexplicably courageous urge to tangle with this appalling cretin. You pause for a moment and think of something cool to say.</cell>
    <cell address="C375" />
  </row>
  <row row="376">
    <cell address="A376">NAR_1_6_ITM_POGS_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B376">The monster is not impressed with your collection of cardboard circles, what a snob.</cell>
    <cell address="C376" />
  </row>
  <row row="377">
    <cell address="A377">NAR_1_6_ITM_SPICE_MIX_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B377">The monster doesn't want your spice mix. You'll have to unload that on someone less discerning!</cell>
    <cell address="C377" />
  </row>
  <row row="378">
    <cell address="A378">NAR_1_6_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B378">Great, the monsters don't like stale crackers! JUST YOUR LUCK.</cell>
    <cell address="C378" />
  </row>
  <row row="379">
    <cell address="A379">NAR_1_6_ITM_E_BATTERY_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B379">Clearly your plan here is to feed the monster batteries, and then feed it wire, so that the wire will connect to the batteries inside its stomach and make it electrocute itself. But here’s the thing with that: it’s totally not going to work. You put the batteries away, thankful that you have such a considerate narrator to save you time and/or batteries.</cell>
    <cell address="C379" />
  </row>
  <row row="380">
    <cell address="A380">NAR_1_6_THROW_PET_TREATS_MONSTER1</cell>
    <cell address="B380">ATTENTION GAINED. Better do something clever post haste!</cell>
    <cell address="C380" />
  </row>
  <row row="381">
    <cell address="A381">NAR_1_6_THROW_PET_TREATS_MONSTER2</cell>
    <cell address="B381">The monster gobbles the treat happily! Nicely done, Joey!</cell>
    <cell address="C381" />
  </row>
  <row row="382">
    <cell address="A382">NAR_1_6_MONSTER_OUT</cell>
    <cell address="B382">Aw right! Monster-inflicted death scene AVERTED. You are unbelievably stressed out right now!</cell>
    <cell address="C382" />
  </row>
  <row row="383">
    <cell address="A383">NAR_1_6_MONSTER_WIN</cell>
    <cell address="B383">The crackle of the WALKIE-TALKIE interrupts your celebratory cavorting. What now?</cell>
    <cell address="C383" />
  </row>
  <row row="384">
    <cell address="A384">NAR_1_7_TAKE_POUCH_CARRIER_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B384">As you do not have flight capability, the PIGEON remains out of reach.</cell>
    <cell address="C384" />
  </row>
  <row row="385">
    <cell address="A385">NAR_1_7_LOOK_ARTWORK</cell>
    <cell address="B385">Did someone bust this fridge out of the Louvre?? Who left all these PRICELESS MASTERPIECES clinging to this appliance with CHEAP MAGNETS? Hmm, it's a sad state of affairs when you are forced to patronize yourself for your own crude childhood scribbles.</cell>
    <cell address="C385" />
  </row>
  <row row="386">
    <cell address="A386">NAR_1_7_LOOK_BACK_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B386">The BACK YARD used to be so much more awesome before the MONSTERS showed up.</cell>
    <cell address="C386" />
  </row>
  <row row="387">
    <cell address="A387">NAR_1_7_LOOK_BASEMENT_DOOR_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B387">That's the door to the BASEMENT. Ordinarily, you'd avoid going down there. And contrary to what your brother says, it's NOT because you dislike icky spiders. //And even if there was SOME truth to that claim, it's still better than the excuse others in this house seem to have, which is an aversion to doing laundry.</cell>
    <cell address="C387" />
  </row>
  <row row="388">
    <cell address="A388">NAR_1_7_LOOK_BASEMENT_DOOR_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B388">You can look but you sure aren't in a position to run down those stairs in abject terror.</cell>
    <cell address="C388" />
  </row>
  <row row="389">
    <cell address="A389">NAR_1_7_LOOK_CABINET_CRACKER</cell>
    <cell address="B389">Whoever built these cabinets would shake their head and sigh if they knew how little their creation was destined to hold in this moment. These cabinets bare all. They bare their bareness.</cell>
    <cell address="C389" />
  </row>
  <row row="390">
    <cell address="A390">NAR_1_7_LOOK_CABINET_NO_CRACKER</cell>
    <cell address="B390">This cupboard is now truly bringing some Old Mother Hubbard level bareness.</cell>
    <cell address="C390" />
  </row>
  <row row="391">
    <cell address="A391">NAR_1_7_LOOK_CARRIER_PIGEON_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B391">That's one of JUDE'S PIGEONS! What's that POUCH doing around its neck?</cell>
    <cell address="C391" />
  </row>
  <row row="392">
    <cell address="A392">NAR_1_7_IMPRINT_CARRIER_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B392">You stare deep into the pigeon’s eyes. It stares back into yours. The strength of your immediate kinship ignites the air between you. You walked through this world alone. But that was before this pigeon looked at you. Another life, long forgotten.</cell>
    <cell address="C392" />
  </row>
  <row row="393">
    <cell address="A393">NAR_1_7_LOOK_DINING_ROOM_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B393">It leads to the dining room and the east wing, but you hardly ever go in there. Why start now?</cell>
    <cell address="C393" />
  </row>
  <row row="394">
    <cell address="A394">NAR_1_7_LOOK_DINING_ROOM_DOOR_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B394">It leads to the dining room and the east wing. //You don't go in that part of the house much, really. The babysitter has a hard enough time keeping up with the housekeeping in the rooms you DO use.</cell>
    <cell address="C394" />
  </row>
  <row row="395">
    <cell address="A395">NAR_1_7_LOOK_DISHES</cell>
    <cell address="B395">The sink is full of dirty dishes. SOMEONE should clean these up!</cell>
    <cell address="C395" />
  </row>
  <row row="396">
    <cell address="A396">NAR_1_7_LOOK_DOG_FLAP</cell>
    <cell address="B396">Your sweet loyal DOG loves that flap. jude used to like it too, when he was younger. (He still likes it.)</cell>
    <cell address="C396" />
  </row>
  <row row="397">
    <cell address="A397">NAR_1_7_LOOK_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B397">This fax machine can be used to send "facsimiles" of whatever you stick inside it to whoever also has a fax machine! It's very high-tech.</cell>
    <cell address="C397" />
  </row>
  <row row="398">
    <cell address="A398">NAR_1_7_LOOK_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B398">The power is off, and as such your FAX MACHINE is basically useless. This is an unacceptable state of affairs.</cell>
    <cell address="C398" />
  </row>
  <row row="399">
    <cell address="A399">NAR_1_7_LOOK_KITCHEN_TABLE</cell>
    <cell address="B399">Your kitchen table has the stuff you and jude left on it still there. None of it seems particularly useful right now, though.</cell>
    <cell address="C399" />
  </row>
  <row row="400">
    <cell address="A400">NAR_1_7_LOOK_LIVING_ROOM_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B400">You appreciate that your house, like the Tanners' house, has a KITCHEN to LIVING ROOM connection. You also appreciate that UNLIKE the Tanners' house, yours is not shelter to a voracious, wisecracking puppet.</cell>
    <cell address="C400" />
  </row>
  <row row="401">
    <cell address="A401">NAR_1_7_LOOK_MOUTH_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B401">PIGEON must be a MONSTER DELICACY, what with all the effort that monster is putting into catching the frightened bird!</cell>
    <cell address="C401" />
  </row>
  <row row="402">
    <cell address="A402">NAR_1_7_LOOK_NOTES</cell>
    <cell address="B402">The notes are usually removed if the food item has been purchased and placed in the cabinet. You let out a little sigh at the number of un-removed notes. Is that... is that one from LAST YEAR? Guess no one ever bought those Teddy Grahams. :(</cell>
    <cell address="C402" />
  </row>
  <row row="403">
    <cell address="A403">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO</cell>
    <cell address="B403">That FM channel that announces all the snow days can surely shed some light on this predicament, or at least tell you if school's cancelled...?</cell>
    <cell address="C403" />
  </row>
  <row row="404">
    <cell address="A404">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT_BATTERIES_INSIDE</cell>
    <cell address="B404">If this BLASTED TRANSISTOR isn't good for information, maybe it's good for something else?</cell>
    <cell address="C404" />
  </row>
  <row row="405">
    <cell address="A405">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT_BATTERIES_TAKEN</cell>
    <cell address="B405">It's empty now.</cell>
    <cell address="C405" />
  </row>
  <row row="406">
    <cell address="A406">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_D-CELL_BATTERIES</cell>
    <cell address="B406">These batteries are way bigger than D-CELL BATTERIES. The UNIVERSAL REMOTE requires some serious juice.</cell>
    <cell address="C406" />
  </row>
  <row row="407">
    <cell address="A407">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_D-CELL_BATTERIES</cell>
    <cell address="B407">OK, good. If this radio didn't need batteries to make those noises you'd have to UPGRADE the SPOOKITUDE to BUSINESS CLASS SPOOKITUDE, and frankly you can't afford that</cell>
    <cell address="C407" />
  </row>
  <row row="408">
    <cell address="A408">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B408">It's off, and it'll stay that way.</cell>
    <cell address="C408" />
  </row>
  <row row="409">
    <cell address="A409">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B409">You usually enjoy whatever's on the radio. Like that song that's real popular right now... about a lady seeing the sun, or something? You're not so great with the names.//Regardless, anything's better than those creepy NUMBER STATIONS that Jude picks up on his weirdo shortwave device.</cell>
    <cell address="C409" />
  </row>
  <row row="410">
    <cell address="A410">NAR_1_7_LOOK_REFRIGERATOR</cell>
    <cell address="B410">You visualize all the delicious items that could be in the cool embrace of the REFRIGERATOR, but are not. //Food shopping has become sporadic of late. Turns out tipsy babysitters are FAIRLY bad at responsibilities?</cell>
    <cell address="C410" />
  </row>
  <row row="411">
    <cell address="A411">NAR_1_7_LOOK_SCHOOLWORK</cell>
    <cell address="B411">The babysitter puts your tests and homework up on the fridge, somewhat indiscriminately. Hey, she's trying. You... guess it's positive feedback for getting good grades? Except she high-fives you even if you get like a C.</cell>
    <cell address="C411" />
  </row>
  <row row="412">
    <cell address="A412">NAR_1_7_LOOK_SPICE_MIX</cell>
    <cell address="B412">A shaker full of SEASON-ALL MAGIC SPICE MIX. Your babysitter is a terrible cook, but she dumps this stuff all over everything, and it... actually tastes pretty good? Maybe it really IS magic.</cell>
    <cell address="C412" />
  </row>
  <row row="413">
    <cell address="A413">NAR_1_7_LOOK_TRASH</cell>
    <cell address="B413">You're not sure why the trash is piled next to the FRIDGE, of all places. Even most animals know better than to let their FOOD fraternize with their WASTE.</cell>
    <cell address="C413" />
  </row>
  <row row="414">
    <cell address="A414">NAR_1_7_LOOK_WINDOW_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B414">It turns out that the windows are not entirely monster-proof.</cell>
    <cell address="C414" />
  </row>
  <row row="415">
    <cell address="A415">NAR_1_7_LOOK_WINDOW_NO_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B415">You don't see any monsters, but that doesn't mean they aren't out there. //Watching. //Training. //Working up an appetite. //Well, OK, probably not training.</cell>
    <cell address="C415" />
  </row>
  <row row="416">
    <cell address="A416">NAR_1_7_OPEN_RADIO_CU_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT</cell>
    <cell address="B416">You OPEN the battery compartment.</cell>
    <cell address="C416" />
  </row>
  <row row="417">
    <cell address="A417">NAR_1_7_OPEN_RADIO_CU_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT_BATTERIES_OUT</cell>
    <cell address="B417">You already took the batteries out.</cell>
    <cell address="C417" />
  </row>
  <row row="418">
    <cell address="A418">NAR_1_7_RAID_CABINET</cell>
    <cell address="B418">All you can raid from this meager cabinet is the stalest, tiniest, worst cracker. Perhaps later you can bury this sad, dead cracker in a tiny cracker grave.</cell>
    <cell address="C418" />
  </row>
  <row row="419">
    <cell address="A419">NAR_1_7_TAKE_RADIO_CU_D-CELL_BATTERIES</cell>
    <cell address="B419">Jackpot. Can never have too many of these, and never in too many different sizes, either.</cell>
    <cell address="C419" />
  </row>
  <row row="420">
    <cell address="A420">NAR_1_7_TAKE_SPICE_MIX</cell>
    <cell address="B420">Of course, there's no such thing as magic. It's all faked with chemicals and stuff. Everyone and the horse they rode in on knows magic is fake, whereas chemicals are real. Still, those chemicals are DELICIOUS.</cell>
    <cell address="C420" />
  </row>
  <row row="421">
    <cell address="A421">NAR_1_7_TURN_ON_RADIO_CU_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B421">No thanks, you've heard all your brain can stand.</cell>
    <cell address="C421" />
  </row>
  <row row="422">
    <cell address="A422">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_TUNER</cell>
    <cell address="B422">That’s the tuner. It’s for tuning the radio. Yep. By golly.</cell>
    <cell address="C422" />
  </row>
  <row row="423">
    <cell address="A423">NAR_1_7_TWIST_RADIO_CU_TUNER</cell>
    <cell address="B423">It didn't even work when the radio was on.</cell>
    <cell address="C423" />
  </row>
  <row row="424">
    <cell address="A424">NAR_1_7_LOOK_RADIO_CU_VOLUME</cell>
    <cell address="B424">Adjust the volume. Or don’t! The world is your oyster, Joey Claire. An oyster full of volume knobs.</cell>
    <cell address="C424" />
  </row>
  <row row="425">
    <cell address="A425">NAR_1_7_TWIST_RADIO_CU_VOLUME</cell>
    <cell address="B425">You've cranked it all the way down to try to stop that awful noise. You crank it a little harder and, um, oops. You might have broken it.</cell>
    <cell address="C425" />
  </row>
  <row row="426">
    <cell address="A426">NAR_1_7_USE_BACK_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B426">You REALLY don't want to go out there right now. Tempting though it is to go rake more leaves.</cell>
    <cell address="C426" />
  </row>
  <row row="427">
    <cell address="A427">NAR_1_7_USE_BASEMENT_DOOR_NO_FLASHLIGHT_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B427">You'd rather not fall down the stairs and break your neck in the dark, thanks! With the power out, you're going to need some kind of LIGHT SOURCE before setting foot down this broken neck trap.</cell>
    <cell address="C427" />
  </row>
  <row row="428">
    <cell address="A428">NAR_1_7_USE_BASEMENT_DOOR_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B428">You are a silly person if you think you can make it past that awful monster.</cell>
    <cell address="C428" />
  </row>
  <row row="429">
    <cell address="A429">NAR_1_7_USE_DINING_ROOM_DOOR</cell>
    <cell address="B429">No need to go roaming around in that part of the house. Leave the dust bunnies in peace.</cell>
    <cell address="C429" />
  </row>
  <row row="430">
    <cell address="A430">NAR_1_7_USE_DOG_FLAP</cell>
    <cell address="B430">You are quite sure you cannot "USE DOG FLAP" right now. Hehe, just kidding, you poked your head through for a second. It was fun.</cell>
    <cell address="C430" />
  </row>
  <row row="431">
    <cell address="A431">NAR_1_7_USE_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B431">You turn the machine on, but need something to fax. And someONE, too, technically, but that's never stopped you before! You feel quite sure you are the world's PREMIER fax-hoaxer.</cell>
    <cell address="C431" />
  </row>
  <row row="432">
    <cell address="A432">NAR_1_7_USE_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B432">The power's still out. You could PRETEND to fax junk to random strangers, you guess. It would still look pretty much the same on your end... no, no. Your heart's just not in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C432" />
  </row>
  <row row="433">
    <cell address="A433">NAR_1_7_USE_RADIO_ONCE_AFTER_SFX</cell>
    <cell address="B433">Finally you just shut the thing off. The room is silent once more.</cell>
    <cell address="C433" />
  </row>
  <row row="434">
    <cell address="A434">NAR_1_7_USE_RADIO_ONCE_BEFORE_SFX</cell>
    <cell address="B434">Curious to see if you can pick anything up, you flick on the RADIO. Maybe there will be a news report about somebody's missing pet snake monster? Or somebody's missing... shadowy figures of mystery? People lose weird things all the time. Or maybe, you'll just hear a funny commercial and laugh your butt off. Heh heh, that would be a nice way to break the tension. Here's hoping!</cell>
    <cell address="C434" />
  </row>
  <row row="435">
    <cell address="A435">NAR_1_7_USE_RADIO_ONCE_WHILE_SFX</cell>
    <cell address="B435">You're bombarded with a lot of radio static and otherworldly noises that surely no human ear was ever meant to receive. The vile sounds worm and weasel their way through your ear canal, and intrude on your meager, mortal mind. //You struggle to comprehend – the tortured groans of a sinister buffoon? Or if not tortured, at least mildly uncomfortable. Perhaps... dissatisfied? Like he wants to send his dinner back at a restaurant. //Your pathetic corporeal neurons contort wildly to parse the dark and garbled tongue of pure malevolence, and even purer idiocy. //As a bit of drool slowly escapes your dumbfounded, utterly mortal mouth, the pitiable speck of matter passing for your mind very nearly, but not entirely, reaches an epiphany; all life on Earth is probably done for. //You twist the volume knob and the tuner, but it has no effect on the sound. OK, gloomy soliloquy notwithstanding, that really is pretty creepy.</cell>
    <cell address="C435" />
  </row>
  <row row="436">
    <cell address="A436">NAR_1_7_WASH_DISHES</cell>
    <cell address="B436">No way. NO WAY. You did them last time. It's Jude's turn now.</cell>
    <cell address="C436" />
  </row>
  <row row="437">
    <cell address="A437">NAR_1_7_TRIGGER_MONSTER_ATTACK</cell>
    <cell address="B437">Yes. DIRECT CONFRONTATION may be the answer. Or your doom. Or both!</cell>
    <cell address="C437" />
  </row>
  <row row="438">
    <cell address="A438">NAR_1_7_ITM_D_BATTERY_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT</cell>
    <cell address="B438">Nah, you have a better use for them.</cell>
    <cell address="C438" />
  </row>
  <row row="439">
    <cell address="A439">NAR_1_7_ITM_E_BATTERY_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT</cell>
    <cell address="B439">These batteries don't fit in there. These batteries have, in fact, never fit in there.</cell>
    <cell address="C439" />
  </row>
  <row row="440">
    <cell address="A440">NAR_1_7_ITM_POGS_BATTERY_COMPARTMENT</cell>
    <cell address="B440">You toy with the idea of putting the POGS here as a prank on your brother. He’ll be all, “hurr durr wheres my pogs joey” and you’ll be all “What pogs, Jude? by the way could you turn on the radio” and he’ll be all “hey it doesnt work oh hurf durf my pogs are in it Ive been schooled by the master”. It’s BULLETPROOF. It’s PERFECT.//In fact, it’s TOO good. You are the only one who will ever know that you even had this perfect idea. You will keep it all to yourself, like a rare pearl that is never spoiled by the opening of the oyster.</cell>
    <cell address="C440" />
  </row>
  <row row="441">
    <cell address="A441">NAR_1_7_ITM_POGS_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B441">You stick some pogs inside the fax machine, dial a random number, and wait for the machine to finish sending the fax. There! Now someone can see your cool pogs. God what a good idea you just did.</cell>
    <cell address="C441" />
  </row>
  <row row="442">
    <cell address="A442">NAR_1_7_ITM_POGS_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B442">You'd love to send a POG FAX to some rube, but it's just not possible without any power. Which is just as well, considering now is a terrible time for SURREAL PRANKS.</cell>
    <cell address="C442" />
  </row>
  <row row="443">
    <cell address="A443">NAR_1_7_ITM_POGS_DOG_FLAP</cell>
    <cell address="B443">Can't decide which of these overwrought POG designs deserves to be flung out of the DOG FLAP more. The FLAMING SKULL eating an 8-BALL, or the FLAMING 8-BALL eating a SKULL.//Either Jude finds these designs more appealing than you do, or he likes to keep some FILLER POGS on hand to bolster his POG strategies.</cell>
    <cell address="C443" />
  </row>
  <row row="444">
    <cell address="A444">NAR_1_7_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_DOG_FLAP</cell>
    <cell address="B444">You don't know why you'd poke the DOG FLAP with the GREEN KEY, honestly. Perhaps you were aiming for the door and missed. Your ACCURACY RATING plummets.</cell>
    <cell address="C444" />
  </row>
  <row row="445">
    <cell address="A445">NAR_1_7_ITM_SPICE_MIX_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B445">You're about to fax a picture of spice to some random person, but worry it might be hard to collect the spices again afterwards, so reconsider.</cell>
    <cell address="C445" />
  </row>
  <row row="446">
    <cell address="A446">NAR_1_7_ITM_SPICE_MIX_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B446">You briefly consider sprinkling some MAGIC SPICE MIX on your powerless FAX MACHINE to bring it to life, but it's not quite magical enough to do that.</cell>
    <cell address="C446" />
  </row>
  <row row="447">
    <cell address="A447">NAR_1_7_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B447">You stick your stale cracker inside the fax machine, dial a random number, and wait for the machine to finish sending the fax. There! Now someone has a weird image of a cracker, and your cracker is slightly more stale. This... this was just an awful, awful idea.</cell>
    <cell address="C447" />
  </row>
  <row row="448">
    <cell address="A448">NAR_1_7_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B448">You're about to send your STALE CRACKER through the FAX MACHINE when you remember it's not even on.//What would compel you to do such a thing, anyway? Why is it now, of all times, imperative for you to fax a cracker? Pull yourself together.</cell>
    <cell address="C448" />
  </row>
  <row row="449">
    <cell address="A449">NAR_1_7_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_FAX_MACHINE_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B449">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C449" />
  </row>
  <row row="450">
    <cell address="A450">NAR_1_7_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_FAX_MACHINE_NO_POWER</cell>
    <cell address="B450">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C450" />
  </row>
  <row row="451">
    <cell address="A451">NAR_1_7_ITM_PET_TREATS_MOUTH_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B451">You dangle a PET TREAT in its direction, but it barely spares you a glance. The beast seems to find the prospect of live prey far more interesting than some preprocessed snack.</cell>
    <cell address="C451" />
  </row>
  <row row="452">
    <cell address="A452">NAR_1_7_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_CARRIER_PIGEON_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B452">Even the pinnacle of pigeon cuisine could not entice the bird from its perch with a MONSTER about!</cell>
    <cell address="C452" />
  </row>
  <row row="453">
    <cell address="A453">NAR_1_7_ITM_STALE_CRACKER_CARRIER_PIGEON_NO_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B453">You manage to entice the scared bird close enough to grab it. You snag the PIGEON along with the POUCH WITH RED AND GREEN MARBLES. //You almost ponder the implications of adding a living creature to your SYLLADEX, but then decide not to.</cell>
    <cell address="C453" />
  </row>
  <row row="454">
    <cell address="A454">NAR_1_7_AB_TAP_MOUTH_MONTER</cell>
    <cell address="B454">And, one more jazzy little tap number oughta do it, you think. Sure enough, the monster cocks its head and goes bwuh?? Success! That thing is TOTALLY distracted.</cell>
    <cell address="C454" />
  </row>
  <row row="455">
    <cell address="A455">NAR_1_7_AB_BALLET_MOUTH_MONTER</cell>
    <cell address="B455">You strut your ballet moves so hard, somebody would think you were trying to get a date with a swan. Unfortunately, your SICK GRACE goes over like a lead balloon. The monster goes right back to badgering that bird.</cell>
    <cell address="C455" />
  </row>
  <row row="456">
    <cell address="A456">NAR_1_7_ITM_SPICE_MIX_MOUTH_MONSTER</cell>
    <cell address="B456">You can't get close enough to give it a face fulla spice!!! This is going to take some... fancy footwork.</cell>
    <cell address="C456" />
  </row>
  <row row="457">
    <cell address="A457">NAR_1_7_ITM_SPICE_MIX_MOUTH_MONSTER_SUCCESS</cell>
    <cell address="B457">Whoa, the monster seems to be allergic to the spice! It's like the old saying. You can't spell ALLERGIC without ALL, and you can't spell SEASON-ALL MAGIC SPICE MIX without ALL either. You guess what you're trying to say is, you can't spell those two things without those three commonly arranged letters. //Anyway, uh. The monster's gone.</cell>
    <cell address="C457" />
  </row>
  <row row="458">
    <cell address="A458">NAR_1_7_ITM_PET_TREATS_CARRIER_PIEGON</cell>
    <cell address="B458">The pigeon picks the treat up with its beak and, after a moment, spits it back into your hand. Evidently he doesn’t care for the taste. Either that, or this bird is literally too dumb to know what food is.</cell>
    <cell address="C458" />
  </row>
  <row row="459">
    <cell address="A459">NAR_1_7_ITM_PORTAL_KEY_CARRIER_PIEGON</cell>
    <cell address="B459">The pigeon immediately tries to eat the key. Jeez. You’re beginning to think Jude sent you his dumbest bird on purpose. Why couldn’t he have sent FROHIKE? FROHIKE is a CHAMPION. Not like this dud.</cell>
    <cell address="C459" />
  </row>
  <row row="460">
    <cell address="A460">NAR_1_8_LOOK_CIRCUIT_BREAKER</cell>
    <cell address="B460">You need to find a way to flip the BREAKER.</cell>
    <cell address="C460" />
  </row>
  <row row="461">
    <cell address="A461">NAR_1_8_LOOK_CIRCUIT_BREAKER_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B461">Is that the thing? You think that's the thing. The thing that brings back the power. You've seen your BABYSITTER use it before. She eventually restored power to the house through a slapstick fog of trial and error.</cell>
    <cell address="C461" />
  </row>
  <row row="462">
    <cell address="A462">NAR_1_8_LOOK_COOKING_IMPLEMENTS</cell>
    <cell address="B462">Your mom was a good cook. That's one bounce or two the apple took after falling from the tree. You don't like cooking, and suspect you never will, you think as you sneer at the jumble of cooking dealies. Dance, though. THE PERFORMING ARTS. That's your passion. And like mom, you'll shoot for the stars.</cell>
    <cell address="C462" />
  </row>
  <row row="463">
    <cell address="A463">NAR_1_8_LOOK_DRYER</cell>
    <cell address="B463">It's a machine that makes things inside it dryer. You call it a "dryer." Some day, when laundry science has reached its apex, they may invent the "dryest." But that modern miracle is likely decades away, if not centuries.</cell>
    <cell address="C463" />
  </row>
  <row row="464">
    <cell address="A464">NAR_1_8_LOOK_HULA_GIRLS</cell>
    <cell address="B464">A souvenir from your Pa after his trip to Hawaii. He's been exploring the Pacific a lot lately, for some reason.</cell>
    <cell address="C464" />
  </row>
  <row row="465">
    <cell address="A465">NAR_1_8_LOOK_KITCHEN_STAIRS</cell>
    <cell address="B465">The warm light from the KITCHEN beckons from above. And you'd really prefer to beckon your behind back up there as soon as possible.</cell>
    <cell address="C465" />
  </row>
  <row row="466">
    <cell address="A466">NAR_1_8_LOOK_KNIGHT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B466">Your dad brought this home as a souvenir. There's nobody inside. You checked.</cell>
    <cell address="C466" />
  </row>
  <row row="467">
    <cell address="A467">NAR_1_8_SWEAR_INTO_SERVICE_KNIGHT_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B467">This chivalrous warrior was sworn into your service LONG ago. Unfortunately, they can’t fight very well, due to their inability to walk or move or really do anything besides be an empty suit of armor. But they’re fiercely loyal in their own way, make no mistake.</cell>
    <cell address="C467" />
  </row>
  <row row="468">
    <cell address="A468">NAR_1_8_LOOK_MUG</cell>
    <cell address="B468">Better not use that mug, it might still have your babysitter's ''morning coffee'' still in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C468" />
  </row>
  <row row="469">
    <cell address="A469">NAR_1_8_LOOK_NARWHAL</cell>
    <cell address="B469">It's a taxidermied narwhal. Your dad brought it back with him from the Arctic.</cell>
    <cell address="C469" />
  </row>
  <row row="470">
    <cell address="A470">NAR_1_8_LOOK_PILE_BOXES</cell>
    <cell address="B470">This former STACK OF MUSTY OLD JUNK is now a PILE, thanks in no small part to your flippant moving attempt.</cell>
    <cell address="C470" />
  </row>
  <row row="471">
    <cell address="A471">NAR_1_8_LOOK_STACK_BOXES</cell>
    <cell address="B471">With Pa's strange affinity towards the BETTY CROCKER brand ever apparent, this MUSTY OLD JUNK mainly consists of all sorts of COOKING IMPLEMENTS, ranging from the familiar to the enigmatic.//Really now, you can tell what a WHISK is for, but some of this stuff looks downright UNETHICAL.</cell>
    <cell address="C471" />
  </row>
  <row row="472">
    <cell address="A472">NAR_1_8_LOOK_WASHER</cell>
    <cell address="B472">It's a machine designed to take your clothes and wash them. You call it a "washing machine." It serves its purpose admirably, on the rare occasion a human being is willing to cooperate.</cell>
    <cell address="C472" />
  </row>
  <row row="473">
    <cell address="A473">NAR_1_8_USE_CIRCUIT_BREAKER_BLOCKED</cell>
    <cell address="B473">You can't get to it. Those old boxes are in the way.</cell>
    <cell address="C473" />
  </row>
  <row row="474">
    <cell address="A474">NAR_1_8_USE_CIRCUIT_BREAKER_CLEARED</cell>
    <cell address="B474">You flip the switch, quaking in the knowledge that every decision you make may lead to your salvation... OR YOUR DOOM.//Just reminding you that every time you click around willy-nilly there's actually pretty high stakes here okay?//Anyway, you flip the switch.</cell>
    <cell address="C474" />
  </row>
  <row row="475">
    <cell address="A475">NAR_1_8_ITM_PET_TREATS_NARWHAL</cell>
    <cell address="B475">This narwhal didn't eat pet treats in life, and it's not about to start now.</cell>
    <cell address="C475" />
  </row>
  <row row="476">
    <cell address="A476">NAR_1_8_ITM_SPICE_MIX_DRYER</cell>
    <cell address="B476">You put CLOTHES in the dryer, not spice mix! Wow. Wow, joey.</cell>
    <cell address="C476" />
  </row>
  <row row="477">
    <cell address="A477">NAR_1_8_ITM_SPICE_MIX_WASHER</cell>
    <cell address="B477">Spice mix doesn't go in the washing machine. You – you shouldn't need to be told this.</cell>
    <cell address="C477" />
  </row>
  <row row="478">
    <cell address="A478">NAR_1_8_ITM_SPICE_MIX_HULA_GIRLS</cell>
    <cell address="B478">Don't waste your MAGIC SPICE MIX on these HULA GIRLS. Their ZESTY ISLAND FLAIR requires no supplement of flavor.</cell>
    <cell address="C478" />
  </row>
  <row row="479">
    <cell address="A479">NAR_1_8_AB_TAP_DANCE_HULA_GIRLS</cell>
    <cell address="B479">You do a quick tap routine for the hula girls. //No response.</cell>
    <cell address="C479" />
  </row>
  <row row="480">
    <cell address="A480">NAR_1_8_AB_BALLET_DANCE_HULA_GIRLS</cell>
    <cell address="B480">You do a quick ballet routine for the hula girls. //They stare at you, unmoved, and also, not alive.</cell>
    <cell address="C480" />
  </row>
  <row row="481">
    <cell address="A481">NAR_1_8_ITM_SPICE_MIX_NARWHAL</cell>
    <cell address="B481">You sprinkle some MAGIC SPICE MIX on the NARWHAL. Maybe one of the monsters will smell the spice, try to eat it, and choke on the horn!//Actually, that sounds really awful. You brush the loose SPICE MIX back into the container.</cell>
    <cell address="C481" />
  </row>
  <row row="482">
    <cell address="A482">NAR_1_9_1ST_PIGEON_SENT</cell>
    <cell address="B482">R.I.P. dear FROHIKE. The tragedy is nigh insurmountable. Still, you must press on.</cell>
    <cell address="C482" />
  </row>
  <row row="483">
    <cell address="A483">NAR_1_9_EMPTY_DRAWER_CU_POUCH</cell>
    <cell address="B483">You dump out the contents of pouch. And by ''dump out'' you mean ''carefully put each marble back in its correct compartment according to color.''</cell>
    <cell address="C483" />
  </row>
  <row row="484">
    <cell address="A484">NAR_1_9_EXIT_HATCH</cell>
    <cell address="B484">Look, if it were just YOUR keister on the line, you'd be out that hatch, down the ladder, and blasting monsters in a Tuscaloosa minute. But you've got a SISTER to save!//Or at least, you've got a SISTER to assist in some small but absolutely critical way. Better get to it!</cell>
    <cell address="C484" />
  </row>
  <row row="485">
    <cell address="A485">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CHEST</cell>
    <cell address="B485">The perfect place to store your MEGA-DANGEROUS COLLECTION OF FLARES!!</cell>
    <cell address="C485" />
  </row>
  <row row="486">
    <cell address="A486">NAR_1_9_HIDE_INSIDE_CHEST</cell>
    <cell address="B486">This is a good tactical maneuver to keep tucked up your sleeve if all hell breaks loose and the monsters scramble up your treehouse and stuff. That hasn’t happened yet, though, and your sister still needs your help. So no.</cell>
    <cell address="C486" />
  </row>
  <row row="487">
    <cell address="A487">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CULT_THEORIES</cell>
    <cell address="B487">You wish you could forget about all this heavy cult stuff, but you're in too deep now! You can never unsee the truth.</cell>
    <cell address="C487" />
  </row>
  <row row="488">
    <cell address="A488">NAR_1_9_LOOK_CULT_THEORIES_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B488">Your copious notes on some DISREPUTABLE ACTIVITIES carried out by members of what you can only describe as some sort of cult. You've been surreptitiously gathering intelligence on them for a good while. //All the cloak and dagger chicanery would fill you with heady glee, if the facts you've begun to uncover weren't so FRIGGIN' DISTURBING.</cell>
    <cell address="C488" />
  </row>
  <row row="489">
    <cell address="A489">NAR_1_9_DEVELOP_ADDITIONAL_THEORIES_CULT_THEORIES</cell>
    <cell address="B489">The sudden presence of weird monsters in your yard/house seems to demand that you seriously restructure your current THEORY MATRIX. Which is... exactly what they want you to do? Maybe? Ah, you’re already making progress.</cell>
    <cell address="C489" />
  </row>
  <row row="490">
    <cell address="A490">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_CULT_THEORIES</cell>
    <cell address="B490">No way! Information is the greatest weapon against conspiracy. Besides... these theories are ALREADY a smoking gun! Ahaha! Ahahahaha! Oh gosh, you gotta tell Joey that one. Assuming she’s still alive.</cell>
    <cell address="C490" />
  </row>
  <row row="491">
    <cell address="A491">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DIAGRAMS</cell>
    <cell address="B491">Yep, there are your theories again, as logical as ever.</cell>
    <cell address="C491" />
  </row>
  <row row="492">
    <cell address="A492">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DIAGRAMS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B492">Sometimes you think your theories make TOO much sense. Sometimes you think that, to confuse spies or the snooping press, maybe you should jumble your diagrams around a little. //To make it all look like the work of a raving lunatic, instead of a studious young man hot on the trail of nefarious forces cloaked in secrecy.</cell>
    <cell address="C492" />
  </row>
  <row row="493">
    <cell address="A493">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER</cell>
    <cell address="B493">There is a NO NONSENSE DRAWER embedded in the SERIOUS WORKBENCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C493" />
  </row>
  <row row="494">
    <cell address="A494">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_BLUE</cell>
    <cell address="B494">These blue marbles are your favorite, mostly because they look like tiny little planets. Neat!</cell>
    <cell address="C494" />
  </row>
  <row row="495">
    <cell address="A495">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_CATSEYE</cell>
    <cell address="B495">You know why these marbles are called "cat's eye" marbles? It's because they kinda look like cats' eyes! //So that's the mystery of Why These Marbles Are Called That introduced AND resolved!</cell>
    <cell address="C495" />
  </row>
  <row row="496">
    <cell address="A496">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_GREEN</cell>
    <cell address="B496">You haven't formed an opinion about these green marbles yet, but you can feel yourself leaning towards "not bad, not bad at all."</cell>
    <cell address="C496" />
  </row>
  <row row="497">
    <cell address="A497">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_JUNK</cell>
    <cell address="B497">What are you calling junk?? This stuff is all borderline treasure. No, not even borderline. It's treasure, plain and simple. //Alright, maybe skirting the edge of borderline. Fair enough?</cell>
    <cell address="C497" />
  </row>
  <row row="498">
    <cell address="A498">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_POUCH_0</cell>
    <cell address="B498">Look at that nice empty pouch! You sure could put some stuff in that pouch.</cell>
    <cell address="C498" />
  </row>
  <row row="499">
    <cell address="A499">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_POUCH_1</cell>
    <cell address="B499">You do a quick visual inspection and confirm that the pouch contains: [[marble1]]</cell>
    <cell address="C499" />
  </row>
  <row row="500">
    <cell address="A500">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_POUCH_2</cell>
    <cell address="B500">The pouch is just about full to bursting, and currently contains: [[marble1]] and [[marble2]]</cell>
    <cell address="C500" />
  </row>
  <row row="501">
    <cell address="A501">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_RED</cell>
    <cell address="B501">These red marbles are your least-favorite marbles, but they're still pretty good. Even a least-favorite color of marble is still a pretty good marble, you know? They're fine.</cell>
    <cell address="C501" />
  </row>
  <row row="502">
    <cell address="A502">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_STACK_POUCHES</cell>
    <cell address="B502">Oh man, these POUCHES are so handy. You can think of at least a MILLION uses for them. //(All one million uses involve putting some things inside them, FYI.)</cell>
    <cell address="C502" />
  </row>
  <row row="503">
    <cell address="A503">NAR_1_9_LOOK_DRAWER_CU_YELLOW</cell>
    <cell address="B503">These yellow marbles are okay. They're not your favorite, but you don't hate them. They are Pretty Okay Marbles.</cell>
    <cell address="C503" />
  </row>
  <row row="504">
    <cell address="A504">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B504">You can easily see your house from here.</cell>
    <cell address="C504" />
  </row>
  <row row="505">
    <cell address="A505">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_DOGHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B505">The PUPPY CASTLE seems fortified for the moment. You and that pup spent some time adding extra DEFENCING IMPLEMENTS this summer. They are holding up nicely.</cell>
    <cell address="C505" />
  </row>
  <row row="506">
    <cell address="A506">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_DOGHOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B506">No way. Under no circumstances. Or at least, under no circumstances that you are presently willing to consider.</cell>
    <cell address="C506" />
  </row>
  <row row="507">
    <cell address="A507">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_FOUNTAIN_STATUE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B507">That statue normally looks pretty cool, but given the circumstances right now, it's kinda spooky. //Spooky if you got spooked, that is, which, come on, OBVIOUSLY you don't.</cell>
    <cell address="C507" />
  </row>
  <row row="508">
    <cell address="A508">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_FOUNTAIN_STATUE</cell>
    <cell address="B508">CIRCUMSTANCES have made this statue SPOOKY. (To wimps. Not you.)</cell>
    <cell address="C508" />
  </row>
  <row row="509">
    <cell address="A509">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_HOUSE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B509">There she blows. Harley Manor. //Well, maybe only Half-Harley Manor, since joey disowned the name in favor of your mother's. Kind of melodramatic of her, you think. //Not that you'd ever say so. She'd bite your head off!</cell>
    <cell address="C509" />
  </row>
  <row row="510">
    <cell address="A510">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_HOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B510">There she blows. Half-Harley Manor.</cell>
    <cell address="C510" />
  </row>
  <row row="511">
    <cell address="A511">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_JOEYS_WINDOW_MONSTERS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B511">You can see JOEY'S ROOM through here. PERFECT opportunity for a pesky younger brother to do some quality snooping. //Except she only ever does boring stuff like play games, and make obscene gestures at you when she notices you peeking, which is almost always. How does she always seem to KNOW?</cell>
    <cell address="C511" />
  </row>
  <row row="512">
    <cell address="A512">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_JOEYS_WINDOW_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B512">Thankfully, this angle shields you from the hateful gaze of Joey's BUBSY poster.</cell>
    <cell address="C512" />
  </row>
  <row row="513">
    <cell address="A513">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_JOEYS_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B513">You’ve had occasion to think it over before, and you decided that firing a flare through your sister’s bedroom window would definitely be crossing the line. Try to keep it more BRATTY BRO and less TREEHOUSE LUNATIC.</cell>
    <cell address="C513" />
  </row>
  <row row="514">
    <cell address="A514">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_JOEYS_WINDOW_NO_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B514">There is some noticeable skulking going on in there but you have no idea who or what is the culprit.</cell>
    <cell address="C514" />
  </row>
  <row row="515">
    <cell address="A515">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_LANDING_WINDOW_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B515">You see joey in the thick of a gross monster fracas through the landing window. There's GOT to be something you can do.</cell>
    <cell address="C515" />
  </row>
  <row row="516">
    <cell address="A516">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_LANDING_WINDOW_NO_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B516">Through the window, you can just make out the weird snake statue your Pa stuck on the landing. //No need to clarify that it's weird actually. It's a big snake statue. Weird's a given.</cell>
    <cell address="C516" />
  </row>
  <row row="517">
    <cell address="A517">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_MONSTERS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B517">Look at this crew. Some sadistic SOB absolutely CRUSHED these lunkheads with the business end of the ugly stick. They're absolutely horrifying. //Still, you feel pretty safe up here, for now. Joey's the one who's in trouble. Time for LITTLE BRO to STEP UP.</cell>
    <cell address="C517" />
  </row>
  <row row="518">
    <cell address="A518">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_MONSTERS</cell>
    <cell address="B518">Look at this crew. Some sadistic SOB absolutely CRUSHED these lunkheads with the business end of the ugly stick. They're absolutely horrifying.</cell>
    <cell address="C518" />
  </row>
  <row row="519">
    <cell address="A519">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_HOUSE_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B519">[TEXT TO BE ADDED] Maybe you should... shed some light on the situation. //Man, that one-liner. Nailed it.</cell>
    <cell address="C519" />
  </row>
  <row row="520">
    <cell address="A520">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_HOUSE</cell>
    <cell address="B520">You only have a few. Better save them for when you really need them.</cell>
    <cell address="C520" />
  </row>
  <row row="521">
    <cell address="A521">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SOUTH_WINDOW_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B521">You can easily see your house from here. It's not that you prefer your TREEHOUSE to your HOUSE, specifically. //It's just that you prefer your TREEHOUSE to literally any conceivable enclosure.</cell>
    <cell address="C521" />
  </row>
  <row row="522">
    <cell address="A522">NAR_1_9_LOOK_FLARE_GUN</cell>
    <cell address="B522">You're probably the only kid in school that owns one of these babies. Hard to believe, really. What if those kids get stranded in the middle of the OCEAN? Then the joke's on them. The big, wet, deadly joke.</cell>
    <cell address="C522" />
  </row>
  <row row="523">
    <cell address="A523">NAR_1_9_LOOK_GEODES</cell>
    <cell address="B523">Geodes are when you smash open a rock and it's got crystals inside. TOTALLY AMAZING, right? You keep hoping you'll find one that's secretly an alien egg but so far all you've got in your collection are the kind that just have cool minerals inside. SO FAR.</cell>
    <cell address="C523" />
  </row>
  <row row="524">
    <cell address="A524">NAR_1_9_SMASH_GEODES</cell>
    <cell address="B524">You already smashed open the GEODE, revealing the crystals inside. If you smash it any more, you’ll just have a pile of loose crystals. Which... actually sounds pretty awesome. Let’s put a pin in that one for now.</cell>
    <cell address="C524" />
  </row>
  <row row="525">
    <cell address="A525">NAR_1_9_LOOK_BINOCULARS</cell>
    <cell address="B525">If these BINOCULARS were really far away, you’d have no trouble seeing them... as long as you had your trusty BINOCULARS. Wait, what? Yeah. Wow. Mind blown yet? You’re welcome.</cell>
    <cell address="C525" />
  </row>
  <row row="526">
    <cell address="A526">NAR_1_9_USE_BINOCULARS</cell>
    <cell address="B526">Those monsters are pretty sneaky and numerous. You think you’ll make the tactical decision to sacrifice ocular precision for a greater overall perception. And you think you’ll feel PRETTY PLEASED WITH YOURSELF while you do it.</cell>
    <cell address="C526" />
  </row>
  <row row="527">
    <cell address="A527">NAR_1_9_LOOK_HATCH</cell>
    <cell address="B527">This hatch allows ingress AND egress from your amazing treehouse. //That means you can get in or out of it via a cool hole in the floor. //The hole is kept covered when not in use, because of SAFETY.</cell>
    <cell address="C527" />
  </row>
  <row row="528">
    <cell address="A528">NAR_1_9_LOOK_JARS</cell>
    <cell address="B528">Look at these jars. These jars are your personal curated collection of jars, containing all sorts of useful items and/or things you thought were cool but don't really remember why anymore.</cell>
    <cell address="C528" />
  </row>
  <row row="529">
    <cell address="A529">NAR_1_9_DRINK_JARS_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B529">Only a few of these are actually liquids, and unfortunately, those are also the ones whose contents you don’t precisely, exactly, 100% remember with total certainty. You’re not saying one of them is pee. But you’re also not saying that NONE of them are pee. Best stay on the safe side and assume the worst.</cell>
    <cell address="C529" />
  </row>
  <row row="530">
    <cell address="A530">NAR_1_9_DRINK_JARS</cell>
    <cell address="B530">You’re pretty sure one of them is apple juice, though. Or at least used to be.</cell>
    <cell address="C530" />
  </row>
  <row row="531">
    <cell address="A531">NAR_1_9_LOOK_LANTERN_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B531">The LANTERN just isn't cutting it! There must be better way to draw the monsters' attention. Something brighter, maybe?</cell>
    <cell address="C531" />
  </row>
  <row row="532">
    <cell address="A532">NAR_1_9_LOOK_LANTERN_NO_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B532">A standard camping lantern. //Your uses of it are hardly standard, youthinks. More like... OUTSTANDARD. (i.e. great)</cell>
    <cell address="C532" />
  </row>
  <row row="533">
    <cell address="A533">NAR_1_9_PUT_OUT_LANTERN</cell>
    <cell address="B533">You don’t really think this situation would be improved by darkness. Unless... no. You got nothing. Except a still-lit lantern, that is. You got that.</cell>
    <cell address="C533" />
  </row>
  <row row="534">
    <cell address="A534">NAR_1_9_LOOK_PIGEON_COOP_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B534">When the heat is on from the government, and you need to send an encrypted message while staying off the grid, you entrust it to one of your trained carrier pigeons, THE LONE GUNBIRDS. //You survey the troops: there's LANGLY, BYERS, and of course FROHIKE. He's your favorite! //Dear, sweet FROHIKE. How you adore him. You cherish the wind he flaps.</cell>
    <cell address="C534" />
  </row>
  <row row="535">
    <cell address="A535">NAR_1_9_LOOK_PIGEON_COOP</cell>
    <cell address="B535">When the heat is on from the government, and you need to send an encrypted message while staying off the grid, you entrust it to one of THE LONE GUNBIRDS: LANGLY, BYERS, and bright-eyed darling FROHIKE.</cell>
    <cell address="C535" />
  </row>
  <row row="536">
    <cell address="A536">NAR_1_9_LOOK_PIGEON_COOP_1ST_SENT</cell>
    <cell address="B536">Trusty LANGLY and clever BYERS are still left.</cell>
    <cell address="C536" />
  </row>
  <row row="537">
    <cell address="A537">NAR_1_9_LOOK_PIGEON_COOP_2ND_SENT</cell>
    <cell address="B537">Brave BYERS still stands majestic and strong. Chest puffed up, head cocked, and a look in his eye that says, "Sure, I may be painfully stupid, but I'm the last chance you've got."</cell>
    <cell address="C537" />
  </row>
  <row row="538">
    <cell address="A538">NAR_1_9_LOOK_PIGEON_COOP_3RD_SENT</cell>
    <cell address="B538">It looks so empty now. Sniff.</cell>
    <cell address="C538" />
  </row>
  <row row="539">
    <cell address="A539">NAR_1_9_MOURN_FROHIKE_PIGEON_COOP</cell>
    <cell address="B539">FROHIKE! Beautiful, sweet, precious, dear, darling and ultimately fragile Frohike! You were too good for this rotten dark nightmare of a world. May the wings of chance and dream bear thee to thy rest on the white sandy shores of paradise. Frohike...</cell>
    <cell address="C539" />
  </row>
  <row row="540">
    <cell address="A540">NAR_1_9_CURSE_LANGLY_PIGEON_COOP</cell>
    <cell address="B540">LANGLY. Langly the coward. Langly the blackguard. Langly the unspeakable. A thousand deaths, a million deaths, an infinitude of deaths would not be enough. Langly worm-hearted. Langly bile-blood. LANGLY. You hate him with everything you are and ever will be. LANGLY.</cell>
    <cell address="C540" />
  </row>
  <row row="541">
    <cell address="A541">NAR_1_9_LAUD_BYERS_PIGEON_COOP</cell>
    <cell address="B541">O! for Byers! Hyperion-child, who pulls the sun! Whose wingflaps are the wind! Whose infinite beak splinters the skin of monsters and brings tyrants to their ruin! O! for Byers! A song for the Golden-bird, who carries us to paradise! The beating heart of god is BYERS! BYERS EVERLASTING!</cell>
    <cell address="C541" />
  </row>
  <row row="542">
    <cell address="A542">NAR_1_9_LOOK_RADIO</cell>
    <cell address="B542">Like most radios, this one allows you to transform the INVISIBLE ENERGY FLOWING THROUGH YOUR BODY RIGHT NOW into sound. Pretty neat!</cell>
    <cell address="C542" />
  </row>
  <row row="543">
    <cell address="A543">NAR_1_9_CHECK_FREQUENCY_RADIO</cell>
    <cell address="B543">Ah, if only you could find a nice NUMBERS STATION! You know, one of those weird stations where someone recites seemingly-random numbers at seemingly-random intervals. You are certain they’re NOT random, though. They are the the bread and butter of...CONSPIRACY.//One time Joey tricked you into thinking your walkie-talkie was picking up a numbers station. The memory is a little shameful and you think you will leave the radio tuned where it is.</cell>
    <cell address="C543" />
  </row>
  <row row="544">
    <cell address="A544">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SCHEMATICS</cell>
    <cell address="B544">THIS thing. Talk about an enigma. One day, you'll figure out what it does, and why certain shady characters want to get their hands on it so badly. You have some theories, of course. //You can't let them find it. Really, no one should be messing with this thing. CERTAINLY not children.</cell>
    <cell address="C544" />
  </row>
  <row row="545">
    <cell address="A545">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH</cell>
    <cell address="B545">You think you've cracked the old man's code this time. //You note that the shading and line work is superb. Frankly you wonder if you are even capable of anything sub-superb.</cell>
    <cell address="C545" />
  </row>
  <row row="546">
    <cell address="A546">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CU_CAT_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B546">It's a sketch you made of the weird cat's head the old man has, stuffed and mounted! Personally, you're not THAT big on hollowing them out and putting them on walls, but I guess old-timey adventurers gotta fill up the hours somehow, right? //Oddly, this cat has one red eye and one green eye. You would rate this as: EXTREMELY MYSTERIOUS.</cell>
    <cell address="C546" />
  </row>
  <row row="547">
    <cell address="A547">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CU_CAT</cell>
    <cell address="B547">Your admirable rendering of Pa's mounted cat head, complete with mysterious RED and GREEN eyes.</cell>
    <cell address="C547" />
  </row>
  <row row="548">
    <cell address="A548">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CU_DEER_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B548">You sketched the deer that Pa has stuffed. You know how sometimes you look at a majestic deer in nature and think "I wish I had the skin of that, but not its insides, stuffed, and in my house somehow?" //Turns out, some people work at making that dream come true!</cell>
    <cell address="C548" />
  </row>
  <row row="549">
    <cell address="A549">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CU_DEER</cell>
    <cell address="B549">Your depiction of one of Pa's most imposing taxidermic efforts. A complete cervid specimen.</cell>
    <cell address="C549" />
  </row>
  <row row="550">
    <cell address="A550">NAR_1_9_LOOK_SKETCH_CU_GLOBE</cell>
    <cell address="B550">You feel like you really captured the true essence of this giant conspicuous globe. It is giant and conspicuous, just like in real life!</cell>
    <cell address="C550" />
  </row>
  <row row="551">
    <cell address="A551">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B551">This is the perfect lookout post for observing the SPOOKY MANSION near your house. You've been theorizing about its involvement in this cryptic plot for some time, but have reached no solid conclusions. Maybe today you'll finally understand what secrets it keeps? Or perhaps, satisfying that curiosity will be deferred for some time.</cell>
    <cell address="C551" />
  </row>
  <row row="552">
    <cell address="A552">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B552">This is the perfect lookout post for observing the SPOOKY MANSION near your house. There's a pretty good chance you won't be getting around to investigating that place for a while, though.</cell>
    <cell address="C552" />
  </row>
  <row row="553">
    <cell address="A553">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW_CU_HOUSES</cell>
    <cell address="B553">The neighborhood of Hauntswitch would be lost without your protective gaze.</cell>
    <cell address="C553" />
  </row>
  <row row="554">
    <cell address="A554">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW_CU_MANSION</cell>
    <cell address="B554">The spooky old mansion on the hill. You always said there was something up with that place.</cell>
    <cell address="C554" />
  </row>
  <row row="555">
    <cell address="A555">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW_CU_MANSION_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B555">The mansion looms. You told your sister it was nothing but trouble, but she never listened. Just as well. You have a feeling that probing its mysteries will have to fall on your shoulders, not hers. Your only job now is to protect her. And hers, to stay safe. It's tough being the man of the house.</cell>
    <cell address="C555" />
  </row>
  <row row="556">
    <cell address="A556">NAR_1_9_LOOK_NORTH_WINDOW_CU_SHADOWS</cell>
    <cell address="B556">What was that?! Did something move out there? //Your imagination is starting to play tricks on you. You decide that your imagination is stupid and can go take a big stupid hike.</cell>
    <cell address="C556" />
  </row>
  <row row="557">
    <cell address="A557">NAR_1_9_LOOK_WORKBENCH</cell>
    <cell address="B557">No TREEHOUSE is complete without a SERIOUS WORKBENCH. Hence, this treehouse is complete.</cell>
    <cell address="C557" />
  </row>
  <row row="558">
    <cell address="A558">NAR_1_9_WORK_WORKBENCH</cell>
    <cell address="B558">Tonight’s machinations don’t require the flat, level, smooth, sanded, lacquered, perfect, perfect surface of your workbench. Unfortunately.</cell>
    <cell address="C558" />
  </row>
  <row row="559">
    <cell address="A559">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_1ST_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B559">You take another pouch from the drawer and load it with one more red and green marble.</cell>
    <cell address="C559" />
  </row>
  <row row="560">
    <cell address="A560">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_2ND_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B560">Your hands are definitely not shaking as you pluck two more marbles from their safe, cozy compartments in the drawer and drop them into the depths of the pouch's waiting, leathery maw.</cell>
    <cell address="C560" />
  </row>
  <row row="561">
    <cell address="A561">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_3RD_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B561">Ah, it seems like just yesterday you were pawing around in this drawer, burdening your tiny friends with little rucksacks full of beautiful glass. Those were your salad days, gone now, like pigeons into the sky and/or the belly of a monster.</cell>
    <cell address="C561" />
  </row>
  <row row="562">
    <cell address="A562">NAR_1_9_OPEN_DRAWER_HAS_FULL_POUCH</cell>
    <cell address="B562">Heh, you already have a pouch with a red and green marble in it! Why would you ever possibly need another? The idea is as outrageous as it is inconceivable, and you REJECT it.</cell>
    <cell address="C562" />
  </row>
  <row row="563">
    <cell address="A563">NAR_1_9_TAKE_DRAWER_CU_POUCH_NO</cell>
    <cell address="B563">You remember the TROPHY ROOM DIAGRAM and reconsider your choices.</cell>
    <cell address="C563" />
  </row>
  <row row="564">
    <cell address="A564">NAR_1_9_TAKE_DRAWER_CU_POUCH_YES</cell>
    <cell address="B564">You take the POUCH WITH RED AND GREEN MARBLES.</cell>
    <cell address="C564" />
  </row>
  <row row="565">
    <cell address="A565">NAR_1_9_TAKE_FLARE_GUN</cell>
    <cell address="B565">The chamber is empty. Weak. //You should load it with some FLARES. Just in case.</cell>
    <cell address="C565" />
  </row>
  <row row="566">
    <cell address="A566">NAR_1_9_TAKE_FLARES_CHEST</cell>
    <cell address="B566">You remove the FLARES from the METAL CHEST. They're pretty lame on their own though. //If only you had a super unique FLARE GUN to use them in. (Hint: you do!)</cell>
    <cell address="C566" />
  </row>
  <row row="567">
    <cell address="A567">NAR_1_9_TREEHOUSE_INTRO</cell>
    <cell address="B567">You are now Joey's KID BROTHER. You can go back to being Jude's BIG SISTER at any time. But then again, what's the hurry? //This guy looks pretty cool, right? Cool for a silly nerd brother, that is. One who's obsessed with a bunch of CRYPTIC AND SINISTER CONSPIRACY NONSENSE that is TOTALLY FAKE. //But then, it all seems to be getting less FAKE by the minute, doesn't it? In fact, with each OCCULT FOE and VILE BEAST that crashes into your home to upset your sister, the FAKENESS ATTRIBUTE of all that stuff shrinks just a little more. You'd claim bragging rights, but at the moment, you've got a sister to save. //Your name is JUDE HARLEY, and today is the day you always feared would come.</cell>
    <cell address="C567" />
  </row>
  <row row="568">
    <cell address="A568">NAR_1_9_TREEHOUSE_INTRO_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B568">There has got to be something you can do to help Joey! She's gonna get her block knocked off.</cell>
    <cell address="C568" />
  </row>
  <row row="569">
    <cell address="A569">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_BLUE</cell>
    <cell address="B569">You add a BLUE MARBLE to the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C569" />
  </row>
  <row row="570">
    <cell address="A570">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_CATSEYE</cell>
    <cell address="B570">You move a CAT'S EYE MARBLE to the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C570" />
  </row>
  <row row="571">
    <cell address="A571">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_GREEN</cell>
    <cell address="B571">You drop a GREEN MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C571" />
  </row>
  <row row="572">
    <cell address="A572">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_RED</cell>
    <cell address="B572">You put a RED MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C572" />
  </row>
  <row row="573">
    <cell address="A573">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_YELLOW</cell>
    <cell address="B573">You place a YELLOW MARBLE in the POUCH.</cell>
    <cell address="C573" />
  </row>
  <row row="574">
    <cell address="A574">NAR_1_9_USE_DRAWER_CU_STACK_POUCHES</cell>
    <cell address="B574">On closer inspection you discover that the POUCHES are perfect for a CARRIER PIGEON'S frame and stamina. Well, by "discover" you guess you mean "knew already", because they're your pouches, and that's literally why you own them. //You take a pouch from the stack and begin pondering what you could put in it.</cell>
    <cell address="C574" />
  </row>
  <row row="575">
    <cell address="A575">NAR_1_9_USE_LANTERN</cell>
    <cell address="B575">You're already using the LANTERN as hard as you can! You try to use it EVEN HARDER ANYWAY, but its brightness is in no way a product of your EFFORT, so trying harder is just plain RIDICULOUS!</cell>
    <cell address="C575" />
  </row>
  <row row="576">
    <cell address="A576">NAR_1_9_USE_MARBLES_FULL</cell>
    <cell address="B576">A CARRIER PIGEON couldn't possibly carry that much weight. Better stick with two marbles.</cell>
    <cell address="C576" />
  </row>
  <row row="577">
    <cell address="A577">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_SOUTH_WINDOW_NO_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B577">Not now. Better save it for an emergency... who knows when you might need it while lost at sea!</cell>
    <cell address="C577" />
  </row>
  <row row="578">
    <cell address="A578">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_NORTH_WINDOW</cell>
    <cell address="B578">Shooting a bright hot flare into the sky WOULD be fun, but maybe save it for a time when you won't feel guilty enjoying said fun.</cell>
    <cell address="C578" />
  </row>
  <row row="579">
    <cell address="A579">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_HATCH</cell>
    <cell address="B579">Oh yeah! Shoot the monsters! Too bad this isn't a real gun, you only have three flares, and the monsters outside are an UNKNOWABLE NUMBER. No.</cell>
    <cell address="C579" />
  </row>
  <row row="580">
    <cell address="A580">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_FIRE_1</cell>
    <cell address="B580">You take aim at the sky over your house. Is "aiming" really something that applies when your target is as big as the sky? Anyway, you fire the FIRST FLARE into the sky with pinpoint accuracy.</cell>
    <cell address="C580" />
  </row>
  <row row="581">
    <cell address="A581">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_FIRE_2</cell>
    <cell address="B581">Here goes flare number two. Only one left after this. //You point the FLARE GUN upwards, generally, and fire the SECOND FLARE.</cell>
    <cell address="C581" />
  </row>
  <row row="582">
    <cell address="A582">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_FIRE_3</cell>
    <cell address="B582">Here goes the last one. Fire in the hole! //You vaguely position the gun toward the opposite direction of the ground, and pull the trigger on the THIRD FLARE.</cell>
    <cell address="C582" />
  </row>
  <row row="583">
    <cell address="A583">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_FLARE_LIT_1</cell>
    <cell address="B583">Everything lights up like a Christmas tree. You did it! You could almost say... this is Jude's time to shine. It will only occur to you to say that hours later, though, long after the moment has passed.</cell>
    <cell address="C583" />
  </row>
  <row row="584">
    <cell address="A584">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_FLARE_LIT_2</cell>
    <cell address="B584">You come through AGAIN. Incredible heroism, really. You almost feel sorry for Joey. Maybe some day she will get to star in her own adventure, but for the time being, looks like she's just another lucky spectator of The Jude Harley Show, starring Jude Harley.</cell>
    <cell address="C584" />
  </row>
  <row row="585">
    <cell address="A585">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SCHEMATICS</cell>
    <cell address="B585">No. While you're PRETTY sure you've committed these to your perfect memory, there might be one or two finer points you need to reference one day.</cell>
    <cell address="C585" />
  </row>
  <row row="586">
    <cell address="A586">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SKETCH</cell>
    <cell address="B586">NO! It's a NICE DRAWING.</cell>
    <cell address="C586" />
  </row>
  <row row="587">
    <cell address="A587">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_RADIO</cell>
    <cell address="B587">Maybe... IF your righteous flames would travel backwards across the radio waves, back to their sinister source, burning them in their viper's nest! MAYBE then you'd shoot this at your own radio.</cell>
    <cell address="C587" />
  </row>
  <row row="588">
    <cell address="A588">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_PIGEON_COOP</cell>
    <cell address="B588">You... no. Things have taken a dark turn, but... you frankly feel a little sick that you felt briefly compelled to do such a thing. You take some deep breaths and shake your head. Keep it together, Jude old boy.</cell>
    <cell address="C588" />
  </row>
  <row row="589">
    <cell address="A589">NAR_1_9_ITM__FLAREGUN_LOADED_HATCH</cell>
    <cell address="B589">Oh yeah! Shoot the monsters! Too bad this isn't a real gun, you only have three flares, and the monsters outside are an UNKNOWABLE NUMBER. No.</cell>
    <cell address="C589" />
  </row>
  <row row="590">
    <cell address="A590">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_NORTH_WINDOW_CU_MANSION</cell>
    <cell address="B590">As much as you’d love to torch that snake pit and bask in the glow of victorious flames, silhouetted against the roaring inferno like a demonic conductor before his infernal orchestra... It would be inadvisable to give away your current position by engaging your enemies directly. Phooey.</cell>
    <cell address="C590" />
  </row>
  <row row="591">
    <cell address="A591">NAR_1_9_ITM_FLAREGUN_LOADED_SOUTH_WINDOW_CU_JOEYS_ROOM</cell>
    <cell address="B591">Heh, that’d be pretty funny. Just imagine the look on Joey’s face if you popped one of these badboys off at her window.//At any rate, she won’t be able to appreciate your priceless capers if she becomes monster chow. Focus!</cell>
    <cell address="C591" />
  </row>
  <row row="592">
    <cell address="A592">NAR_COM_TALK_WALKIE_TALKIE_JUDE_THIRD_PIGEON_UNSENT</cell>
    <cell address="B592">[DUMMY TEXT]</cell>
    <cell address="C592" />
  </row>
  <row row="593">
    <cell address="A593">NAR_COM_TALK_WALKIE_TALKIE_JUDE_PIGEON_LANDED</cell>
    <cell address="B593">Jude can only encourage you so much. Time to do something.</cell>
    <cell address="C593" />
  </row>
  <row row="594">
    <cell address="A594">NAR_COM_TALK_WALKIE_TALKIE_BEAT_STAIR_BATTLE</cell>
    <cell address="B594">You gonna talk to your WIDDLE BWUDDA every two steps you take, or are you gonna GET MOVING? //Sorry. He's a nice widdle bwudda. SOMETIMES.</cell>
    <cell address="C594" />
  </row>
  <row row="595">
    <cell address="A595">NAR_WP_LOOK_FLASHLIGHT_ON</cell>
    <cell address="B595">The giver of Light. The brandishment of Progress. The see-saber of Truth. You have the Pow-AUGH! Why'd you have to shine the truth beam directly into your eyes?</cell>
    <cell address="C595" />
  </row>
  <row row="596">
    <cell address="A596">NAR_WP_LOOK_FLASHLIGHT_OFF</cell>
    <cell address="B596">The giver of Light. The brandishment of Progress. The see-saber of Truth. You have the Power!</cell>
    <cell address="C596" />
  </row>
  <row row="597">
    <cell address="A597">NAR_WP_TURN_OFF_FLASHLIGHT</cell>
    <cell address="B597">You click the flashlight off.</cell>
    <cell address="C597" />
  </row>
  <row row="598">
    <cell address="A598">NAR_WP_TURN_OFF_FLASHLIGHT_CANNOT</cell>
    <cell address="B598">Uh, no. That’s staying on. Think before you act, Joey!</cell>
    <cell address="C598" />
  </row>
  <row row="599">
    <cell address="A599">NAR_WP_TURN_ON_FLASHLIGHT</cell>
    <cell address="B599">You turn on your trusty flashlight.</cell>
    <cell address="C599" />
  </row>
  <row row="600">
    <cell address="A600">NAR_WP_TURN_ON_FLASHLIGHT_UNNECESSARY</cell>
    <cell address="B600">You flick it on and off. Still works!</cell>
    <cell address="C600" />
  </row>
  <row row="601">
    <cell address="A601">NAR_REPLACE_FIRST_TALK_JUDE</cell>
    <cell address="B601">[YOU USE THE WALKIE-TALKIE TO TALK WITH JUDE.  YOU'RE SO REASSURED, YOU COULD PROBABLY EVEN GO OUTSIDE NOW!!]</cell>
    <cell address="C601" />
  </row>
  <row row="602">
    <cell address="A602">NAR_AB_TAP_DANCE_JOEY_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B602">Tap dancing is loads of fun, but it sure does make a racket! When you practice it sets the whole house a-shaking. //Or... is that just your pulse pounding? Hard to say. YOU LOVE TO DANCE!</cell>
    <cell address="C602" />
  </row>
  <row row="603">
    <cell address="A603">NAR_ITM_LOOK_DIARY_KEY_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B603">This will open your DIARY. It's the key to all your most private thoughts and fantasies, so, shhhhhhh. //Meh. There's really nothing juicy in there. You WISH you led a life full of secrets worth coveting. But then again, maybe you're about to?</cell>
    <cell address="C603" />
  </row>
  <row row="604">
    <cell address="A604">NAR_ITM_LOOK_DIARY_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B604">This will open your DIARY.</cell>
    <cell address="C604" />
  </row>
  <row row="605">
    <cell address="A605">NAR_ITM_LOOK_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B605">You really don’t know what this thing is, except that it was your Mom’s. Some kind of key-thingy?</cell>
    <cell address="C605" />
  </row>
  <row row="606">
    <cell address="A606">NAR_ITM_LOOK_C_BATTERY</cell>
    <cell address="B606">These batteries hold the POWER TO ILLUMINATE.</cell>
    <cell address="C606" />
  </row>
  <row row="607">
    <cell address="A607">NAR_ITM_LOOK_WALKIE_TALKIE_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B607">Ah. Turns out your strapping muscles were not to blame at all. It's just out of batteries. As in, completely missing them.</cell>
    <cell address="C607" />
  </row>
  <row row="608">
    <cell address="A608">NAR_ITM_LOOK_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B608">You check again, but the batteries have stuck to their position of “not being in the walkie-talkie.”</cell>
    <cell address="C608" />
  </row>
  <row row="609">
    <cell address="A609">NAR_ITM_GET_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B609">Success! The WALKIE-TALKIE works like a charm now. A charm with BATTERY POWER! //You feel pretty pleased with yourself. It would seem you just solved your first puzzle of many, on what is sure to be a sweeping adventure full of nutty problems. //Then again, putting batteries in a thing isn't technically "solving a puzzle," you suppose. It is just overcoming a minor inconvenience using mundane, widely available modern technology. //You don't care though. YOU'RE COUNTING IT!!!</cell>
    <cell address="C609" />
  </row>
  <row row="610">
    <cell address="A610">NAR_ITM_WALKIE_TALKIE_TURNED_ON</cell>
    <cell address="B610">The WALKIE-TALKIE is ready to go. Go on and give it a whirl!</cell>
    <cell address="C610" />
  </row>
  <row row="611">
    <cell address="A611">NAR_ITM_WALKIE_TALKIE_NO_RESPONSE</cell>
    <cell address="B611">Nothing but static right now.</cell>
    <cell address="C611" />
  </row>
  <row row="612">
    <cell address="A612">NAR_ITM_LOOK_PET_TREATS</cell>
    <cell address="B612">PET TREATS! Animals LOVE these! Except the most dangerous animal of all... MAN. Wow. Blew your own mind there for a second.</cell>
    <cell address="C612" />
  </row>
  <row row="613">
    <cell address="A613">NAR_ITM_COMB_PET_TREATS_JOEY</cell>
    <cell address="B613">You sniff curiously at one of the treats and give it a tentative lick. //Bluh! //OK. Great for all animals, maybe not so much for people.</cell>
    <cell address="C613" />
  </row>
  <row row="614">
    <cell address="A614">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLASHLIGHT_CONTAINER</cell>
    <cell address="B614">This sure takes you back. The old strifing days with Pa were pretty intense, back when he used to be around a little more often than next to never. It's as solidly built and good for boppin' heads as ever. But you wonder if it still works?</cell>
    <cell address="C614" />
  </row>
  <row row="615">
    <cell address="A615">NAR_ITM_TURN_ON_FLASHLIGHT_CONTAINER</cell>
    <cell address="B615">Click, click... no dice. Either its flashing days are kaput, or it just needs new batteries.</cell>
    <cell address="C615" />
  </row>
  <row row="616">
    <cell address="A616">NAR_ITM_TURN_ON_FLASHLIGHT_CONTAINER_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B616">Click, click... no dice. Either its flashing days are kaput, or it just needs new batteries. //Why's everything gotta need batteries all the time? You figure it's just the price one pays for living in such a miraculous age of sweet modern gizmos.</cell>
    <cell address="C616" />
  </row>
  <row row="617">
    <cell address="A617">NAR_ITM_OPEN_FLASHLIGHT_CONTAINER</cell>
    <cell address="B617">Wait, there were no batteries in here at all. Just a bunch of stupid pogs! Dangit, Jude. He REALLY needs a better pog storage system.</cell>
    <cell address="C617" />
  </row>
  <row row="618">
    <cell address="A618">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLASHLIGHT_EMPTY</cell>
    <cell address="B618">You're going to need some D-CELL BATTERIES if you want this flashlight to serve any purpose other than emergency pog storage container and very poorly designed paperweight.</cell>
    <cell address="C618" />
  </row>
  <row row="619">
    <cell address="A619">NAR_ITM_LOOK_POGS</cell>
    <cell address="B619">JUDE'S POGS. Some are cooler than others (Scully 4EVA) but really most of them are boring promotional junk that JUDE must've won. If anything, that Squiddles ANNIHILATOR slammer warrants some respect.</cell>
    <cell address="C619" />
  </row>
  <row row="620">
    <cell address="A620">NAR_ITM_COMB_POGS_JOEY</cell>
    <cell address="B620">Maybe one day...you’ll be such a great veterinarian that you’ll get your own POG? Wow. Dream big, kiddo.</cell>
    <cell address="C620" />
  </row>
  <row row="621">
    <cell address="A621">NAR_ITM_COMB_POGS_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B621">You shave down the edges of the POG with the GREEN KEY. It will now be used to solve lots of different puzzles throughout your house. Good work!//Haha, just kidding. You don’t do that, because that would be ridiculous, and an insult to your PUZZLING SKILLS.</cell>
    <cell address="C621" />
  </row>
  <row row="622">
    <cell address="A622">NAR_ITM_COMB_FLASHLIGHT_EMPTY_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B622">The bad news is, the walkie-talkie takes a different type of batteries than the flashlight. The good news is... now you get to find a different size of battery.</cell>
    <cell address="C622" />
  </row>
  <row row="623">
    <cell address="A623">NAR_ITM_COMB_FLASHLIGHT_EMPTY_POGS</cell>
    <cell address="B623">You have no interest in putting pogs back inside this flashlight. You'd much rather fill it with batteries!</cell>
    <cell address="C623" />
  </row>
  <row row="624">
    <cell address="A624">NAR_ITM_LOOK_E_BATTERY</cell>
    <cell address="B624">These batteries are way bigger than D-CELL BATTERIES. The UNIVERSAL REMOTE requires some serious juice.</cell>
    <cell address="C624" />
  </row>
  <row row="625">
    <cell address="A625">NAR_ITM_COMB_FLASHLIGHT_EMPTY_E_BATTERY</cell>
    <cell address="B625">These batteries are so huge, they don't even begin to fit! Like fitting a round peg into a round hole that's a bit smaller than the peg. You'll need some D-CELL BATTERIES.</cell>
    <cell address="C625" />
  </row>
  <row row="626">
    <cell address="A626">NAR_ITM_LOOK_D_BATTERY</cell>
    <cell address="B626">You can almost feel the electric potential held within their vaunted COPPER TOPS. Cylindrical power capsules cast in alloy of myth, thrumming with the barely contained galvanism of one hundred Greeces' worth of muscular gods. You say this without the slightest hint of exaggeration, clutching a battery in your fist, and looking skyward piously.</cell>
    <cell address="C626" />
  </row>
  <row row="627">
    <cell address="A627">NAR_ITM_GET_FLASHLIGHT</cell>
    <cell address="B627">Hurray! Another electric device successfully powered through clever manipulation of resources in your immediate environment! You are on FIRE. //With your FLASHLIGHT fully functional and in fit fighting form, you equip it to your STRIFE DECK posthaste. Now you're ready to take on any baddies and nasties you might encounter! //Of course, you'd PREFER to overcome any problems you might face with cleverness and pluck, but sometimes you just gotta strife.</cell>
    <cell address="C627" />
  </row>
  <row row="628">
    <cell address="A628">NAR_ITM_LOOK_SPICE_MIX</cell>
    <cell address="B628">A shaker full of SEASON-ALL MAGIC SPICE MIX. This doggone powder adds the taste of flavor to every bite.</cell>
    <cell address="C628" />
  </row>
  <row row="629">
    <cell address="A629">NAR_ITM_COMB_SPICE_MIX_JOEY</cell>
    <cell address="B629">OK, just a taste... //Yum. Sweet and savory, with just a little spicy kick! You try a little more and, //Yep, you overdid it. Ugh.</cell>
    <cell address="C629" />
  </row>
  <row row="630">
    <cell address="A630">NAR_ITM_LOOK_STALE_CRACKER</cell>
    <cell address="B630">An old stale cracker that's been sitting in the back of the cabinet who knows how long. The cracker is so old, taking it almost feels like robbing a museum.</cell>
    <cell address="C630" />
  </row>
  <row row="631">
    <cell address="A631">NAR_ITM_COMB_SPICE_MIX_STALE_CRACKER</cell>
    <cell address="B631">It would probably make it taste better, but you're still not going to eat it. Heck, the spice would make cardboard taste better.</cell>
    <cell address="C631" />
  </row>
  <row row="632">
    <cell address="A632">NAR_ITM_COMB_SPICE_MIX_PET_TREATS</cell>
    <cell address="B632">Nah, they're already irresistible to pretty much all animals. Why gild a lily?</cell>
    <cell address="C632" />
  </row>
  <row row="633">
    <cell address="A633">NAR_ITM_COMB_STALE_CRACKER_JOEY</cell>
    <cell address="B633">You're not that desperate for a snack.</cell>
    <cell address="C633" />
  </row>
  <row row="634">
    <cell address="A634">NAR_ITM_COMB_STALE_CRACKER_PET_TREATS</cell>
    <cell address="B634">You combine the STALE CRACKER and PET TREATS into a SADNESS BRUSCHETTA.//Wow. Things have gotten pretty bleak around here, huh? Maybe not THAT bleak, though. You separate the SADNESS BRUSCHETTA into its original ingredients.</cell>
    <cell address="C634" />
  </row>
  <row row="635">
    <cell address="A635">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLAREGUN_EMPTY</cell>
    <cell address="B635">Just your average super awesome light and flame dispensary unit. No biggie.</cell>
    <cell address="C635" />
  </row>
  <row row="636">
    <cell address="A636">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLAREGUN_EMPTY_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B636">You know you're not supposed to do this, but if you DO ever have to fire your flare gun at someone, you hope you remember to deadpan the line "Sorry, life isn't FLARE" when you do it.</cell>
    <cell address="C636" />
  </row>
  <row row="637">
    <cell address="A637">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLARES</cell>
    <cell address="B637">These babies are looking for a good home. You don't want to disappoint, do you?</cell>
    <cell address="C637" />
  </row>
  <row row="638">
    <cell address="A638">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLARES_ONCE</cell>
    <cell address="B638">These FLARES can combine with a FLARE GUN to produce - you don't know what you'd call it? Fun times? They combine with a gun to produce a gun that fires BALLS OF FIRE that can LIGHT UP A ROOM and perhaps ATTRACT THE ATTENTION OF A RESCUE SHIP if you're ever stranded at sea. //You have been stranded at sea this many times in your adventure so far: 0.</cell>
    <cell address="C638" />
  </row>
  <row row="639">
    <cell address="A639">NAR_ITM_GET_FLAREGUN_LOADED</cell>
    <cell address="B639">You load the FLARES into the FLARE GUN. You now have a LOADED FLARE GUN. You feel the cool wash of security, justice, and above all, preparedness flow over you. Let's do this thing.</cell>
    <cell address="C639" />
  </row>
  <row row="640">
    <cell address="A640">NAR_ITM_LOOK_FLAREGUN_LOADED</cell>
    <cell address="B640">It is almost unfair that one kid gets to wield this much power! Use it wisely.</cell>
    <cell address="C640" />
  </row>
  <row row="641">
    <cell address="A641">NAR_ITM_LOOK_POUCH_MARBLES</cell>
    <cell address="B641">It's got one red and one green marble.</cell>
    <cell address="C641" />
  </row>
  <row row="642">
    <cell address="A642">NAR_ITM_COMB_POUCH_MARBLES_FLAREGUN_LOADED</cell>
    <cell address="B642">Have you lost your MARBLES? FLARE GUNS only shoot FLARES! Maybe if you had a MARBLE GUN, you could miraculously launch these MARBLES directly into Joey’s waiting hands, but, well, you don’t.</cell>
    <cell address="C642" />
  </row>
  <row row="643">
    <cell address="A643">NAR_ITM_LOOK_ATTIC_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B643">Remember when you found this key? Good times, friend.</cell>
    <cell address="C643" />
  </row>
  <row row="644">
    <cell address="A644">NAR_ITM_LOOK_PIGEON</cell>
    <cell address="B644">It is impressive, the extent to which this bird is able to express a complete dearth of wit through his tiny little eyes. You must protect him, for it is the witless creatures who need you the most.</cell>
    <cell address="C644" />
  </row>
  <row row="645">
    <cell address="A645">NAR_ITM_COMB_DIARY_KEY_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B645">You try to engage the keys in some sort of  twisted Escher-esque impossibility wherein they may unlock EACH OTHER in an infinite loop. But it fails.</cell>
    <cell address="C645" />
  </row>
  <row row="646">
    <cell address="A646">NAR_ITM_COMB_ATTIC_KEY_PORTAL_KEY</cell>
    <cell address="B646">Oh wow, the teeth mesh together PERFECTLY! This is... wait, no they don’t. They’re just two keys that look nothing alike. Still, it was worth a try, you guess. Kinda.</cell>
    <cell address="C646" />
  </row>
  <row row="647">
    <cell address="A647">NAR_ITM_TALK_JUDE_WALKIE_TALKIE_PIGEONS_UNSENT</cell>
    <cell address="B647">You can bark out sentences that end with "OVER" into this thing as much as you want, but that's not going to do you or Joey any good now. THE MYSTERIES OF THE TROPHY ROOM require ACTION, boy!</cell>
    <cell address="C647" />
  </row>
  <row row="648">
    <cell address="A648">NAR_ITM_TALK_JUDE_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B648">Joey knows it's up to her now. No need to pester her about it... //Hey! Pretty mature thought, Jude! Good one.</cell>
    <cell address="C648" />
  </row>
  <row row="649">
    <cell address="A649">NAR_ITM_LOOK_JUDE_WALKIE_TALKIE</cell>
    <cell address="B649">It's a WALKIE-TALKIE, but not just ANY walkie-talkie. This comes straight from the back pages of SUSPICIONS MAGAZINE (A periodical about suspicious activities and the suspicions of them). They're more secure from PRYING EARS than OTHER, REGULAR walkie-talkies... //probably. Joey has the other one.</cell>
    <cell address="C649" />
  </row>
</data>

